Hello, everyone.
In this chapter, I want to talk about morphing or transforming one object into another.
Maybe it's not wrong to say that morphing is one of the advanced topics in motion graphics.
And when you learn these techniques entirely and you can transform any object into another, you can
see that your works will stand one head and shoulders above the other ones.
As you can see in these examples, if you are professional in this technique, you will no longer have
any restriction on morphing objects and you can transform anything to everything you want.
This not being so simple and at the beginning level, generally the best and most attractive parts of
promotion graphics are the scenes in which we use the morph technique and objects transform into another
in it.
If I want to talk about the simplest models, I should point out to these kinds of samples that some
lines get morphed together, but these samples are way more vocational in which the technique of masking
overlapping frame by frame animation or 3D simulation have been used.
The important point in morphing that you should pay attention to is that there is no need that two objects
get morphed together so reasonable.
It is good enough when a viewer can imagine two objects have been transformed together, which for this
we use high speed, color, shape changing, bouncing or anything that can cause the destruction the
audience so they can detect the transforming process.
So let's go and create a simple morph using shape so that we get to know the basics and roles of morph
practically all working well.
These are the objects that I want to work on and morph into another.
And the reason that I have selected these three objects for morphing is that their shapes and volume
are completely different, and it may seem hard to move them together at first.
Look.
That's why I have selected these three shapes.
So after you have done this, you get more familiar with morphing different shapes together so that
in the future when you get serious projects in morphing, you can get through it.
Well, in the end, I want this kind of result.
So let's get to the job.
The first thing I should do is relocate the camera to the center of the scene because I want all of
the moves happening in the center of the scene.
I hide the other objects for now.
In morphing like animation is better than first you do the main actions like transforming, and then
you get to the details like anticipation, bouncing or shape elements that can make your work look better.
So first I do the main actions and then I try to improve the morph.
I go to the first second because I want to add anticipation to the animation later.
So I skip the first second for now.
The first thing I want to do is that the camera transforms into the magnifier.
For this, I locate the magnifier in the center too.
I set the opacity to 50 so I can see the blue layer, and I start animating the camera.
First, I want the camera to rotate, and its lens gets bigger to the same size as the magnifier.
And this great layer transforms into the magnifier handle.
And these two layers appear step by step.
For this, I open the camera rotation and create a keyframe for it.
I go ten frames forward and rotate the camera so the angle of the camera can be the same as the magnifier.
I open the camera layer in content.
I go to the group lens and transform and create a keyframe for its scale.
I go ten frames back and create another keyframe.
I go to the second keyframe and change its size to the size of magnifier lens.
Now I start animating this great layer of camera.
I go to the second one.
Isolate the grey layer.
Because I want to animate its path.
I can read it Busier path.
I create a keyframe for it in second one.
I got in Frames forward and I did the path.
So it becomes the same size as the magnifier handle.
I appeared the magnifier layer so that I can know how much I should edit the path.
I get back to the second one.
This camera was clearly should fade when the camera is transforming to the magnifier.
That's why I opened the layer.
And rectangle path.
I create a keyframe for the roundness and another keyframe for its size.
So the layer gets smaller and hides behind the lens.
Then frames forward, increase the roundness, so it becomes completely circle and decrease the size
to zero.
Then I should animate this layer.
And this one.
I should hide them too.
For this, isolate the layers.
This is the rectangle here and this is the flash layer.
So this anchor point in the center of the scene.
An animate the scale of these two layers.
I press U.K. so I can only see the key frames I go to in frames ahead and set the shape scale to zero.
As you can see, shapes are located on the lens.
But it shouldn't be like this.
That's why I put the shapes below the lens group.
It's good.
I should animate the lens shadow and hide it.
Well, as you can see, when the camera retains all of the additional points hide and the camera becomes
the magnifier.
Now I should animate the other layers of magnifier handle.
I open the magnified layer and in group handle a copy this and this layer to.
I go to the camera layer and I select contents and I press control V so they paste in camera contents.
I move to new shapes above the create shape.
I relocate the shapes to the right places so that eventually I have a shape like a reference.
Let's take a look and see how it is.
And this frame.
I should create a key frame for these two shapes.
I go back to the second one and put these two layers beneath the lens so it can be seen.
Let's take a look at the animation.
That's good.
I should turn this hand layer to white because the reference magnifier was wide.
So this one should be too.
That's why I go to the second one.
Selling the layer.
I open the fill and create a keyframe for its color.
I go to frames forward and pick white color for the magnifier handle.
So for the camera, morph into the magnifier has been completed.
It's the main action is done.
And the next lesson, I want to morph the magnifier into the locator and the map.
Good luck.