Hi.
In this lesson, I want more of the magnifier into the locator and the map.
For this, I open the position and create a keyframe for it.
And another keyframe for its rotation.
I want to start morphing the magnifier to the locator.
From the second to I appear the locator.
When I want more of two shapes together should see what their common points can be.
In my opinion, this wide angle in the magnifier and this wide circle in the locator can be the main
part of the morph animation, and other parts can appear based on these two objects.
I want the magnifier to have a rotation and go up and fall down and be placed on the map like a locator.
For this, I created a keyframe for its rotation and position in the second to go 15 frames forward,
Move the magnifier up.
Benton frames forward and paced the key frames position here.
It rotates and at the end is like this 90 degrees.
I iss this key frame.
So I have a little pause here.
Let's see how it is.
It's pause is too short.
So I go to the graph editor and increase these two handles so its pores gets longer.
Let's see how it is.
Well, it looks good.
Let me just increase these a little bit more.
It's better now.
After that, I moved the located exactly here in the center.
I opened the layer and parent to the camera layer.
I hide, the map shames for now.
This layer to.
I just want to animate this layer.
That's when I go into the Libs path and create a keyframe for its size and another one for stroke width.
I press you so I can only see keyframes.
Hear that the magnifier is at the top.
I increase the size of the stroke.
My stroke was too.
Until.
Isolate the keyframes and reverse the.
I go five frames forward and set the first key frames there.
Again, I go to the second to set the stroke width on zero so it becomes hidden at first and it appears
after five frames and then its size gets back to the original size.
After I'm done with the locator stroke.
I go into the locator group.
In a wide eye open path and increase the size, as you can see, because I use merge path and said it's
more than subtract when I increase its size, the locator hides.
I create a keyframe for each size here.
I go to the second to decrease its size.
So like the key frames and reverse.
Its size should be exactly the same as the stroke path.
As you can see, the locator is crooked.
That's because I didn't do parenting at the right time.
I go to the second two and appear map players.
The layer is completely level and that's good.
Here I am pairing the layer.
I go to the last keyframe, which the magnifier comes down, allocates in the right place.
And here I present it again to the camera layer.
I hide my players for now.
And if you pay attention, you see the locator appears and lens completely straight.
It's really important that you know, in which frame you should parent the layers to another.
After that, I go to the second two, I open the camera layer.
Open the group lens.
Then I go into transform and create a keyframe for this scale.
Here.
And another one for the handle layers.
Because I don't want to create a keyframe for the scale of every one of them.
Isolate these three layers, and by pressing control G I put them in a group and rename it.
I go into it and create a key frame for this scale of the group.
As you can see, its anchor point is here, but it shouldn't be here.
So I move it to the center of the shape.
I press you key to see all the keyframes.
I said this scale off the lens up to zero here so it becomes hidden.
For hiding these magnifier handles.
I go into the handle group and set the scale to zero.
Let's have a look and see how the animation is.
The movements of the wide circle locator doesn't match with the magnifier, so I should match them together.
From here, the size of the locators starts to decrease.
And that's where I should put the beginning keyframe of the magnifier scale here.
See how it is.
I should move the second keyframe forward.
So continuous here.
Let's take a look.
Well, it's fine.
Now I start to animate the map, isolate the map layers first, control G and make them a group animate
group map.
I go to the transform of the group and create a keyframe for this scale.
And when they locate their places down here.
The scale of the group map should start to increase to.
I said it.
Two zero here.
And see how it is.
I want the map to appear in seven frames.
After the locater landed on the map and the map appeared.
I want to create a wave kind of shape like this under the locator.
For this, I open the locator.
Select the contents and create an ellipse beneath the locator.
I hold them control.
And according to the viewing angle of the map, I create the circle.
Isolate the libs, press control g and move it to a.
Name it.
Group Wave.
Put it beneath the locator.
First, I create a key frame for its size and frames forward and decrease it size to zero.
Isolate the keyframes and reverse them from Keyframe assistant.
So it becomes like this.
I should easy ease the second keyframe.
I increase its initial speed a little bit.
I duplicate this ellipse and add a merge path to this group.
And I want the marriage path filled with this orange.
I get a sample of it.
I set the merge path mode on subtract.
And move the players keyframes forward.
So becomes more like this.
Let's see how it is.
It's fine, but I think it's just a little fast, so decrease it.
If I want the wave animation to repeat and doesn't stop, I should use the loop outside expression for
it.
I paste it for this one to.
It's good for now.
Let's see how the animation is.
So far I could create the main actions of the Morph animation.
And now it's time to add bouncing and anticipation to the animation to have a more dynamic animation.
So I'll see you in the next lesson.