Hi.
As you know, in this lesson, I want to add bouncing and anticipation for the animation, for creating
anticipation, isolate the camera layer and open its rotation.
And I go seven frames backward and create a keyframe for rotation and go to the second one because the
camera rotates to the left.
I want to write a little bit and say, Don't.
And easy is this keyframe.
I want the rotation to look better, so let me use it to an effect.
I added to the layer and create a keyframe here for the angle and here seven for the five degrees.
I go three frames forward and send this to -50 degrees.
And at the end on zero.
I press you so I can see the keyframes.
I paste this keyframe here.
So it's cavernous, continuous until here.
Let's create the anticipation of this movement when the magnifier starts going up.
I go back seven frames again?
I would say the layer to this side.
Isolate the two key frames and reverse them.
And easy is this key frame.
I just the keyframes.
So the animation looks better.
I uses this key frame to.
Here.
The rotation of the layers should be like this.
And I make the keyframe continuous.
Let's see how it is.
It's a little bit better.
I think its rotation for anticipation is too much, so I decrease it.
Now it's better.
I need you to see the keyframes.
Isolate all of the key frames belonging to the second morph.
Move them a little bit forward so that the animation don't overlap.
Well, it's good for now.
I've done the anticipation of the animation.
Let's create the bouncy animation so the animation becomes more dynamic, isolate the rotation and apply
excite.
So from motion to a script.
And I said the overshoot to ten.
And the bouncing to 20.
So it's rotation and the bouncing amount gets decreased.
Let's see how it is.
I believe the key frame of the total effect.
So the animation looks better.
Let's see it again.
Let me move the keyframes of the second animation forward.
So the bouncing of the first move becomes more obvious.
As you see, it, has bouncy animation and then it starts to move and the bounce effect is still on
the layer and this causes the map to have this rotation.
First stop in the bounce in the second move.
I go to this frame and create a keyframe for the overshoot slider.
I go to the next frame and say, one zero.
As you see, it doesn't bounce anymore.
Let's take a look and see how it is.
Well, it's good enough now.
When the locator places on the map, I want it to have a bouncy animation to.
For this I open the locator layer and select these two layers relating to the locator.
Press control g and put them in a new group.
And name it Group locator.
I said its anchor point to the bottom.
I often transform and create a keyframe for its scale.
I press you key when the locator is floating.
I put this scale keyframe here.
And here I create another keyframe.
And up to here, which is falling, is its wide scale on 110.
After that, isolate the scale and apply to it.
Overflowing and bouncing on 20.
Let's see how it is.
As you can see, I have created a spring animation for it, but it's not enough.
That's why I said this on 20.
Let's see if it gets better.
I increase the bouncing a little bit.
Let's see how it goes.
Its animation is good.
Now I want to create a bounce animation for the map scale for this isolate group map scale.
Go into motion to a script, then click on Excite.
Let's take a look.
As you can see, the changes I make here don't apply to the map.
Because the coding is associated with these sliders.
As you see, if I increase this, this one rises to.
One of the bikes that motion to have is this.
That's why I don't use motion to here.
I use another way for my bouncing and that is the expression.
I'll click on it and paste the bouncy expression in it.
And as you can see, I have a reasonable enough animation.
Let's see the animation from the beginning.
I want the second more first thoughts when the magnifier rotates up.
That's why I select the keyframes and move them back to this point.
Let's see how it is.
Well, it's good.
After that, you can add a few shapes elements at the end and make your animation more dynamic and lovely.
Creating these changes is not that hard.
As you can see, this is a circle that has only a stroke and with the help of pass modifier, I created
this kind of animation for it.
I have explained the way of making these shape elements in the Shapes chapter.
Good luck.