Hello, everyone.
In this video, I want to talk about loop animations.
The first thing I should know is what is loop and what kind of clips I call loop.
In general, I call a few seconds clip loop videos because they repeat and less times and I can't easily
decide which part is the first and last part.
I think that they are long clips, but that is not true.
At first.
Let me say a few points about loop animations.
So further I use them in a project.
The first point I want to say is that try to make your loop animation as simple as possible as it shows
only acts of one thing like eating, walking or etc..
Not that we use several acts in one loop animation because in this condition it's better that we call
it the short film rather than loop animation.
Maybe now you are thinking that the loop animation that only shows one act is not that interesting,
but as you can see, it is not like that.
Only with adding details and more elements to the animation we can create.
Simple yet really interesting clips.
The second point, I should say, is that we should try to make our scenes as dynamic as possible.
It should always have movements.
There should be no objects to be in your scene.
On the contrary, everything should be moving in your loop animation.
Why?
Because the scene is going to be repeated a lot of times for your audience.
That is why it should be as dynamic and interesting as possible.
The next point that should be considered in loop animations and has a lot of influence in making our
animation interesting is overlapping.
Overlapping makes your animation more smooth and natural and makes it more realistic.
The next and most important point about loop animations and generally in all of the animations is smoothing
keyframes and path animations.
So use as much as possible from easiest keyframes and don't use linear keyframes as much as possible.
Because naturally when you use these keyframes, you will have smooth and more interesting animations.
The last point, I should say, is timing, which you should pay attention to it from the beginning
of making your loop animation so that the time of your whole animation should be matched with the time
of the objects loop.
For example, if our whole animation loop time is 30 frames, the object's time multiple in the scene
should be a 32.
It means that if, for example, an object is looping in a scene, its loop time should be either five
frames or six, ten, 15 or 30.
So it matches with a whole loop animation time, which is 30 frames.
So this way we don't have any kind of leap in our loop animation.
The next point about timing, which sometimes happen, is all of the loops in a scene and in the same
frame.
For example, we have a few characters walking and a first and last part of their walking, and in the
same frame you are walking exactly at the same time and it creates a robotic and artificial state.
In these situations, with a little bit of moving and overlapping the key frames of the loop, we get
better results and make the scene look more natural.
When we can consider and use these points in our loop animations.
You can see we have made more interesting loop animations which have unclear first and last part, meaning
we have no leaps in our loops and eventually attracts the audience so audiences can watch over and over
and doesn't get tired of it.
So in the next lesson, I start to make a simple loop animation considering points we just talked about.
Good luck.