Hello, everyone.
In this video, I want to create a simple loop so I get to know the points that I mentioned in a previous
video practically.
Well, this is the plan that I want to make it a loop animation.
And finally, I want to have this kind of result.
Let me first explain how I can create these shapes so you don't get confused about how these shapes
have been made.
It is so simple, but I will explain it to you.
As you see, this is the head layer of my character, which its main shape is a rounded rectangle.
I open the layer.
This is my main shape.
Then I made the main beard layer.
Let me hide other layers so I can see it.
I created the main beard layer by duplicate this layer and then cut it in half.
The next layer is the front part of the beer.
And this is a rounded rectangle too.
The next layer is hair, which I made this part again by duplicate this layer.
The next layer.
Is this part of the hair?
As you can see, I created an ellipse here for my character's ear, another smaller ellipse for the
inner circle in the ear.
The next shape I made is the nose layer.
I created it by pen tool.
Next, I created the eye layer with a small ellipse and this one by a stroke.
And finally, the last layer, which is the characters scrunchy, has been made by stroke.
All of these shapes are my character's head layer.
I have put this part of the hair in an individual layer and said its anchor point here, so I can make
a springy animation for it.
The next layer is the neck.
As you can see, it is rounded rectangle and its anchor point is here.
And the anchor point of the head layer is here.
Next is the buddy layer, which I named it hip.
It's better to be the body.
Well, this is my buddy layer.
Let me make it slow so I can completely see how it is.
I open the layer.
There is a main layer which is an ellipse.
The next layer is the hip.
I created a pelvis for it and next is for the color shadow.
And this is the color.
And finally, a layer for its belt.
Designing this part of character is not much hard.
The point is that you should set the anchor point of the body here because the character's body is going
to rotate from here.
Well, the next layer is the character's leg.
The main shape is a rectangle, which is the path of my character.
The next layer is the bottom part of the pants, which I made with a different color.
The next shape is the leg part.
And finally, another layer for my character's socks.
The next layer is shoe, which as you can see, it is a single shape.
And has been designed like this.
And for the shoelace, I just made a path and kept its stroke.
And said the anchor points of layers in this part.
Maybe you wonder my legs.
Anchor point is here in the bottom part, which should be here around its pelvis.
This is because my character animation, as you can see here.
In such a way that the bottom part of the legs are still and this part of the leg should rotate from
here.
That is why the legs anchor point shouldn't be here in the pelvis, but it should be here in a button
so I can have this kind of rotation in the leg.
I should say this point that you break the character relatively to your animation and it is not like
that.
Characters, Rick should be the same all the time.
It is different depending on a need and the movement you should make with your character.
Your method is going to change.
Well, I duplicated the leg layers and put it behind.
Let me hide them so you can completely understand.
I created the hand layer with a rounded rectangle, which is obvious.
This is my main layer.
For making the hand sleeve.
I duplicated this rounded rectangle.
Let me swallow this layer.
This is the stroke of the character's sleeve.
And this is the sleeve itself.
And this is the hand.
The next layer is the ax.
Its root is completely obvious.
That has been made with a rounded rectangle.
This is the worst part.
I created one rounded rectangle and here I selected these points.
And with heating control t, I made this part a little bit bigger.
For the iron part of the ax, I created a main shape.
I created this shape and then I created its edge by duplicating the shape.
I only kept this part of it.
And finally, I created a reflect like this.
Let me disable the marriage path and hide this part of X.
Let me hide these two layers so you completely understand.
As you can see, this is the reflect part of the ax.
This is the ax shape which I have created it by duplicating this shape.
And then I added marriage path as modifier to its group and said its mode on intersect.
So it keeps the common area of these two layers and hide the rest.
These layers are completely obvious.
I created the shape here.
Then I created this shape.
And at the end, the two leaves and one branch here.
And I created this wood with two shapes.
After we are done with getting acquainted with these objects designing, we should go to this animation.