The important point in the loop animations is that the first and the last frame of your animation should
be the same.
So there is no jump when your animation starts replaying.
And the main point which I mentioned in a previous video, is that you should make your loop animations
as simple as possible.
Let me take a look at this animation.
Well, as you can see, I have this kind of pose for my character.
This is one pose for my character, and the second pose that I should create for my character is this
pose.
In fact, I create two poses for my character or my animation, and my loop will be going in a cycle
between these two poses.
Well, let's go to the job.
The first pose I want to create is the pose which my character has hit with the axe and is bending.
For this I should parent the layers together so I don't have any problem when I animate.
As I said, this layer should be parented to the shoe layer.
So I parent the right leg to the right shoe.
That is why when I animate the right leg, there is no need to animate the left leg to.
I patterned the left leg's rotation to the right.
Leg's rotation.
So when the right leg got rotated, the left leg rotates to.
So I appeared the rotation of the left leg.
The right leg too.
Then I patterned the left leg's rotation to the right.
Leg's rotation.
If you pay attention.
You see, when I rotate the right leg, the left leg rotates, too, and changes its value.
The next thing I should do is parenting the character's body to the leg.
It.
So when my character's like, rotates, the body moves to.
So I parent the body to the right leg.
Well, now, if I move the right leg, the body moves to.
It's good so far.
I should pattern the hand layer to the body.
The next should parent to the Buddy ledger.
The head lawyer should parent the next lawyer.
And this part of the hair layer should be parented to the head layer.
Let's rotate and see how it is.
It's good.
All the parts of the character move by rotating the character's leg.
Well, I should attach the ax to the character's hand so when his hands moves, he swings the ax too.
I parent a layer to my character's hand.
Let me rotate.
You see, when the character's hand rotates, the ax moves with it to.
What we need to do here is that when my character's hand moves to the back of this body, it should
be bent.
I want to create this kind of shame for him.
I create this bending state in two ways.
The first one is by using banned effect.
Let me add the band effect to my character's hand so you get the impression.
Well, as you can see, when I increase the band and the character's hand bands are no longer the X
moves with the hand, and this is not good.
Because I want the axe moving with a hand when the hand rotates and I don't want the axe left behind
from the hand so they bend.
The fact is not useful for us.
The second and the best way that I can parent the axe to the character's hand is that I use puppets.
Let me set the hand's rotation on zero.
I activated the perpetual.
I create three pins for it, one in the shoulder, one in the elbow, and finally one to the part which
I want my axe to pair into.
I press cancel A to select the three pin puppets and for having more control over the puppets, I should
create a null object for these puppets.
For creating null objects.
I can use the motion to script.
In this drop menu, select the PIN Plus.
And as you can see, three null objects have been created for us.
Another way you can use is you select the PIN puppets and use the free script, which is a completely
pro script for the characters.
I go into the rigging panel and links and constrains.
I click on Add Bones and it creates a three layers for your pin puppets.
After I created layers for the pin puppets of the character's hand, there is no need for the hand layer
to be parented to the body layer because I want to control the hand by these bones.
That's why I am apparently here.
They said bones should be parented to the second and second.
Bowen should be parented to the first one, and the first one should be parented to the body.
Now, if I rotate the body, you can see the hand rotates to.
And now if I parent to axe Layer to the third bone, which is this layer.
When the hand rotates.
Let me rotate The first one you see the X moves to.
And if I want to create a bending state for the hand.
I rotate the second bone a little bit, and as you can see, the hand has a bending state.
Very simple.
The axes completely parented to the hand, and it doesn't matter how much it bends.
The act is parented to the hand, and it is not like band effects and the acts doesn't leave behind.
Well, I said these values on zero now, which my characters can play the lyric.
I go to creating the first post.