The first pose I should create is my character moving a little bit to the back?
The body should rotate.
And these hands should rotate.
So it places like this kind of situation.
And at the end I rotate the axe so it completely lies on the trunk.
Well, it is good enough.
I have created the first post.
I created a key frame for the ride legs rotation.
Another one for the body is rotation.
For the axis rotation.
And another one for this bone rotation.
I should rotate the next rotation a little bit and set it on 18.
And the heads rotation on minus nine.
Well, I create a key frame for the head and neck to.
After I have created the first post, I go to the second one and create the second post.
Well, and here the character should completely move backward.
The legs rotation comes forward.
I set it on for.
I moved the body more to behind.
Well, it's good.
I move the hand to back.
Rotate this.
It has a bending state.
I should create a keyframe for this bone, too.
And because it doesn't have any keyframes in the first post, I should move back.
Set this on zero and create the first post keyframe for it.
And the next should rotate to behind here.
Also for the head.
Well, it's fine.
I think the hands should move more to behind.
And here I go into the heads later.
I create a keyframe for the eyebrows position.
And as you can see, its anchor point is here.
And another key frame for its rotation to have this kind of animation.
I go into the eyes shape and in the lips path I create a keyframe frame for the eye size to.
I hit you.
So only the keyframes would be shown here.
I create a simple animate for this part of hair for now, but I should change it later.
Well, I create a keyframe for its rotation.
I move it a little bit behind.
I get back to the first post.
Its rotation should mean this way.
Here.
I create the eyebrow and I keyframes.
I go to the second pose and here the eyebrow should rotate like this.
Also a little bit slower.
And said the ellipses and one so I can see the pressure on my character.
Let's take a look at my animation.
As you can see, my animation is on loop because it has the leap.
I should make it loop.
For this.
I go for frames ahead from second one and pace the first post key frames here.
I use this script motion to and I click on the clone.
I leave me to work here again until here so I can see how the animation is.
Here.
The ax should move a little bit backward.
And here it gets back to its first position.
Let's see how it looks.
Well, I select a middle key frames and easy ease of them.
As you can see, I have created a really simple loop animation, but it is so artificial I should give
more details to it and regulate the speed of animate so it looks better.
I select all of the middle key frames and set their easy ease on 100.
Let's take a look.
It's real bad.
It's too much.
Let me move the keyframes on second 14.
The animation got better in a second post.
It slows down and speeds up again.
I moved the key frames a few frames ahead so I can create a movement before the character's animation.
I go to frames backward and create keyframe for these three bones.
Then easy is the keyframes.
So I have a smooth movement at first.
I change keyframes so I can have this kind of state.
I make I make these keyframes also busier so my animate doesn't have a pause.
And here I move the ex lawyer and again I set these on auto busier.
Let's take a look.
I should move this up.
I copy the frame and paste it here.
So the first and the last of my animation would be the same.
Well, the character animation is much better.