They made an animation of My character is almost done, but I want my loop animation to look better.
So I go for the details like scene details, animation layers, overlapping animation, creating a springy
animation.
So I have a more dynamic and better animation.
The head animation should begin a little sooner.
And when the ax touches the trunk, I want the head to have a springy animation.
That is why I like the rotation and click on Excite.
Let's have a look.
The head movement is too much.
I said the overshoot and ten.
And it's friction on 60, so the movement stops sooner.
And as you can see, the head gets a fancy movement.
Well, it's good.
After that, I go for this lecture.
While the character is moving behind, this part of the hair should rotate to forward.
So its rotation should be to the backwards, for example, on 23.
Then it comes till here and sets on zero.
And it should be easy.
Easy to.
It should get back to his place from here.
Here is zero.
And gets down to.
You'll hear.
It should be on -23, meaning it should be leaning backward.
Go forward till the head is going back.
And here, set it on zero and make it linear.
And apply excite to it.
And its overseer should be ten like head.
And in the beginning it should be zero.
Increase its overshoot so its animation becomes more obvious.
Well, it's good.
After that I go for leaves animation.
When my character hits its ax and the trunk.
This leaves should animate and have follow through animation.
Well, I go for the trunk layer.
I go into group leaves layer leave zero one meaning this layer.
As you can see, its anchor point is here, and it should be here so I can rotate it from this part.
I create a keyframe for the rotation of Leaf zero one and another one for the Leaf zero two rotation.
I hate you Key.
I go to frames ahead.
I move it a little bit down so it shows the power wave when the axe hits the trunk.
I move this one a little bit down to and because I want the animation of these two leaves to be different,
I move the second key frame of the upper leaf, so the animation be different together.
I go to a frames for it and set these on zero.
I said the key frames differently.
I make their medial keyframes Easy, easy.
And I apply IXI to both rotations.
Let's take a look.
I move this more to the side.
Let's see if it looks better.
Well, it's good enough.
Let's get to animating Delicious.
I should do the same for these two.
I appear the rotation and create a keyframe frame for them.
Two frames forward.
Bring them down a bit.
Again, I go to frames ahead and duplicate their first key frames.
I make these and easy easy to.
And for being different, I changed the keyframes.
I select the two and click on Excite.
I can move these two through these side also for these two.
So its animation looks more smooth.
I should do the same for the two places behind.
This time I go three frames ahead.
So it looks different from this.
I bring it down.
Again.
Three frames ahead.
I copy the first key frames.
Make the middle keyframes Easy.
Easy.
And make more changes in their animation.
I select the two rotations and click on each side so they can have a spring animation.
Led me increase this one to.
Well, it's good so far.
I can intimate more details.
For example, I can create bounds for the hand sleeve.
And this is my slave group.
I go into its transform and create a keyframe for its scale.
I put this scale keyframe here.
And I want to animate it in the y axis.
So I go three frames ahead and set this on 105.
Again, three frames ahead and I paste the first key frame.
I easy is the middle key frame and then select scale and apply excite to it.
I increase its bounds a little bit.
Well, it's good.
I want to create the same bouncing for the bottom part of the character's pants, too.
For this, I select the pants layer.
I'm going to contend this part, in part.
As you can see, its anchor point is up here, and it should be here to.
I go into its shape, transform and create a keyframe for its scale.
I do the same for the other, like behind.
I go into content pants, too, and I create a keyframe for this scale.
I hit you key for this one to.
I select this scale keyframes and move them here, which the X places on the trunk.
This one to.
I go Three frames ahead.
I set the scale on 110.
I also do the same for this one.
Three frames ahead.
I paced the first key frames and easy is the middle key frames.
And I said, like this scale and apply excite to them.
Let's take a look.
I make some changes, so their animation looks different.
So far, my character's animation has been completed and now I should start animating splitting the
firewood.