For creating the file with animation, I should create two new shapes.
I create a rectangle here.
And said it's colored the same as the trunks color.
I name it our timber.
I want to animate this layer for this IP position and rotation.
Exactly in a frame.
My character's ax placed on the trunk.
I put the first keyframe here.
I go nine frames ahead and I place my layer here and a little bit higher.
I adjust its path?
Well, it's good.
I go six frames ahead and put the layer here.
It should almost place here.
I go eight frames ahead and I put the layer here again, five frames ahead, and I put it here.
Here.
The Y position is on 924.
And here should be 924 to.
Because the ground is the same.
Again, I go seven frames ahead and put it here.
Let me change these a little bit.
And I continue to do the same.
After I'm done, I select the pencil and edit the upper points handles.
I select the keyframes which my object places on top and make them easy ease.
I limit the work area to see how it looks.
Well, as you can see, when my object is in these places pauses a little bit.
And this is not right.
For removing this problem.
I select the key frame and go into graph editor.
Right click on them and go into keyframe velocity.
I turn on the continue so I can move the keyframes together.
I move them a little bit higher so its speed doesn't get to zero in this point.
Let's take a look.
Well, it's good after that in places in the firewood is on the ground.
I want its rotation to be like this.
And when it places here, I want it like this.
And at the end it should rotate and plays like this.
Let's take a look.
Well, it's good.
I want my firewood to have a burning stay.
That is why I add band effect to it.
Let me follow the ledger.
When it is here, I set the start and end points.
I increase the band a little bit and set the start point in the middle.
I move this higher so I can have this kind of shape.
Now I want that when the object moves, these points move with it to.
For this, I hit all click on a start and type the two command and type value and it.
And I copy this expression four and two.
And at the end I put the endpoint here and they start in the center of my object.
After that, I create a keyframe for each band in here and set it on zero.
I hit you key.
When my object is here, I want it to bend to the side.
-20.
When it is here, it should be on 20.
And here again, -20.
Let's take a look.
In my opinion, -20 is too much.
I change it to minus ten.
Yes, that's better.
This one on ten.
And here on minus ten.
Well, it's much better.
In fact, this is my left Firebird Slayer.
I rename it to L Timber.
I go into it.
I duplicate the rectangle.
And its color should be the same as the inner color of the trunk.
And in here change the size of the rectangle path.
So it looks like the left piece of the Firebird.
After that I duplicate the layer.
Name it to write.
I come at the beginning of the animation, I should pattern this layer to another object.
I put the null object exactly in its center.
And apparent derision to the nul objects.
Then I select three horizontal for this layer and let this null.
So this layer moves to the side.
Well, as you can see, it moves through this side.
Now, I don't need the upper rectangle because I want to be the right piece of my firewood.
And another point is here the band direction should be reversed to.
And eventually this left layer should be placed under the character layers.
Let me play the animation from the beginning.
After that, I should start creating shadows for the fire with pieces.
For this.
I create an ellipse here.
Exactly when the firewood is on the ground.
Make it black.
Move it down and place it under the L timber layer.
I said it's opacity on 30 and name it Shadow.
And I want to point out it's exposition to the exposition of my firewood layer.
That is why I alt click and define exposition of lhe timber layer for its ex.
I write a semi column and move to the next line.
I define what the layer is itself so it doesn't change.
And here I write X and Y.
So my expression ends.
Now, as you can see, the shadow moves with my object.
Another thing is when my object is floating in the air, the shadow should be smaller, and when it
is closer to the ground should be bigger.
For this.
I open this kale.
I activate its expression.
And in expressions interpolation I select the second linear.
I hit an answer at first.
So the linear moves to the second line and I defined the y position of Firebird layer as DT variable.
I write semi so it ends its minimum, meaning when it is here is 924.
And the maximum when the place top is 592.
And when it is on 592, I want the X and Y scale to be on 100.
Well, as you can see, the shadow changes as I wanted to.
Just let me move its x more to this side so the shadow completely fades at the end.
After that, I duplicate this layer and bring it up.
And do the same for the other five with peace.
I appear its position.
I double tap on E so I can see the expressions.
I defined x position of r timber as x variable the y of itself.
Good so far.
As you can see now, the shadow of the other firework piece is going to be good to.
Just I want the shadow layer to appear from here.
That is why I said it's beginning.
And this layer to.
Let's take a look at my animation.
Well, as you can see, my animation is completely fixed.
Let's get to creating a math ledger.
I move this above my axe layer and name it Matt.
I selected alpha inverted math for the axilla.
Yea.
I bring this down a little bit so the firewood can't be seen.
Well, let's see how my animation is.
Well, it's good.
The last thing I should do is create a motion blur state and a trace of the Axis movement.
As you can see in my frame, my accent moves from here till it places under trunk.
I want my ax to have a trace to look more interesting.
For this, it is enough to select the pencil and create a point here.
And another one here.
I adjust the path the way it shows the Axis movement path.
I disable its feel and enable a stroke.
It's a stroke.
Should be the same color as the axis color.
I increase its size, it becomes the same as the bottom part of my axis.
And this frame which the act places on.
I go to frames ahead and set the layers.
And here.
Here appears in the next frame.
My stroke should be half.
That is why I added three path modifier to the contents.
I said it's and on 50 and create a keyframe frame for it.
And in previous frame I set it on 100.
And eventually it fades.
Well, my love animation is completely finished.
As I said, we should first hypothesize our animation so simple.
And as I said, our character has two poses.
One of them is this and the next pose is when the ax hits the firewood.
And in the beginning, as we did first, we created these two simple poses.
And then the other details and elements of the scene have been animated in relation to these two poses.
Good luck.