The next modifier we will talk about it is repeater.
Open share player in content.
Press add button and from modifiers at repeater to the contents.
As you see, immediately after I add repeater modifier, the shape is repeating and as it name implies,
this modifier is used to repeat your shapes and create several shapes like that up and repeat their
modifier.
The first option is copies, by which you can control the number of shape copies.
It is set on three.
You can set it on any number you want.
The next one is offset.
It's better to explain it later.
The next one is composite by which you can define how they overlap each other.
For example, the first one should be on the second one, the second one, and the third, or vice versa.
The first one, the second one, and the second one beneath the third one.
The next one is transform, which is most important parameter in this modifier.
Inside transform.
First option is anchor point.
We have nothing to do with.
The second option is positioned that as you see, x position is set at 100, meaning that the distance
between two copies should be 100 pixels.
As I increase this value, the distance between two copies increases, I set it on 100 again.
You can also apply this change in y axis.
The next option is scale.
Using this option, you can control the scale of the copies you have just like ramp.
The next option is rotation, which you can use for rotating the copies.
The next options are start and end opacity.
By then, you can control the capacity of the beginning or the end of the copies.
Now we have finished all options.
Let's talk about offset.
Offset performance is based on the settings you apply to transform.
I have only changed the position X of the transform of the repeater.
Therefore the copies are ordered in this position.
If I change offset, let me hold down control to make it slower.
I can move them in the same position X that I have changed.
Now, if I change my position and change upset as well, it will move in this direction.
I changed this to zero, this one as well.
Now if I change a scale like this.
By changing offsets.
As they go to the right, the stars get smaller and as they go to the left, they get bigger.
The same thing applies to the rotation and opacity.
After introducing this modifier.
Briefly, let's go to the examples to see when do we mostly use this modifier?
The first example is creating such a background using repeater modifier.
Or this one.
The first background is this one.
I open the layer.
This is a background layer.
The gradient color is here and these two are for creating this hive mode.
I like these and I will create it again.
I use Polygon Tool holding down shift.
I create the shape.
Disable its feel.
I said it.
Stroke on 3.5.
Change its color to white.
I move it to the left.
I should stick to the frame.
Now we should repeat it.
So to do this, I select contents and from ADD, I add the repeater and I move it above the background
since I don't want it to affect on the background open repeater, transform and decrease exposition
to place them next to each other.
Then you can increase the number of the copies until they completely fill the scene.
Select shape and repeater press control and g to move them to a group.
Then we add another repeater.
Move the repeater above background.
I said copies to two.
And it transformed said exposition to zero and increase the Y position.
Let's zoom in.
It's OC.
Then we move the repeater and this group to a new group.
Then I add another repeater to the shape.
Then we set position X to zero and said Y two.
Let's see, what number should it be set on?
78.
Now you can set the number of the copies.
It's nine.
You see now we have created this background so easily.
You can easily create this background as well.
Let me delete these.
I select contents.
I add a shape to the contents.
Then we had to repeat there to the shape player.
I said the copies number to ten.
Decrease its exposition to place them next to each other.
13 is fine.
I set the start capacity on 80 and set end to 15.
Now we have such a shape.
Set the start to 72 seem like fade a bit.
Sixties.
Mother.
Yeah.
Then group these two and add another repeater to the scene.
Here.
First we said position X.
Set it on 130.
Change it to 132 to be a bit far from each other.
Said copies to ten.
Change, it's offset.
Let me change it to feet to see the top right corner better.
Change it to minus six.
It's better now.
Change their copies to 13.
14.
That's better.
It created this background that much easy.
The next really useful example of repeater modifier is repeating the shapes.
For example, in such for animation, we have a part here.
Here is a file that we go for war.
The.
File is repeated, windows repeated.
Again, the window is repeated again.
The same part.
And so on.
You can create such background using repeater.
Open the background composition.
As you see, we have placed three files here and three windows.
Look here.
If I open the files layer and hide this repeater, you can see that the two other files are removed.
You see, even the single file is created using repeater modifier.
I disable the repeater.
First of all, you had just one dropper which I repeated that using repeater and made four of that and
again using repeater, I repeated the whole file.
I did the same with the windows.
Attention that if I disable the repeater, the rest of the windows will be removed.
As you see, one of the usages of this modifier is the situations that you want to copy the objects
and make a busy background.
The next example is creating such a thing.
Let's create such a shape and animation.
Let this enable title action safe.
First create a shape from this point.
After that go to contents shape.
We don't need its feel.
Change the stroke line.
Cap to round cap to make its corners round the.
Then open transformed parameter of the shape and create a key frame for its position.
Go ten frames forward.
And move the shape up until here.
I set the stroke to five.
Change this stroke to ten.
It's better now.
Now add a trim path modifier to the shape.
Zoom in a bit.
First of all, nothing of the shape should be visible so set and parameter to zero and create a key
frame.
Go three frames forward.
Now the shape should be set to 100.
Press you to see the keyframes.
Easy is the second key frame of the position of the shape to make its final movement a bit smoother.
Then create a key frame for a start parameter.
Set it to 100.
Go five frames backward and set it to zero.
Now the shape starts appearing, and as it goes to the end, it disappears.
Let's have a look.
Now we want to repeat the shape.
Contents.
Add.
Choose Repeater.
Enable title action save.
All three of them move together.
We don't want to repeat this imposition.
We want it happen in rotation.
So the number of the copies to eight and set its exposition to zero.
And set the rotation to 45 degrees to have the copies in equality stances.
Now we have this.
Let me disable title action safe.
In order to make it more interesting, I add another shape.
Press control shave to create the shape exactly from center and completely symmetry.
Now we have created the Ellipse.
Move it below the repeater.
Open it.
Remove its field.
Open ellipse path.
Create a keyframes for its size.
Drag it to frame ten.
Go to the first frame and set it to zero.
Now is he eased the second key frame.
Let's have a look.
Up in a stroke and create a keyframe for a stroke with a keyframe in the beginning.
Go to this frame.
Here.
Set it to 20.
At the end set it to zero.
It should be said, and zero in the beginning as well.
Let's see.
It is very wide.
So set it on 15.
It is the first and last frame and said this one on Otto busier.
It's better now.
Let's limit the work area here.
The circle should be a bit smaller from these lines.
So move the indicator to the middle of the animation.
Double click on the last key frame of the size of the ellipse.
Now decrease its value to make it better.
Let's see how it looks.
These lies appear so fast.
Therefore move the Anki frames here to prevent them from appearing so fast.
Go back a bit.
It's fine.
To make it even better.
I duplicate this ellipse and drag it here and change its color to yellow.
A bit to the right.
Change its capacity to 60.
As you see using repeater.
We have made such a thing and you can create better examples as you like and based on your creativity.