The next modifier we will talk about is round corner.
We have a square here and we want to add round corner modifier to it.
Immediately after we add the modifier to this shape, its corners become smoother.
Inside the modifier we have reduced parameter.
By that you can adjust the smoothness of the corners.
You may wonder what's the difference between this modifier and the roundness parameter in the shape
layer?
Now.
I will explain it for you.
Let me delete this.
I sell it.
Its roundness to zero.
Sometimes after you create a rectangle, you may want to adjust it manually, so you convert it to busier
paths.
Then you apply some changes to it like this.
After that, you may need to make the corners smoother.
In this case, you won't have round this parameter in a shape layer.
So you need to use round corner modifier to make the corners of the shape smoother.
Okay.
The first example is a notification.
Open contents.
This is the rectangle we have created.
We want to create this notification.
First.
Let me let this.
I click on the contents, I select rounded Rectangle Tool.
Then I create a rectangle here.
I move it beneath the shaped layers.
I open a rectangle path and increase its roundness.
I move it up it to maintain its symmetry.
Now we need to add a triangle here.
So you have to convert the shape to busier path.
Then using pencil, I create a triangle here.
Now we need to make these corners smoother.
Here we don't have roundness anymore.
So we select rectangle and add round corner modifier.
Immediately the corners gets rounded.
You can also control the roundness of the corners easily.
Now we want this corner to get smoother and we don't want these corners to get rounded.
So alter and left, click on the point to see the handles.
Hold down alt and make these corners sharp using handles.
Do the same thing for the other points.
Strides in the hand also.
Now only the corners we want will become rounded with round corner.
So when you reveal a point handles round corner won't affect that points and round corner will only
affect the corners that their handles are not revealed.
Let's go to the next example.
In this example, we want to create such esteem for this shape.
We have such an animation.
We want to create such a steam using round corner.
So I delight this shape player.
Let me zoom in.
We create a shape close to this part of the coffee cup?
Exactly.
In the size of the opening door of the coffee cup.
Disable its stroke.
Change its field color to color of the stroke of the coffee cup.
Open rectangle to let this stroke.
Increase its size in y axis.
Set it to ten.
Said this 1 to 30.
Now duplicate this rectangle.
Open IT settings, move it up a bit and make it tangent of the rectangle.
Decrease its size in x axis.
Then add a repeater modifier.
Set copies to 20 open transform.
Said position ex of the repeater to zero and increase y position until the shapes become completely
tangent to each other.
It's fine.
Increase its scale in X direction.
Now as it goes up, its scale will increase.
We can edit its crookedness by moving the anchor points.
We add wiggle transfer modifier to the shape and place it below the repeater.
Open transform of the wiggle transfer set position X to 15 to change its shape like this.
Now we add merge path modifier.
To let its stroke.
At path to turn all shapes into a single shape.
Finally we add round corner modifier to it to make it seem like a steam or smoke.
Let's see.
Let me swallow the layer to only see the layer.
It's a bit fast.
Open wriggle transfer, said Weagle.
Second to 0.5.
Sometimes this shapes get apart from each other to prevent it.
We should decrease x a bit.
We set it to ten.
It's better to decrease the size of the second rectangle.
Then open the repeater and decrease the offset of the shape until where the original shape is.
Create a keyframe for its offset.
Then at the second six, move the offset to zero.
Let's see.
It's OC.
Exit the solo mode to see the whole animation.
Exactly in a frame that the door of the cop stands on the cop.
We should set the beginning of the shape layer, move it down a bit.
Exactly beneath the cop.
Now we should mask the shape in order to see the shape in this area and make it hidden here.
So select the layer, select the pen tool.
Now enable the tool creates mask.
Now start creating mask.
Said the father on 50.
Let's see.
Move the shape a beat up.
Now it looks better.
We can set the capacity of the layer on Thursday to look better.
This was another use of round corner modifier.
Good luck.