The next modifier is train path.
We have created such notification and we have animated in this way.
Now we want to animate this circle and these lines using tree path.
Open shape player.
Open contents.
First of all, we want the circle to create.
So click on ellipse and add train path modifier to eight.
Now open the modifier layer.
The first option is a start.
By this option, you can remove the shape from the beginning point of the shape.
And end means this will happen from the ending point.
I've said is used for moving the shape you have created.
As you see, you can easily move this area using a set parameter.
I create a simple animation for this circle.
I said the start on 100 to hide the stroke in the beginning.
After ten frames, I set it to zero to appear completely.
Let's have a look.
As you see, when the train path is applying, it is applied on the field as well.
This makes the animation an interesting.
To prevent this, we duplicate the ellipse.
The light train path and a stroke of the upper one.
Move it.
Benioff La Swan.
Gillette, Phil and Philip Swann.
Now, when the stroke is animating, the circle won't look uninteresting.
Its animation is a bit fast.
I set the second keyframe on one second.
Let's see.
It's a little slow.
Set it on 20 frames and easy is both key frames.
It's OC.
I want to make the stroke corners smoother.
So I open a stroke and select round cap.
Now we should animate these lines.
In order to animate these lines with one train path.
Select all three of them.
Press control g to move them inside the group.
At the train path for this group.
Now we should animate the start.
You see, the layers are animating in this direction.
We want them to animate in the opposite direction.
So we use and all three lines are now animating at the same time.
But we don't want this.
We want this line to be animated, first of all, and then this line and finally, this one.
Therefore in three multiple shapes.
You should select individually.
Now you see the lines are animating from the third line, but we don't want that and we want them to
animate from upper lines.
So we should change the order of the shapes.
That's okay now.
When the notification reaches this point, we create a keyframe for any parameter, and after 30 frames
we set it on 100.
Easy is its key frames.
Let's have a look.
OC You can create such an animation using three path.
Another thing that you should learn is that if you want to start from this point.
You should open shape and open lips of the stroke.
And right click on its ellipse path and convert it to busier path to be able to see its point.
Select the point that you want the train path to be animated from there.
Right click and from Mask and Shape Path.
Select Set first where Text.
Now you see, the start point of the animation will be from that point.
Look at here.
The next example is this one that you can create for the growth of the plans.
We want to remake it.
So to create this, we go to the end of the animation and select the stem of the planter.
Disable the keyframes of the three path.
Delete the train path modifiers which are applied.
They say, well, the animation of the Last Circle as well.
Go to the last key frame in which the circle is completed and yellow trim path.
Okay.
Now simply create a trim path in the contents of the circle.
The stroke.
Zooming then from the frame that the seed enters the circle.
Exactly.
From here it should start animating.
Open stream path.
Create a key frame for its starter.
Go to any frames forward and set it to 100.
Select two key frames and apply time.
Reverse keyframe to reverse it.
Easy is both of the key frames.
Move the keyframes back a bit.
Good.
When the circle completed, we start animating the stem of the plant.
Open this down layer contents base.
This is the main shape of this term of this plant.
Then instead of adding a train path here, I copy this one.
Click on the base and press control V.
Then we open three paths and increase keyframes distance.
Exactly the amount of camera movements.
Move the key frame here.
The first key frame of the camera is here.
Move the first key frame of the train path here.
Said.
The second key frame of the circle here in order to start the animation of this time of the plant as
it finishes.
Now why this term of the plant is animating, the camera is moving as well.
It moves until here.
Here.
This demo of the flower should be created.
So we copy this train path.
Select this shape and press control V.
Open the shape.
After 20 frames.
Move this key frame here.
Let's see.
Good.
The next shape is this one.
Now, you should animate this one.
These are the rest of the shapes.
Copy this train path again.
Select the next shape and press control v.
Go forward.
This is the next shape.
So like this.
Control, we go forward.
This is the next shape.
Select this control V.
We go up there and this shape.
Press control V.
Let's see.
As you see, when the main stem reaches to the stem of the flowers, their animation begins.
And after that, the animation of the flowers starts.
Sometimes it happens to start from the end point like this.
To solve this, click on the Reverse Path button.
Okay, let's have a look.
To learn how to animate the hands and bushes around the scene.
Follow us to the end of this chapter.
This example was one of the most useful ways using tree path.
Good luck.