The next modifier we will talk about is taste.
I have created a line here and I will apply to it straight.
As I add the modifier, as you see, the line starts twisting.
This modifier is used to twist a shapes open the modifier.
The first parameter is angle by which it can define the amount of this twist.
The next parameter is center that determines the axis of twisting.
I change its exposition and place it here.
So I increase its value in x axis until here and decrease its angle.
Now, if I scale down the shape and place its anchor point here.
You can create this shape.
Let's go to the examples.
We can create such a shapes using this modifier.
I start with this one.
Open the candy group.
And open the twist group.
I have created this using twist.
I delighted.
I have created this stroke here.
At the Tour street.
If I increase the angle a bit, this spiral will happen in the center of this shape.
But we don't want this.
We want the center of this spiral to be here.
So I increase the y axis of the terrorist until it's n placed exactly here I increased the amount of
the terrorist.
Move with a bit upper.
As you see, we can create shapes like this so easily.
The next example we created with Twist is this one.
Open the share player.
Contents.
Open the candy group and then peace.
Here we have created this using two modifiers to east and repeater.
Repeater is used to repeat these and twist is for twisting this shape to remake it.
Ideally, twist and repeater.
I have created a circle in the beginning and I have cropped this shape from it.
Then I have added this modifier to it.
After I add to its modifier, I select a piece group and add repeater modifiers to it.
Often repeat their change its value to four.
Change its exposition to zero.
Then set the rotation parameter to 90 to have the same distance from each other.
Then open to us and adjust its center to turn into the shape that we want.
Seems good.
OC As you see, we created such a shape using two and repeater modifiers.