The next modifier we will talk about is wiggle path.
I have created a stroke here.
At the wiggle path to the shape.
Their shape gets a bit rougher.
Open legal path.
We have some parameters here.
The first one is size that lets you control the size of these vibrations.
The next parameter is detail, which lets you increase or decrease the amount of these vibrations.
You see, I increase and decrease them.
The next parameter is point that makes the points of these vibrations sharp or smooth.
I set it on corner for now.
The next parameter is wiggle second, which shows you the amount of the wiggle per second.
For example, now it is set on two.
I change it to ten.
You see, it is now so quick.
I change it back to two.
The next one is correlation.
It is the relation between two things.
It controls the resemblance of the movements of the points which are next to each other.
If we decrease it to something like ten, the similarity of motion of points which are next to each
other will decrease so much, and accordingly we will have more vibration.
And if we increase it to something like 97, the similarity of motion of the points which are next to
each other will be the same.
Therefore, we will have less vibrations and we will have smooth movements.
I reset it to 50 again.
The next parameter is temporal phase.
It is used to animate the wiggle manually.
Now if I play, it wiggles randomly.
For example, in second one.
I don't want it to be like this.
I want it to be like this.
To do this, I use this parameter.
For example, in the beginning I said we go second to zero.
You see, when I play it, we won't have animation anymore.
I create a keyframe for temporal phase, and at the second one, I want such a situation to be created.
I created this manually.
And if I want to stop it, I can do it using this parameter.
The next parameter is spatial phase, which is exactly like temporal phase.
The difference between these two is a bit technical.
Temporal phase moves the ways in horizontal direction.
I mean a long x axis.
The spatial phase moves the waves along the y axis.
They are usually used to apply changes manually.
Random speed is also used to make the waves of the shape random.
Now let's go to the examples.
We want to create this animation.
You see, as the charger connects to the phone, these waves are created by wiggle path.
We want to create this animation now.
I deleted the wiggle passes of the shapes to create them again and have the same waves.
We want to make this line around the phone to wiggle, just as the charger cable connects to the phone.
So we enter the mobile layer shake.
It is the layer of the line around the phone.
I had a visual path to it.
Now I create a keyframe for the size of the wiggle path.
Press You return back to the frame that the charger cable is disconnected from the mobile and set the
size to zero.
I play to see the result.
The animation of this line is not synchronized with the animation of the wiggle of the mobile.
So open the shape and set its regal second to ten.
Let's see.
Good.
I disable vehicle path for now.
Note that here I have created a path with some points which have the same distance from each other to
have synchronized vehicle.
But if the points didn't have same distance from each other, the Wiggles would be like this.
And they're not good.
So pay attention while creating a shape.
You should have points with same distance in order to have same visual pathways.
I copy wiggle path.
Open a screen layer.
I want to add, we go to the green circle.
Open green layer.
Press Control V.
Let me see.
Where are the keyframes?
I should move to keyframes here.
All right.
It's Miguel is okay.
Just I think it's details are not sufficient.
So I increase its details.
It's good.
We should create Miguel for this line, too.
So I copy.
Miguel path.
Open line.
In this frame that the first key frame is set.
Select the line and press control V.
Let's see.
Good.
Price you to see the keyframes.
Wriggle is applied from here until here.
Just framed the mobile doesn't have wiggle anymore.
And the charger is disconnected from the mobile.
So we should copy the keyframes of the visual path here.
Copy of these two Control V.
And reverse.
We should do the same with the vehicle path of the line around the mobile.
Copy paste.
Reverse.
Let's have a look.
OC.
This was another usage of visual path by which you can create such waves.