Okay, let's talk about the next modifier which will transfer.
I have created a shape layer inside it.
I have created three template shapes.
Now let's add wiggle transfer modifier to the contents.
Open modifiers menu and select wiggle transfer.
It creates some wiggle and random transforms for our shapes.
Now if I play.
Nothing will happen.
Why?
Because in regard to transform and transform section, we should first change position, scale and rotation
in order to let the modifier animate the shape.
For example, I said position x to ten and play it.
You see these shapes wiggle in exposition.
Let me change.
It's my position.
You see, they're moving in both X and Y position.
Here we have eagles and we talked about that in wiggle path modifier.
It is the amount of wiggle per second.
By that you can increase or decrease its speeds.
The next one is correlation that we talked about in visual path modifier.
It is used to increase or decrease the amount of shaking of the vehicle.
I told you about temporal phase and a special phase by them.
You can control your wiggles manually.
And random seed as its name applies.
It is used to change the random vehicle.
This is transformed by this.
You can control the vehicle happen in which properties position scale.
As you see their scale is changing or rotation.
You see, the rotation is also changing.
Let me tell you a tip when we want to add another shape to the contents.
So I click here and create it.
Now you see, we got Transform is applied to this shape and its position.
Rotation and scale is changing like the other ones.
Now I want to create a multiplication sign.
Let me disable wiggle modifier.
I disable its feel.
I enable wiggle transform to it.
You see this shape don't rotate from its center because its anchor point is almost at this point.
Let me select the shape you see.
It's anchor point is here.
If I move the anchor point to the center, let me disable it, enable it again.
You see, nothing changed.
We cannot rotate this shape from the center using wiggle transfer.
To help it.
It is better to use one of these template shapes.
Let me disable wiggle transfer.
Then convert it to busier path, then convert it to busier path and by editing the shape, create a
new one.
Now you see the shape transforms from its centre and it is no longer a concern.
So it is better to make them from the template shapes and change it to the shape you want.
Now we know exactly what we call transform does.
So let's go to the examples in this example.
We want to create such a plan.
When the phone heats the ground, these shapes should come out of it and have such wiggle.
The animation of the shapes are made using wiggle transfer.
So let's go to the example.
We have such a plan and we want to animate these elements using visual transfer.
We drag the beginning of the layer to this point, appear this scale, create a keyframe here and go
to the second key frame of the page and create a second keyframe for a scale.
Go back to the first keyframe and place the anchor point of the elements layer here.
It will scale from this point.
Then said the first scale frame on zero.
Now as we all transform to the elements.
Open Contents.
Select contents and add visual transform to.
Now, said Weagle second on one.
Said exposition on ten.
And said the Y position on ten.
Says rotation on 50 and set the scale on ten.
Let's have a look.
As you see, when we add, we will transform to these elements.
Some problems occur since we will transform wiggles every shapes separately.
Therefore, the shapes have a mess here.
To prevent this mess.
We move, we will transform above these two groups.
So the we shall transform won't be applied to this happy face.
And this like it.
As you see, seems the anchor point of this heart is here and it is rotating around it.
It is not correct.
So to solve this, I disable vehicle transfer.
Select contents.
And then I use the rectangle shape and create a square here.
After that, we convert it to busier path to change its path.
Then I edit the shape again.
Then we change its name.
Let me change its feel.
Now we delete the previous heart.
Enable the vehicle transform again.
As you see, the heart is rotating and moving around its own center and it is not moving this way.
Now, how should I add, will transform to these groups.
The open sticker group transfer position.
And here we use wiggle expression.
As you see, it moves as well.
So to apply the same thing for its rotation, we paste this to the rotation, so we increase the frequency
a bit.
We do the same thing with like.
We apply it to the rotation to.
Let's have a look to see how is the animation now?
Now we apply a side to this scale to be softer.
It's okay now.