OC last modifier is zigzag.
As its name implies, it is used to make the shape like zigzag.
Well, I have created a line open the layer and from the modifiers list adds the exact modifier.
Immediately after I added these modifiers.
The exact shape.
All opinions.
The first parameter is size.
You can change the size of the zigzag using this.
The next parameter is used to increase the number of the zigzags.
And the last parameter point is used to make the corners of the zigzag line sharper or softer.
After introducing it.
Let's see its usages in motion graphics.
This is my first example.
As you see, you can create such a waves using zigzag modifier.
Let's see, how can we create such a wave?
Open the next composition.
We want to change this line into waves using zigzag modifier.
First, I enable action safe.
I just remind the area I want this wave to be on.
Let me zoom in to be more accurate.
From this point.
Until here.
Then I add zig zag modifier to this line.
Go to the base wave layer and add zig zag modifier to it.
Open zig zag modifier increase its size to seven.
Placed a ruler.
Exactly.
On this point of the zigzag.
Then we should add trim path modifier to the shape as well.
And we should remove this part.
Och, it should be 18.
Let me solo de la here.
We go to the beginning of the timeline and create a keyframe for the offset parameter of the shape.
Create a keyframe for his position as well.
Press you to show the keyframes.
We go ten frames forward.
Move upset forward until the shape reaches its end.
Exactly here.
-65.
After that, we move the shape back using position X parameter.
It's okay.
Then we should look the position.
We should look to offset parameter as well.
Now you see the shape seems like it's going forward, but it is not like a wave.
So we open, zigzag and set the point to smooth.
Let's see how it is.
That's what I wanted.
At.
It seems just like a wave.
On Solo de la.
Och, it's a bit fast.
Move the keyframes a bit forward.
The wave is ready.
The next thing we need to do here is when the boat goes inside the water, this part of the wave should
be opened.
So I alphington wear this layer to the above layer to open this part as the boat impacts the water.
It's okay.
There is just something wrong.
That's when the boat goes inside the water.
The bottom part of it that goes into the water shouldn't be seen.
So we duplicate this layer and move it above the boats layer.
We set it to no track matter.
Let me follow the boat and wave.
Then we delete the train path and edit the shape.
I disable the stroke and open shape.
They feel to it and change its color to the background color.
Then alpha convertible layer to the neo layer we've created.
Let's see the animation.
As you see, it's totally fine.
As the ball impacts the water, the part behind the water won't be shown anymore.
Well, one of the good usages of this modifier is such a way that you can easily create with the help
of this modifier.
Good luck.