Hello, everyone.
And before starting the training course, let me briefly explain about the tools I need in the process
of creating the motion graphics in this course.
The tool I used in this tutorial to change the graph of keyframes and create spring animations is the
motion to script, which of course it's not free.
So those who have this script and don't know how to work with it can easily watch the working with the
motion to a script course and get acquainted with all the tools available here and those who doesn't
have this script or cannot afford it should not worry, because we can also do manually the things we
did with this script in this course.
For example, I make an animation for this square.
And in order to easy ease the keyframes, it just need to go to the Keyframe assistant and select the
easy ease.
As you see when I go to the speed graph in graph ed.
A graph like this will be shown.
And when the shape gets the frame, nine and ten has its highest speed.
At first the speed is low.
Then it increases and finally it decreases again.
Well, this is the easy ease mood in which in the beginning and at the end of the movement, the animation
speed reduces.
If I want to use the motion to escape, I will use this option.
For example, I set it to 70%.
The speed will decrease in the beginning and the end of the animation look.
And here this points indicate the frames and the speed is slower at first because more frames are shown
here in the middle.
The speed is higher because less frames are shown here.
And at the end the animation speed reduces.
You can make changes to your graph using this slider in full control.
As you see both the graph and the spots that exist in the animating path will change.
The more I increase it, the more the speed of the beginning and ending of the animation decreases and
in the middle of the speed increases.
So this option is for easy ease the keyframe.
When this option is at the left, it makes the keyframes linear and the animate will be completely linear.
And in no part of it does this speed increase or decrease.
And when it is at 100, as you see, the animation would be easy out at the beginning.
The speed is low and it increases in the end.
This last option when I set it to zero.
As you see here, the key frame will be toggle hold and the animation is done in a frame as a jump.
And then I set it to 100.
The animation will be easy and it means that the speed is high at the beginning and lowers at the end.
As you see, I can do all of that here using this handles as well.
I see.
I can easily do the same using these handles and I don't need to use these options.
But the only difference is that a reward gets faster.
The next tip I'm going to give you is the excite option.
Let me set the animation an easy out mode so that the speed is low at the beginning and it increases
at the end.
And I want to create a spring animation for it.
I select the keyframes and apply the side option to it.
Now, if you take a look, you'll see that the spring animation is created for the shape.
I go to the effect controls.
And here the first option overshoot, which is the same as amplitude, and shows the distance that the
shape takes from its original position.
If I set this to ten, the shape distance from the last key frame position will reduce.
The next option is bounce, which is the same as frequency and shows the reciprocity of this layer.
For example, when it's on 40, it goes this much when it's on to any.
It will go almost half of this.
And the last option is frixion, which is the same as decay.
That the more I increase it, the spring animation is stopped sooner and the more I decrease it, it
will stop later.
For example, I want to increase it and set it to 80.
Look what happens.
It is stopped soon.
But if I set it to 20.
As you see, it took longer to stop.
Everything I just did depends on whether I have the motion to script.
But what should I do if I don't have this script?
In order for those who doesn't have this script to be able to go along with us through creating the
animation during the course.
First, I delete these expressions and effects created by the motion to a script and paste expression
related to creating this spring animation here.
Now, if I play, you'll see that I was able to create the same animation I made using the motion to
script.
Using this expression too.
As you see, its amplitude is high, so I'll set these to 0.5.
It is still can be less than this.
And exactly the same values I had there.
I have here.
This is the amplitude, which is actually the overshoot.
Frequency is actually the bouncing and DK is actually the friction in motion to escape.
Only their names have changed.
I will put this expression in the course resources folder so that you can use it to create your own
spring and bouncing animations.
That's it for now.
I did not make much use of the other options available in motion to a script.
If you want to get acquainted with all the options of this script, which can help you a lot in creating
beautiful motion graphics, you can get and watch the motion to a script training course.
Good luck.