In this session, we're going to talk about shapes.
There are two ways for creating a shape.
The first one is manually in which you use pen tool and create the shape.
I select pen tool.
I click once.
After the first click, the first point will be created and one shape layer will create in timeline.
Hold down shift, click one more time and create a straight line.
I click again and create a square.
There are some other tools in this menu, for example, at Vertex Tool.
It allows us to create a vertex in any point that we want.
The next tool is delete vertex.
Like its name by this tool you can delete Vertex.
The next one is converse Vertex tools.
Using this tool, you can edit vertex.
If I click on a point using this tool point handles of the shape will appear.
Thus you can edit them.
As you see, normally when you start editing, you can edit just one handle.
But if you want to move both handles together, you should hold alt and click on the points and drag
it.
How can we open a shape after closing it?
For example, if you want to open your shape from this side.
You should select two points of the side.
You want to open the shape from right click and from Mask and Shape Path.
Uncheck the closed option.
You see the shape open from the side that you choose.
Press control there to undo it.
This was the manual way.
There is another way that you can use this parametric shapes to create your shape.
Be careful that none of the layers must be selected in timeline.
Since if, for example, this shape layer was selected and you create a rectangle.
As you see, this rectangle won't be placed in a separate shape layer and it will be created in a layer
of the previous one.
And we don't want this.
We want to place the rectangle in a new shape layer.
So we unselect all layers and start drawing.
As you see, when I drag, the shape is created from its corner and I can define its length and width.
But if I hold shift, all sides will be symmetric.
So this was the second method.
The difference between these two methods is that in first method, by using convert vertex tool, you
could edit your points.
But in the second one, if you select the tool, you can't do that.
But never mind using convert to base your path tool.
You can edit rectangle paths.
To do this.
Open Shape Layer.
Contents.
Rectangle Rock.
Click on Rectangle Path and select Convert to busier path.
Now you can edit the shape using convert vertex tool.
Price controls are there to undo it.
Okay, let's go to the next parameter shape rounded rectangle.
This is a rectangle that has rounded corners.
Hold shape to have symmetrical sides.
While dragging.
You can increase or decrease the roundness of the corners by scrolling.
Now am decreasing.
Let me make it bigger.
Now I'm craving the roundness.
The next one is Ellipse tool, with which you can create circles.
You can hold down control in order to create the circle from the center and from the point that you
click on.
And also by holding shift and control, you can create an accurate round circle and it won't turn into
Ellipse.
The next one is Polygon Tool.
Let me create one.
I hold down control to be created from the center.
I also hold down shift to have equal sides by scrolling.
You can decrease or increase the shape sides.
As you see, when I created this shape, I forgot to deselect the previous shape layer.
Therefore, the shape is placed inside the previous shape layer.
I don't want this, so I like this shape and select the circle.
Now I start making the new shape layer.
Well, the next one is a star tool and you can create a stars using it.
By scrolling.
You can increase or decrease its wings.
By holding control, you can adjust the wings length.
You see, I'm holding down control and I can adjust the wings length.
You can do all these things only if you hold down left click of your mouse.
Otherwise, if you release it, it won't be possible anymore.