In this session, we're going to talk about filling a stroke of the shapes.
I create a rounded rectangle in the center of the scene.
I increase its roundness by scrolling.
OC It's good.
As you see, when we select a shape at the top, three options appear fill, stroke and width, which
is the width of the stroke.
Here we can select the field color of the shape.
I click on it and change its color.
If you click on field text, a window will appear that has a couple of options in it.
The first one is none with which the field will be removed from the shape.
The second option is solid color.
It fills our shape with one single color.
The next one linear gradient.
It makes us a gradient.
And with the help of these handles, you can adjust the combination amount of the colors.
And the last option is radial gradient, which makes you a radial gradient here, the capacity and you
can adjust its transparency by this option.
You see, I can adjust the combination amount of this gradients by using this handle.
Also, I can come here and by clicking on this button, change its color.
And also this one.
So we can change the color of the gradient.
Stroke is the same as feel.
It has non cells, color, linear gradients and radial gradients.
And here is the opacity.
By clicking here, you can change the colors as well.
And here is its width and you can change its thickness.
You have these options in timeline on the rectangle path.
Set this on solid color.
It will feel.
And if it was gradient, this would be gradient too.
Here you can disable or enable the stroke here.
Or enable or disable feel I open a stroke.
The first option is composite, and you can choose the stroke to be below the other objects or above
them.
Since now the stroke is above the field.
It is not recognizable.
I will move it below the field.
Now this stroke is below other objects.
If I select above, the stroke will be placed above the other objects, although its below fail.
Let me change it to default and move it above the field.
The next option is color.
You could change it from here as well, and you can change your opacity from this part as well.
Stroke width is the thickness of it.
Here is line chap.
Let me create a line here to explain.
Line cap better disable title action save.
Upon the stroke of this shape to explain line cap.
This option makes the end of your lines, Cap.
Or round.
Or projection that includes the whole path in it.
If it is set to bad cap, it will be placed at the end of path.
So long cap is for the end of lines and line join is for the corners.
For example I changed line join to round you see the corner will change into round either makes it sharp
round makes it round and bevel makes the corner like bevel.
The next option, which is important is Dash.
You can change the stroke into dashes by clicking on this plus icon.
By dash property, you can increase the length of dashes.
I press.
Plus, once more, your property increases the space between these dashes.
So gap increases, the space between dashes and dash increases the length of dashes.
And I've said we'll move these dashes.
Now open field property.
Here we have composite, which is the same as a stroke.
This places the field under other layers.
And above previous in same group places the layer above the others.
By choosing this, although feel is below this stroke, this option places feel above the others.
I said this to its default setting.
The next option is field rule, which is used when your shape is too complicated.
Let me explain it briefly.
For this kind.
Things we often feel when it is said a non zero widening the field contains the whole shape and its
visible are over the shape, but in even odd mode, close areas of the shape won't contain the feel.
Let's go back to our example.
I explained field rule.
Color is obvious and we already know opacity.
So these were fuel parameters.
But here if we set feel on linear.
They feel will change into gradient feel and we will have more options as well.
You cancer type two radial or linear?
In order to make the handles of the gradient visible select gradient feel and then select pen behind
tool.
As you see, the handles appear.
Star point is this one which shows the area of the first color and end point is the second one, which
shows the area of the second color.
And here we have a combination of two colors in color property.
It can choose colors.
And here you can set its opacity.
For example, you can set it to zero.
You see here it disappears.
And this is the capacity of the whole gradient.
And the next part we will discuss about the rest of the shape parameters.