In this lesson.
We're going to talk about the rest of the shape parameters.
First of all, I create a rectangle.
The first parameter is content.
In front of this parameter.
There is an option called ADD, which was also here.
By adoption, you can add some functions to this content.
I click on this triangle and menu will open.
The first one is group.
By this it can create group and put layers in it.
I have rectangle, ellipse, Alley Star and path.
I click on ellipse you see an ellipse created.
Ollie's Star makes a star.
And in this section you can create field, stroke, gradient feel and gradient stroke for the shape.
And from here you can create modifiers for shape.
We will explain them in the next session.
When you open content, there is a rectangle and it's very small.
In the rectangle I have fill and a stroke I have explained about before I open the rectangle path.
It can change its size.
The difference between size and scale is that if you increase the scale, the strokes thickness will
increase as well.
But when you increase the size, the stroke thickness won't change.
By this parameter, it can change the position of the shape, and by the next parameter you can change
the roundness of the corners of the shape.
This parameter reverses the path.
To explain it more.
I added train pass modifier and place it on their feline stroke.
I don't feel for now.
A stroke is enough.
I animate a start.
You see, it starts animating from this point.
If I want the animation to start in this direction, I should click on this icon and you see its direction
changes so it reverses the path.
So this option reverses the path direction.
I delete this.
I enable field.
I place it here.
I create a rounded rectangle.
Open it up.
Rectangle path.
Rounded rectangle has the same parameters that the rectangle had.
The only difference is that the roundness is set on 65 while it was zero for rectangle.
I don't this.
The next one is El.
I create an ellipse and open it.
Slager.
Here.
I just have size and position.
The next one is Polygon Open Poly Star Path.
As you see here, I have different parameters from type.
You can select Polygon or a star.
Point defines the size of the shape.
We know our position and rotation.
Outer radius is for its size.
Outer roundness softens the corners.
The next one is a star.
I don't need to create a star.
Just I go to the poly star path and change the type.
You see, the parameters changed in a radius, which changes the inner radius of the star.
How the radius is four wings length.
In there.
Roundness is for softness of the inner corners of the star.
Outer roundness is for the softness of the outer corners, and I have explained the other parameters
before.
The important point to say here is that every shape has its own transformed parameter.
By which you can apply individual changes to any shape.
And in spite of the fact that every shape has its own transformed parameter, every layer has a separate
transform parameter.
You see, when I change the position, both shapes move together.
When I rotate it, both shapes rotate together.
This helps you have more control on the shapes.
For example, I drag it here, make a keyframe, and at the second one, it comes here.
This shape moves.
I want to rotate the poly star while moving.
They shape, layer moves, and meanwhile the police are rotate.
You can do the same thing for this square.
I create a keyframe for position of the rectangle in time line.
After half of a second, I drag it up.
At second one, I paste the first keyframe here to move the rectangle down again.
Finally, I got this animation.