In this session.
We want to talk about taper and wave options.
These are updated options for a stroke.
In this session, we'll explain how to use these options and their applications in projects.
I have created a stroke here since taper and valve options are used for strokes.
I open its contents in a stroke parameter under dash parameter.
You can see taper and wave parameters.
Taper is used to make the start and end of a stroke thinner.
Open taper.
The first parameter is the length units.
Using this parameter, you can set your taper based on Pearson's or pixels.
I set it on.
Pearson's start length is used to make the starting point of this stroke narrower as I increase this
value.
It becomes narrower from the start point when it is 100.
Start taper continues to the end.
And if you change it to pixel, its highest value is 600 pixels.
If you decrease it, it will become thicker.
It applies taper from the starting point based on pixel.
I changed it to percent and set this to 100.
So start length is for starting point and end.
Length is for end point.
I said both of them to 50.
Using a start with you can change the width of strokes starting points.
And with is for its end with as well.
Start ease softens the starting point.
And and ease softens the end point.
These were parameters for taper option.
Let's go to wave.
Wave, as its name implies, makes the stroke wavy.
Open wave.
The first parameter is a mount.
It makes these waves.
You can set the amount of the waves.
The next parameter is units.
Unit creates waves based on pixel.
It makes one wave every 100 pixels.
As you increase this number, your waves will decrease.
The next parameter is cycle.
You can set how many waves should a path have?
For example, I set it to three.
You see?
One, two, three.
The last parameter is phase.
It can animate your way of using this parameter.
Now that you're introduced to wave and taper.
Let's go to the examples.
The first example is making such trays for the ship.
And also make these clouds.
So we want to create this case.
To create this idea, let the shape trace and create them again to completely understand how to use
these options.
I create a stroke here?
After creating this stroke increase its width.
I move it beneath the shape layer and move it down.
Now change its color to pink.
Up in content shape.
Open a stroke and then set the start length to 100%.
Increase its start with increased the stroke size a bit more.
Now open wave and increase its amount.
Change it to cycle and set it to three.
Now to have a continuous animation, I'll click on a stopwatch of the phase.
Type.
Time expression for its phase.
You see, the animation of the ship Trace is created so easily.
Let me increase it.
Start with a bit more.
That's better now.
Now duplicate this shape.
Up in a stroke.
Change its color to allow their color.
Move it beneath the first shape and increase its width.
It will be better if it's a bit lighter.
Now duplicate this shape again, move it above the first shape and decrease its width.
Then open wave.
Change cycle to five.
Increase its way to create such line in the middle.
Increase its amount a bit more.
Change it to 100.
To create two other lines here.
Let me change its name to wave, to replicate this layer.
Open it.
The lead shape three and shape one and only keep shape to open a stroke.
Increase its width.
Open Taper.
Change it.
Start.
Let's have a look.
Now rename layer two wave line.
Duplicate this layer change wave lines is true color to white.
Apply Alpha inverted Matt to it.
You see, this is created.
Up and contents of the wave line to.
And decrease the stroke with a bit.
So easily.
We created this wave line as well.
Now we want to create such clouds.
Let me hide these.
To create these clouds.
I create a stroke.
It creates its width.
Renamed a layer to cloud.
Opening stroke.
Set the start length to 40.
Set and length to 60.
Now open wave and increase its amount.
And make it start a bit softer.
And it's and is OC.
I'll click on stopwatch of the phase and type time expression for its phase.
It is a bit fast.
Said it to -50.
Now we should create a layer for the matter of the cloud.
Disable its stroke and enable it to feel.
Renamed the layer to match Layer.
Now I apply alpha inverter to the cloud to only see the part which is out of the shape.
Let's have a look.
So we can do such a things with the clouds using taper and wafer.
Then move it to the camp and do the same thing that we've done with these layers.
And create a drop shadow for it.
So we can use taper and wave for these kinds of things.
Let's go to the next example.
The coffee cup example.
You can create such a stream for the coffee.
Let's create it.
It's really easy.
I will show you now.
Click here.
Holding down shift, click again here out of the scene.
Then disable, feel and enable the stroke.
Change their stroke with as you wish its end to be.
It's good to be this much.
Then open its contents.
The latch is filled up and Taper said its start length to 100%.
Increase it.
Start with.
Now open a mount and set it to 50.
I think it's better to be on 35 type time expression for its phase.
Then we want to steam fades as it goes up.
So select the layer upon the stroke and select linear gradient.
Here you can select the color you want, like red.
You see, we don't have any red color here.
Because we should set up these handles to see the handles.
Select gradient stroke and click on Pan behind Tool.
Then move there.
Start here at the end button of the stroke and move the end up.
Now as you see Star, these one and end is red.
We don't want the red color.
We want white here.
It's color can be selected.
And from this part you can change its capacity.
I want to set its end opacity to zero.
It can set your opacity gradient using this handle.
I move it a bit down.
Okay, let's see.
Yes, it's okay.
I should move this layer below the coffee cup layer.
Then when the coffee cup is stops should start coming out of this hole.
To do this move, the starting point of the layer here that it's store is fixed and the coffee cup open
gradient stroke.
We should animate and point in y axis.
As I move it down, it fades.
Create a key frame for it.
Go 20 frames forward.
Then move it up again.
Let's see.
It's a bit fast.
We want to decrease its opacity in the beginning so open gradients and set the beginning opacity to
50.
It's fine.
Good luck.