In this session, we will talk about shape modifiers.
By shape modifiers, we can make changes to the shapes and passes.
To create modifiers, you should create a shape.
Here I have created a square and circle in content parameter.
If you click on this icon next to add bottom, you can see modifiers in a bottom of this menu.
The first one is mash paths and the last one is zigzag.
In this session I will talk about marriage path, so I click on marriage path and add it to the content.
Now match path is is added to the content and shape colors changed since merge path adds a separate
field and a stroke to the shape.
We don't need its fill so I disable it for now and we will just keep this stroke open.
Merge path.
Merge path like its name is used for merging and combining the shapes.
In match path.
We have mode by this option.
You can combine your shape in different ways.
Marriage is the first option.
It helps you combine both shapes together in a way that none of them overlays the other.
For example, I enable feel here.
I disable the mesh path.
I place the square here.
You see, since I moved this square here, the circle is overlaying this square.
But when you enable a path, fill and a stroke of both shapes will be visible.
This is useful when you don't want any of your shapes to be placed on another, and you want them both
to have filling stroke.
I disabled feel.
I move it back.
You can add another shape to the existing one using this option.
As you see, if I move this square closer to the circle, they will match with each other.
I drag it forward.
You see, they are merged.
If I enable Phil Now, it seems like they are a single shape.
I changed the field color.
The next one is subtract.
In this mode, the shape that is above the contents will be the main shape and below shapes will be
subtracted from the main shape.
You see, the circle is subtracted from the square.
I sweep them.
Now the square is subtracted from the circle because the main shape is the circle now.
This was subtract mode.
The next one is intersect.
It keeps the intersected part of the shapes and removes the rest of the shapes.
And the next one is exclude intersections, which is the opposite of the Intersect.
It removes the intersected part of the shapes and keeps the rest.
You see here is empty and the rest of the shape is remained oc I explained Mayr's path generally.
Now let's start examples.
The first example is two circles and a triangle.
I open content.
You see?
Here is the circle here.
I have made a triangle using polygon, a star.
You can increase or decrease its points from here.
And at last, we've made another circle.
First of all, I hide the little circle and I want to merge these two shapes.
To do this, I click on content.
Select match path from modifiers.
You see, the circle and triangle are merged now.
If I move any of them, you can see the original shapes.
After merging these two shapes.
Now I want to subtract this circle from these two shapes.
First of all, I should place the circle on their merge path.
Why?
Because modifiers affect on shapes that are placed above them.
I mean Poly star and outer lips.
To subtract this little circle from these two shapes, I should add another merge path.
We can add Mare's path from this menu, or we can duplicate this layer by pressing control D.
I moved the second marriage path below the inner ellipse.
Open it.
Click on subtract.
You see, the circle is subtracted from the previous shapes.
So we created this shape using two mesh patches.
Och, we made this locator.
This is the main plan that we want to add the locator to it.
The main plan has such animation.
OC.
We want to animate this locator.
We wanted to enter the scene from top and stop at the point of the plan that we want.
Position, said the anchor point here.
Make a keyframe for its scale.
After ten frames, create the second keyframe.
Go to the first keyframe and move the locater up.
Easy is the first two keyframes.
After the map completed.
We want the locators to calm down.
Move it back a bit.
It's slow.
I change the space between key frames to seven frames.
Good.
We want to animate its scale in y axis.
Go five frames forward, decrease its wide scale after three frames, set it to 100 again.
Easy is the middle key frame.
Let's see the result.
When the locater is coming down, it should stretch a bit.
Now select scale.
Addicted, excited.
Let's have a look.
Said overshoot to ten and said bounce to 20.
This keyframes should go forward a bit to have better speed.
Now we want to make a way for it.
So I'll create an ellipse here.
Disable its stroke.
Change the field color to a darker one.
In Lake's path animate its size.
First of all, say the two zero, create a keyframe, go ten frames forward.
Easy is the second key frame.
Duplicate the clips.
Drag it down.
Move its key frame back.
Add match pass modifiers to it.
Said mesh path is mode to subtract.
The second ellipse should be higher.
It should be like this.
Open transformed property of the layer.
Decrease its wide scale to make it seem like 3D.
Now rename it.
Place it under the locator.
Exactly in a frame that the locater stands on the map.
This shape should be created.
Och, it's good.
Let's see the result.
All right.
It's good.
So let's go to the next example.
The next example is for learning to create complex shapes.
I have created a Polly Star here.
Let me hide these ones.
I have created a poly star.
Then a circle in it.
And a smaller circle and a more smaller one.
I want to merge these ones to create a gear.
For now, I hide these circles.
I want to match these two shapes together and just keep the intersected parts.
So I select the contents and add match path.
I move my path above these two circles to prevent it from applying to the below layers and be applied
to the above layers.
By default.
It merges these two shapes together.
But we just want their intersection.
So I select Intersect.
You see now just the intersection is shown.
I want to add the second circle to these.
So I duplicate Mare's path and move it below the circle.
Set its mode to add.
Up to this point.
This gear is created.
Duplicate Mary's path again and move it below the inner circle.
Said it's more to subtract to make it center empty.
You see, now we have a gear in polyester layer.
Change the values to change the gears shape.
Eventually you can animate it easily.
Now.
I'll make it Look.
Set this on offset to have continuous animation.
The next useful example that Maersk Path is used in it.
Is this what?
In these cases, you want to keep the black area of the eye inside the white area.
And also we use match path when we want to black part disappear while it exists.
The white area.
I hide the right eye.
Open the left eye layer.
We made the shape for its eyebrows, another one for this slight part of the eye.
Another one for the black part of the eye.
One for eyelashes.
And the last one for the white area.
As you see, we've made a simple animation for blinking.
We want to hide the black part of the eye when it blinks.
So we should animate it in a way that the black part be shown just in white area of the eye.
To do this, we should subtract the light from the black part of I.
We're going to create marriage path and place it under these two.
So in order to stop its affection and the shape of the eyebrow.
Press control g to group them.
Rename it to black group.
At marriage pass modifier in the group.
Delete its stroke, set its mode to subtract.
Light is above the black.
One should be above.
Change its color to black.
OC.
The black part is ready.
If it blinks, the problem is still shown.
To solve this problem, duplicate the shape of the white area of the eye.
You see, I have animated the path of the white area of the eye to make it seem like blinking.
Duplicate this shape.
Place it above this layer.
Now group the watch area of the I and black group press control G.
And another mesh path here.
Delete this stroke.
I want to keep the intersection of these two, which is the black area of the eye.
So I set the mode on Intersect.
It's all right.
Now, pay attention.
When I moved in to cater the black part of the.
I will hide completely.
It can also move.
The black part of the eye is in transform of the black.
If it is out of the white area of the eye, it won't be shown.
This is the animation of both eyes.
To learn how to animate the blinking of this eye.
We have full animation of this example at the end of the chapter.