The next modifier is offset path.
As I told before, in order to add a modifier to the scene, we should add a shape open shape layer
in contents parameter of this layer.
There is an ad and by clicking on this button you can add any modifier you want.
I add offset pass modifier to the shape.
Up an offset path modifier of an offset path modifier.
The first parameter is a mount with which you can expand or abbreviate the shape.
It somehow like scale or size.
But there are some difference that I will explain you.
The first difference is that in order to scale down or scale up the star, you should go to Poly star
and poly star path.
You want see such parameter for size and you can just do that in transform parameter, which has some
problems that the size of this stroke will increase simultaneously, which is not interesting at all.
Go back to offset path modifier.
You can easily do this with amount.
You can scale up or down your star, although your stroke size won't change.
The next parameter is line.
Join that.
As it name implies, it changes the corners of the shape.
Now they set on miter join, which makes the corners sharp.
If you change it to round corners will change into round and bevel, adds Bevel to the corners.
I said it on miter join again.
The next parameter is miter limits.
It is used to define the sharp area of the corners.
For example, here, the angle of this part of this star is this.
But if we open Polar Star and increase the angle of these corners in inner radius, you see the shape
is now like bevel.
Let me increase my term limits.
You see, I increased the sharp area of the corners because I want its corners to be sharp in larger
radius.
I reset it.
The next parameter is copy.
Using this parameter, you can have several copy of your shape.
I set it on five.
As you see, five copies are out of the main shape.
But if you want to create the copies inside the main shape, you should change the amount to a minus
value.
Five copies are too much.
I set it on three.
I set it on to.
When a mount is set on a minus value, the copies will be created inside the main shape and if the amount
is positive, copies will be created outside it.
Copy offset is also used to offsetting the copies like this.
Now we have introduced a set path modifier briefly.
Let's go to our example.
One of the perfect usages of this modifier is for these kinds of things that you can have such a stroke
around the shape.
We want to create such a stroke for this notification.
So I OpenShift layer contents.
I delete a group of these stroke since I want to create it again.
To do this.
I use this rectangle.
Let me disable this to understand better.
I use this shape to create the stroke I mentioned.
So I duplicate this layer and move it down.
You might think that you can do this by just scaling, but that is not true.
I hide this layer, I select this shape, I reveal this layer.
I press control DT.
I want to scale it.
As you see when I scale it, that is not interesting enough.
By moving it, we can't create it easily as well.
We should try a lot to make the space between the shape and a stroke.
The same everywhere.
It's so hard and it's better for you to use a set path modifier.
So I press control Z.
I return to the first mode.
I reveal these ones.
This is the main shape and this one is the shape that we want to create a stroke from.
I press control g to move it to a group.
I open the group.
Add offset path modifier to eight.
Increase the amount.
You have some space.
As you see the space all around, the shape is the same.
And we have done that with and we have done that without any problems.
Here, you can decide whether to be sharp set and miter or you want it to be smooth.
So set it on round.
I want it to be sharp.
Then open rectangle.
I don't want the feel of the second stroke, so I delete it.
Open a stroke eye.
Click on Dash to turn the stroke into dashes.
I click again and change its settings.
I press it again to make it a regular.
Then in line cap parameter select round cap to have rounded stroke corners.
To rotate this troll continuously alt and left click on a stopwatch of the offset parameter.
Here.
Time.
Time 100.
I think the diameter of this stroke is a bit much.
So go to stroke width and set it to eight.
I want to reverse its rotation.
I change 100 to -100.
So here is the animation of this stroke.
The next example is creating such thing.
So open shape content.
Andela, this wave, since we want to remake it.
Also the litter offset path, so the shape is inside the group.
Duplicate this group.
Remove the animation created for this scale.
After removing its animation, click on Contents and add offset path modifiers to it.
Move with benefit group to.
I had this layer to better know what is going on.
By increasing the amount of the offset path.
All shapes that are inside the group will be offset separately.
We don't want this.
We want all of them to be recognized as a single shape.
So open group and add merge path modifiers to it immediately after adding it of said parser recognized
all of that as a single shape and the sets all shapes as one shape.
Now, inside the group layer we don't need fill anymore, so I disable it.
Then I enable group one.
From this point, that offset path has covered around the shape.
I start animating it.
Create a key frame for it.
Go to second one.
Increase its amount.
This march.
Then create a key frame for a stroke with.
Finally set it on zero.
Press you to see the keyframes.
Then the sun comes here and from here on it gets larger.
In order to coordinate the animation of the wave with the sun and make it loop and continuous.
Drag these two key frames for words to have the same duration for the animation of the wave and so on.
And create loop hound expression for these two as well.
Press control C and paste it here.
Let's have a look.
It's fine.