The next modifier is poker and bloat.
It is used to make your shape loose and poker.
So I open poker and blow its modifier.
In it.
We have the amounts parameter.
This is below the status and this is poker status.
It just stretches the points inside and outside.
So you can create such a status.
Like flower and such a diamond shape.
By increasing this amount, you can create abstract shape in order to see what happens to different
shapes using this modifier.
I have created all these shapes.
Let's see what happens if I increase this value here.
The points are stretched inside and here as well.
You see this is rounded rectangle.
The points are stretched inside.
This is a circle and its points are here and stretched inside as well.
The same thing is happened for the polygon and poly star.
You see now they are stretched inside and now they are stretched outside.
So using this modifier you can create such shapes or you can create abstract shapes.
Now let's go to the example and use this modifier.
We have a project like this and we want to coin shine.
I play it to see its animation.
We want this part of the coin to shine as it spins in the air.
So zooming.
Exactly.
At this point, I create a circle.
We don't want it's stroke and let's set its feel and white.
Then at poker and blow it modifier to eight.
I make it solo to just see this layer and proceed the task faster.
Decrease its amount parameter to look like this.
Set it on -60.
And we want to animate it.
Open our lips.
Create a keyframe for its size.
And another one for a mountain press.
You go ten frames back and change the circle size to zero.
It comes here, and after ten frames, it turns into zero.
Easy is the middle keyframe.
Go to the middle key frame of the size and go five frames back.
So the first key frame of the amount here and after ten frames set it to -90 to have such a shape.
Now let's see.
How does it look?
Press you key.
Close the beginning and the end of the layer.
After creating that as the coin reaches its climax point.
I mean this point.
Our shape should be placed here.
Duplicate it.
Move it here.
Duplicate it again.
And place it here.
Let's have a look.
When it is here, the shape should be animated first, then this one.
So I move it here.
And finally, when the reflection of the coin is here.
The third shape should be placed here.
Okay, let's see the result.
Move this a bit.
If you want the stars to move with the coin.
You can parent them to the rink back layer.
Which is the Slayer.
At this point.
Parent This one to the layer.
And here, the third layer.
Let's have a look.
The third star should be placed here.
You can create such shining mode using this modifier.
Let's have a look at the animation.
That's really good.