Hello, everyone.
In this video, I want to talk about one of the most attractive parts of motion graphics logo animation.
And his widow.
We will talk about all kinds of logo animations, how we can create them and the tools we can use for
creating them.
The first thing we should know is that we can create logo animations by two methods.
The first one, which is the fastest, is using templates and the second one is custom.
In the first method we go to video five dot net select the project that we think it is suitable for
our job and then put our logo in it.
We can also change the color if needed and eventually we render it and create our logo animation.
This method is more suitable for business managers and beginners who have just started motion graphics
and want to create their logo animation as soon as possible and they don't care about it being so unique
and special.
They should know that if some of these templates are so beautiful and detailed, yet they are not a
good option for some of the projects because they are not personalized at all and they express no meaning
about the brand or its productivity.
And it is also so hard to find a good quality project and what you really want between a lot of templates
and if you do, probably some people before have used it already, and when a customer sees that they
think you are a lazy or amateur motion graphics designer, well the second method of creating logo animations
is a little bit harder and more complicated to create custom logo animations.
And this method look animation should be created exclusively and relatively for customer purposes and
its work area.
So it is not like templates.
So we could use it for many customers and because it is exclusive and it has been made for a particular
brand and it is explaining about that, it can be a very good tool for the brand marketing.
Well, it is obvious that in this video our topic is the second method, because the first method it
is not professional.
It is even so simple.
It doesn't need instruction.
After getting acquainted with the ways of creating logo animations, it is better than at first.
We get to know all kinds of logo animations and the tools we can create them with.
That's first.
Before we can create a logo animation, we should have a logo.
We need to design a logo that can be designed in different ways and shapes like geometric, abstract
and etc..
And then for animating them, we can choose hard or easy ways.
The first and the simplest way to make logo animations is by using lines.
And this way we use exactly the same effects and do what we did for making lettering animations.
But differences here lines form the logo shapes.
Changing pathways can also help a lot for creating this kind of animation.
We can use shape reformers, especially tree path.
We can use effects like stroke, 3D stroke, track maps, and also curve a plugin which is particular
for this kind of works.
As you know, it is right that we are working with lines here, yet it doesn't mean because we are only
using lines.
Our work won't be attractive enough.
As you can see, with a little bit of taste, creativity and creation, we can create really beautiful
logo animations with these lines.
We have talked about lines.
Maybe you have already seen these kinds of logo animations which have been made by lines for these kinds
of works.
Connect Layer Script is going to be really useful for you for creating these connections.
It is enough to select the layers and click on the tree button.
After animating the layers, you can see that the lines are connected to them.
Of course, we can use other plugins for creating these kinds of work which are more advanced but not
free like plex's.
The next method, which is very interesting, is the Lego components shown by them impacting together
or to the surface.
For example, at the first animation, a circle goes into the scene and by meeting the logo components
and then logo components meeting to each other creates a logo.
We can say that our team's logo has been created with this method.
There are many tools we can use in this method, like changing the layers transform like changing rotation
position scale.
Scale is really important because layers bouncing animation depends on that and you should pay attention
a lot to the anchor points places because they have a big part in bouncing.
The next tools we can use are a squash and a stretch.
Changing pathways which it is used for changing objects shape.
Train path the former.
3D stroke and also warp and band effects, which are really handy for bending objects and making objects
look soft.
The next method is the glitch.
As you know, there are many kinds of glitches like moving pixelation, fragmentation of the logo and
its colors and other different kinds.
You can use all of the glitch coins in this method.
There are many ways to create glitch, and so far many plugins, scripts and templates have been created
which you can use to create glitchy.
I repeat the last point I told you, because it is so important in using methods you get familiar with
now or before.
Be a little bit cautious and consider its brand and work field.
Then use one of the methods.
So you should understand this kind of animation is related to what brand or field?
For example, if there is a company that is technology related, this kind of animation might be suitable
for it.
But if your customers field is meditation or cooking, there is no need to use glitch for that logo.
But if your customer likes it, you can use it.
A lot of people like these kind of logo animations.
Tools that we can use to create glitches are effects like turbulence, displaced displacement, map
noise, noise, less Venetian blinds, mosaic shift channel and posterized time.
The next method is using geometries and playing with geometric shapes.
And this method, simple things happen.
But because objects are scattered and in one moment a few objects go into the scene and are animating.
They make our work look professional and beautiful.
For creating these kind of logo animations.
As you can see in these examples, it is enough to imagine your logo to geometric shapes and then appear
each part with the geometric shape and combine those geometries.
So eventually your logo can take a shape.
You should be aware that you shouldn't disrupt scene balance, meaning we don't want our logo to be
so dynamic in some parts and not in other parts.
In other words, logo animations should be fully framed, meaning movements and tearing and exiting
objects should be the same on both sides of the scene so it can avoid the scene being unbalanced.
The next method is on fold, meaning opening, which shows opening or folding a paper.
As you can see, combining it by lines makes our work much more beautiful for creating this kind of
logo animation.
You can make your layer 3D and rotate them in X, y, and z axis.
With this method, you can create this kind of animation to.
The next method is 3D.
As you know, Aftereffect is not a 3D software, but yet it has good tools for making 3D like making
layers, 3D giving volume to the shapes and texts, creating shadow and light in 3D space.
If you set your cursor in the Engine and Cinema 40.
For example, these kinds of samples in which Lego components come into the scene and form the logo.
We can call them three logo animations, which are so popular in the past but now are unfashionable
and are not used anymore.
If you wanted to do a little more professional works, you can use the Elements three D plugin, which
has good abilities in animate and creating beautiful materials for 3D objects.
If you want to know all the abilities of this plugin is better to check out its creator website video
copilot and then watch the tutorial videos.
If you are more interested in making 3D animations, my opinion for you is to learn the Cinema 4D software
so you don't have after effects limits and your logo animations and anything else you want to create.
3D can be made faster and simpler with the software's professional tools.
The next method is retrospective, meaning take a look at the past.
The way that we create this kind of animation is so simple it is just enough to animate your logo's
texture and tissues.
So you can have this kind of result regularly.
This kind of animation is used for old companies which are willing to show their experience and knowledge
in their work field.
Pay attention that this technique shouldn't be used everywhere.
And as I said, this method usually shows the experience and the oldness of something.
Therefore, there is no need to use it always, especially when a brand wants to express itself being
modern and its vision to the future.
The next method is using character or some parts of it like face and or in logo animations.
The properties of this method are that it shows more life and our logo animation makes better contact
with our audience.
Usually being a character in logo shows a connection between the logo and the brand, or for expressing
the brand's work.
Feel better for creating this kind of animation.
We should have some pieces of information about characters make different poses and the way of animating
the different components of our character.
So eventually, with a little bit of help of creativity and different tools we have in this field get
a good result.
Maybe you think that this method is too hard and you don't want to go for it, but with a little learning
and practicing, it can create much more professional logo animations.
And after creating these animations, you're going to feel more confident and you will understand that
there is nothing that you can't do and other methods get much easier for you to do, and in the end
you will see that it is worth a try.
Sometimes you have to work with the typography logo that doesn't have any kind of icon or element graphic.
In these situations for getting a good result.
You can use your creativity.
Some tools which we talk about like line animation, glitch and other methods.
That's why I don't repeat them again.
The next method is animation Liquid, which is one of the most attractive methods to create logo animations,
and it is usable variously in different places.
For making liquid animation.
You can use the blur effect combining by the match of care.
This combination causes the objects to be shiny and flowing.
And the objects themselves can be created by 3D stroke or a particular effect.
And eventually, for creating splashes, we use a frame by frame animation to reach a great result.
Another log animation kind is intensive reveal.
This kind of animation is created by beak shapes, which further will be transformed into the logo.
This technique is frequently used in logos with small details like the logos you see now.
This method is going to be really useful when you want to use your log animation as the intro video.
For this method, you can combine different techniques together, but don't use more than three effects
at the same time.
And don't create your animation too long because watching some shapes which are frequently transforming
to another shapes more than 10 seconds is not so appealing.
After we got familiar with all the methods and different kinds of logo animations, it's better to talk
about giving sense to our animation that how we can make our animation meaningful and to understand
the concept to our audience.
There are two ways for giving sense to our animation generally.
The first one is abstraction, and the second one is sense.
The first method, which is so simple as its name implies, is abstraction animations, meaning creating
an animation by graphics elements and brand style, animate it the way you want and show it, because
this kind of animation doesn't say anything special, and it's enough for it to look attractive because
it's abstraction.
In the second method, which is sans your logo, an animation should express something about the brand
or the brand's products or its customers and explain about them.
There are different ways to make our logo animation meaningful.
The first way is to play a little bit with the logo or company's name because companies name explains
good descriptions about the company itself playing by name or logo and showing the company's activity
by objects.
Animation helps us to demonstrate the company's goal.
The next method is using morphing meaning showing what a company does by shapes, icons and effects.
You should pay attention that everything we use should be coordinated with the logo style animation
kind.
For example, if the logo has a smooth corners, we should try to use smooth corners in designing the
shapes we are adding to the logo animation.
Not only does this make the animation more beautiful, but makes our job much easier and more fun animating
the shapes and causes our animation to be more appealing.
The third method that we can make our animation meaningful with is animating the characters in the logo
itself.
Usually the characters using the logo are relevant to the company and its activities.
But yet you can do two things in animating the Lego characters.
The first thing you can do is to create a normal activity for your character, like flying for a bird,
because normal activity for bird is flying.
The second thing you can do is to animate your character as it does an activity which is related to
the company.
Like and are you looking around and looking for something?
And this animation is completely suitable for the researcher companies which are looking for new things.
The important point about logo animations that should be always considered is you are making logo animation.
So don't let it be too long and transform into a short film.
The last thing we should talk about is the animation from a technical point of view.
The logo animation should have an entrance at first.
It shouldn't be in the scene from the first, but it should form step by step.
Then the logo got formed.
If it is not going to be a loop, it should have an exit stage.
Meaning the logo after got completely formed again starts to end the animation and fades from the scene.
And if it is going to be looped, the first and the last part of the loop shouldn't be obvious.
Good luck.