Hi, and welcome to the motion hero course
In this course, you will become a better version of yourself in motion graphics.
So I want you to be patient and follow me to the end of this course and come along with me step by step
during tutorials and practices to get the intended results.
This course for people who are familiar with after Effects, but for those who are still beginners and don't
know too much about after effects, don't worry, because I've set this course the way that even beginners
can also follow it.
So in the beginning we will get to know about after Effects, but I'm not going to introduce all the
after effects tools and confuse all of you.
In the beginning.
You'll just learn the required tools in motion graphics and animation, but the other more advanced
tools in future lessons during practices.
So let's see what we're going to learn in this course.
In the beginning, you will learn about the main and important panels of after effects.
After that, the tools, then the features of the composition and how to create it, and also its settings.
And finally, you will learn how to import your files into after Effects.
Then we'll talk about concepts and tools we need to create animation.
At first you will learn what actually a keyframe is and how to create it.
Then you will learn all different types of keyframe and when to use each type.
Then you get acquainted with graphs and how to use them to lead and master your animations and control everything.
In the following you will learn about keyframes interpolation, all types of them, and how they work.
And also you will learn where to use each type.
After you learn all about animation tools, we're going to do a little simple practice to put what we've learned into an actual project.
Then to better understand the timing, spacing and easing that are some of the most important principles of animation.
We'll do a couple of Bouncing ball exercises.
Firstly, we'll start with a simple exercise and create a beautiful bouncing ball animation.
In the next practice that is a little more advanced.
You will learn how to make a bouncing animation using a reference, since working with references is
one of the most important things in animation.
It's better for you to learn how to use them early in the course and for the last practice with help
of creativity and what we've learned, we're going to make a complex, bouncing ball animation.
And then you will learn about some other important principles of animation and how to use them in your works.
in this step.
You will learn how to use anticipation in your animations and also how to make your animations more
alive and interactive with overlapping and follow through principles.
Be aware that these practices and principles are very important, but most motion designers ignore them
and it makes them not have a good understanding of movement and animation.
And finally, they cannot create attractive animation.
In the next chapter, you'll learn about the 12 principles of animations and how to use them in motion graphics clips.
After that, you will get familiar with text layers and their performance and also all types of selectors.
And to have a deep understanding of the content, we will create three takes animations together.
We talked about animations and we better also mention Lettering animation.
So in this chapter, firstly, you will learn how to make your write in effect for the letters,
how to make them more attractive by adding bouncy animation.
Then you'll learn how to add details to your animation to increase its beauty and in the end to completely
learn all steps to create a lettering animation.
We will animate a text from top to bottom.
After that, you will learn about logo animations, how to create them and the tools we need for logo animation
Also, you will learn how to make your logo animations make sense and give debth to them.
Another technique that every motion designer should know is creating loop animations.
In this chapter you will learn what principles you should follow to create a standard loop animation.
And then we put these principles into use to make a good loop animation
After that, you get familiar with one of the most beautiful techniques of motion graphics called Morph animation.
In the beginning you will learn what things you need to create a smooth morph animation and then will
start to morph three different objects to make you guys ready for serious projects.
And finally, with anticipation, bouncy animation and adding details to our animation will make it as attractive as possible.
In the next chapter, we're going to talk about character rigging
And since we do this with Duik Bassel script, first, you will learn how to install it.
Then we will have a little introduction to it and you will learn the required tools for rigging.
And after you are entirely introduced to the script, I will start from the most basic concepts of rigging, meaning preparing the character,
and then you will learn how to skeletonize the character.
Then you'll learn to create an automatic work cycle animation without any keyframe.
In the next chapter, you will learn how to animate characters in this chapter.
You will learn how to use references.
And also you get familiar with different walking poses.
And finally, you can create a beautiful walking animation on your own.
After that, you will learn how to create a walking cycle without references and using only three principles.
And also you will learn how to create running cycles with the help of references and also without any references.
And in the last chapter, you will learn how to rig a head with the joysticks and sliders and create
different facial emotion for it so that you can create a cool animation for the character's head.
The important point to know is that this course will be useful for you if you always keep your aftereffects open
and do exactly what I do step by step and don't just watch clips because motion graphics is a skill,
not a knowledge.
So you need a lot of practice.
And if you have any problems or any questions during this course, you can join our Facebook group and
share your questions and experiences with other students of this course and get your answers from me right away.
And the last thing, if you like to continue this way and don't want to be stopped midway,
you can join my YouTube channel and watch more updated advance tutorials.
I will try to upload tutorials once a week there, so let's go to the next lesson and start our learning.