Hello, everyone.
Before I start the course, seriously, and learn how to work with keyframes and create different animations
in after effects, it's better to get acquainted with the after effects, panels, workspace and also
tools This software gives us a bit, so those who are about to learn after effects for the first time get
familiar with the software entirely and be able to follow us in the next levels.
In this lesson, we want to talk about after Effects user interface and learn how to adjust our workspace
according to our needs.
After I open after effects, the first window to appear is home where you can see projects you have used before.
And by clicking on the new project, you can create a new project.
And with the open project button, you can open a project you have already saved.
I click on the new project and enter the work space of AfterEffects.
The first thing I have to do is to set up workspace in standard mode.
I go to the Windows menu workspace section and click standard.
As you see, panels changed and our work space went to standard mode.
If your work space is not like this, after clicking on a standard, you just have to go to the Windows
Workspace and select reset standard to saved layout so that the standard layout resets to its default settings.
Now your work is this panel should be exactly like mine.
But if it's not the case or by mistake, you close a panel.
You just need to go to the Windows menu.
Here you can open all of the panels again and see what panels are now open in standard mode.
Well, I closed the effects and presets panel and I open it again from here.
You can see it came back.
You can easily change panel positions and place them wherever you want in after effects, or you can
make your panel float by pressing this button.
If you wanted to change back, you can click on the panels name and drag it back here.
After you adjust your panels as you want.
You can save this work space from Windows, Workspace, and save as a new workspace and name it whatever
you want.
For example, I name this one new.
As you can see here, our workspace is saved.
If I go to default and then select new, I go back to the workspace I made before.