Well, let's have a look at the menus in after Effects.
The first one is the file, including options divided by these lines.
The first section is for creating an opening project.
You can open a project by clicking on the open project or pressing Ctrl + O.
For example, I open this project.
The second section is for closing projects and also saving the project you are working on.
And one of the interesting options existing here is increment and save, which allows you to save several
versions of your project without changing its name every time.
The next section is for importing and exporting files.
With these options, you can export and import different files in after effects.
The next important option is dependencies, by collect files.
You can save your project, alonge with every footage and pictures have used in it as a folder wherever you want.
This option is useful when you want to move your project to a different computer and continue your work there.
As I said, you just need to go to the file menu, dependencies, collect files and then click collect.
As you see here, it shows your collect folder size.
I click collect and I choose desktop for example, and the project will be saved in the specified location.
The next important option is the scripts.
You can find scripts that you have put in the script folder in the after effects installed location.
Well, the next menu is edit which includes many capabilities that we use a lot, like undoing,
redoing, cutting, copying, duplicating, splitting layers and selecting.
One of the most important option in this menu is purge, which you can use when your project has become
too heavy and your frames are not shown correctly.
Click on all memory and disk cache and delete the after effects cache so your project gets lighter and
easier to work with.
The next important option is preferences.
From here you can different settings on your after effects.
The next menu is composition.
From here you can create a new composition, change your composition settings, trim or crop a composition.
Add your composition to the render queue and also the save frame as an option, which allows you to
take a picture of a frame that your indicator is on it.
The next menu is the layer.
You can see different settings if you right click on a layer in the timeline you see have the same tools here.
The next menu is the effects, which includes existing effects and presets in after effects.
You can have easy access to the same effects here in the Effects and Presets panel and you can find
them easier by searching here.
The next menu is animation, including options about creating keyframes and keyframe settings.
here You can exactly the same options you have in the timeline.
The next menu is the view.
Here you have options about viewport settings like zooming, resolution, showing guidelines, rulers,
and other tools regarding the viewport panel.
The next menu is Windows.
It contains workspaces.
Here you can activate or activate different panels.
Here are important panels.
At the bottom, you can see installed scripts.
And also here you can see extensions.