The next thing we need to know is the panel.
And in this lesson, I want to talk about the most important panels.
Well, the first and important panel we have in After Effects is the project panel.
Layers, films, pictures, compositions, folders, and everything we have used in our project are place in this panel.
By selecting any of these items, you can see a little preview of the item here and you can acquire
some details about this item, which is a composition as you see its Size is shown.
And here comp duration.
And here frame rate is visible, at the bottom or some options.
With this, you can create a folder and organize items in the project panel.
The next option is create a new composition.
By this, you can create a new composition.
And the next option brings up the project setting window where you can change your project settings.
And the next option is for deleting selected items.
The next panel is composition or viewport.
As you can see in front of the name of this panel is written 'space'.
And this means I have opened the com namespace from the project panel and also in the timeline, the
composition or space is shown.
And as you see, the composition panel shows all the items that are in the comp space.
And using this panel, you can see whatever happens in your comp, in the bottom part of the viewport
or composition panel.
There are tools that I will mention, important ones.
This tool is for zooming in and zooming out of the viewport.
The next tool is for activating or activating rules and guidelines.
The next tool activates or activates paths for shapes and masks.
Here you can specify a time so the indicator shows in the timeline.
This one is for taking pictures, by clicking on it
You can take a shot and if you make changes by holding down this button, you can see the changes you
have made.
The next option resolution, which is very important, is for when you have a heavy project, you can
reduce viewport resolutions, so your project works slightly.
This option is for when you want to render a specific part of the composition.
The next option is transparent, which shows the areas that are transparent or with no pixels.
In this project, I don't have transparency.
If I hide the background, you see, it shows the areas that are transparent.
The next option is for perspective.
By this you can have different perspectives of your layers and it is more practical when you put your
layers in 3D mode.
This option is for when you want different views of your project.
As you see, you can control your view in double, triple, quadrupole and other different kinds of view.
Another important panel to be discussed is the timeline panel.
As you see, this panel has two main sections.
One of them is for timeline and time progress, and the left section is for layers and their settings.
By clicking on this arrowhead, you can see settings for the layers here.
here You can control visibility of the layer.
If it's a sound layer, here you can mute and unmute it.
With this, you can solo a layer.
With this one, you can lock it so it cannot be selected.
In this section you have time line.
By dragging this, you can specify your work area.
Or you can use the B key for the setting of the beginning and N for the ending of the work area.
By holding alls and scrolling, you can make the timeline bigger or smaller.
Also you can use this option for the same, making it big or small.
Or click on these icons.
Now that we got familiar with the main panels in After Effects, let's have a look at the layer settings
and options existing in the transform of the layer
in transform, The first option is the anchor point.
By this, you can move the layer anchor point to any place you want.
The second value is position.
By this one, you can adjust the position of your layer.
Or you can just change it by dragging the object.
As you can see, changes in position or applied here.
The next option is the scale.
You can make your layer bigger or smaller.
And also, if you take down this chain, you can change size in one direction.
The next option is rotation.
Using this option, you can rotate your layer.
Also, there is an opacity option by which you can change the transparency of the layer.
If you want to just work on the position of a layer and you don't need the other values,
you just have to select the layer and press p on your keyboard.
So only the position value appears.
Or if you only want the anchor point, you can press A; for scale press S; for rotation R.
And T for opacity.
And if you want to values, you just have to hold down shift after appearing opacity and press p for the position.
Now, if you want to add a scale too you can keep holding down, shift and press S.
And if you want to make one of these values disappear, you can do this by holding down shift and pressing
the related hotkey.
For example, I hold down, shift and press T.
You can see opacity is disappeared.
So A is for opening the anchor point; P for the position.
S for scale, R for rotation and T for the opacity of layers and also for adjusting the ending and
beginning of your layers in the timeline, you can use close bracket and open brackets, open bracket
for specifying the beginning of a layer and close bracket for specifying the ending of a layer.
And also you can use Alt + [ for trimming the beginning of the layer and Alt + ] for the ending.
And as I said before, B and N are use for specifying the beginning and end of the work area.
And for changing the layer's name first select the layer.
Then press enter and write the name you want.