One of the main panels in the after effects is the Tools panel or toolbar.
The first tool is home.
By clicking on it, you can open the same window as the one that opens at the beginning when after effects run.
The next tool is selection.
But this one, you can select objects in your scene and move around.
It's hot key as it's written Here is V.
The next one is hand.
This will allows you to move the viewport and the scene itself.
The next tool is Zoom,
using this tool you can zoom in and out by holding Alt and clicking.
You can zoom out.
And without Alt, Zoom in.
I press V
So we get back to the selection tool and for using the hand tool temporarily.
All I have to do is to hold down space and adjust your viewport by hand tool.
And as soon as you release it, the selection tool will be activated again.
I go to the next group of tools.
The first tool is rotation.
Using this tool, you can rotate your layers.
The next tool is the camera.
This one activates when you have a camera in the scene for adding a camera layer to composition.
I Right click here and from new I add a camera to the comp
After that, you see that the camera tool is activated for us and you can see the capabilities of this
tool and it's hotkey is C.
The next tool is pen Behind.
this tool allows you to move and put the anchor point of your layer anywhere.
So all the changes to the layer happen according to the anchor point.
If I select the rotation tool and start rotating, you see now it rotates around the new position of
the anchor point.
Also, if I use the selection tool and change layer size, it happens from the anchor point.
Now we go to the next group.
The first is the rectangle tool.
By holding down the left click.
We can see other tools too.
Let me create a rectangle here.
As you see, when I create a rectangle here, a new layer is added to the timeline, and here you can
see settings related to this layer.
When I choose the last layer, you see these options appear.
And when I choose this one, you see other options appear for adjusting this layer.
Well, I delete this layer.
The next one is the pen.
Using the pen tool, you can create every shape you want.
The next tool is T, which is used to create text layers.
The next group of tools, including Brush, Stump and Eraser, has a unique property, which is you cannot
make changes to the layer in the composition panel and you have to open them in the layers panel to
be able to edit them.
For this, I double click on the layer, so the layer opens up in the layer panel and now you can use
the brush tool and make the changes you want.
And from here, you can adjust the Bruch setting like color.
Let me select the eraser tool
And to make it bigger, I press Ctrl + Left click and drag.
For example, I want to erase this part.
Let me put it in transparency mode so it is completely clear.
As you see, we only can use this tool in the layer panel.
After we make the changes we want to the layer.
We go back to the composition panel and here we see that changes also will be shown here.
The next tool is the Roto brush.
This one is mostly used for rotoscoping and background removal.
The next one is the puppet pin, which has several usages and is mostly used to rig characters.
It's also good to introduce the effects control panel.
Here, this panel shows the effects that are applied to the layers.
For example, if I add a gradient effects to this layer, you see here in effect control of the layer 'mars1'
the settings of the effects and you can control them.
Okay.
I delete this now.
I go back to the sun layer now.
And as you see, we have changed the layer using paint tool.
So now there is a paint effect in the effects control panel.
And by deleting this effect, our layer goes back to its original state.