Well, in this lesson, we want to learn how to create a new project in After Effects.
As you know, when we open aftereffects, the home window will appear for us.
Here you can create a new project.
And here you can open the project you have saved before.
And here are the projects you have used recently.
I click on the new project, and new project is created for me.
You can also do this using the file menu, new and new project.
After we've created a new project and after things here you can see your project name.
But before you save your project and choose a name for it, it is named Untitled Project.
And after you save your project and choose a name, here you can see your project address and its new name.
After creating your project, the first thing we need to do is to create a new composition.
Composition is like an artboard in Photoshop, which allows you to choose your clip size, duration,
frame rate and other settings.
In order to create a new composition, I click on the new composition, and then the composition setting
window is shown to me.
You can do the same from the project panel and by clicking on Create new composition button.
The other way to do this is by clicking the new composition from the composition menu or using Ctrl + N
to create a new comp.
After that, the composition settings window will appear.
here You can choose a name for your composition here.
here there are some presets to make adjustments easier to create a comp.
For example, it is now on HDTV ,1080, and 25 frames.
You see I select
This preset our resolution is set to 1920 By 1080,
the pixel aspect ratio is set to squre pixel and the frame rate is 25.
But if I select this preset you see our resolution changes, frame rate changes and all the other
settings changed to.
I put it on the last one here.
here You can set the width and height of the camp.
Here is your comp frame rate,
Here, you can specify your comp duration.
For example, it starts from 0 to 20 seconds.
And here you can make a decision about your composition background.
I choose gray for it and click okay.
After I click okay, you can see that new composition is created with the name I specified.
And here the comp duration is on 20 seconds as I decided in composition settings.
After I create a composition, I can add different layers to the timeline, to add new layers to the composition.
I just have to open the comp.
Right click on the timeline and in the new section I can add different kinds of layers.
For example, I add a text to the comp.
You see, a text layer is made and you can type whatever here.
Well, note that adding a layer is only possible when you already have a composition.
If I delete this composition and try to create a new layer, you can see that by right clicking no option
is going to appear.
it is because there is no comp in the timeline.
So first we need to create a comp and then start to add new layers to it.
Okay, Now I add a solid to the time line when I choose solid.
Here you can choose your settings for your solid.
Change its name.
Change its color.
And here make a decision about its size.
I choose a size a smaller than my comp size and click okay.
You see, a solid is created for us.