Now that we have learned how to make a composition and add new layers to the composition, it is time
to learn how to import footage, images and layers that are outside of the after effects,
for importing a file into the after effects.
You just have to double click in this blank area of the project panel.
Then choose your file and click import.
For instance, I choose this photo and click import.
You see, this selected photo is now added to the project panel, and by dragging it on the timeline,
you can add it to the composition.
This is for when you want to import photos into your project.
Another way to import your file into the after effects is to click on file import and finally click on file.
Then you can bring your file into AfterEffects.
This time I import my video file into the project.
And as you can see here, my video file is added and by dragging it into the comp, we can work on it.
The next thing to know is that sometimes you need to add an illustrator file that contains several layers itself.
When you import these kinds of files into aftereffects, a window like this will appear.
Here you can adjust different settings.
In the first section, you decide whether you want to import this file as a composition or footage.
If I choose footage, the down section activates for me.
By this option you can import all the layers as one layer, and by this one you can import each layer separately
so only that layer gets imported.
I choose composition here and in footage dimensions you have two options Layer size and document size.
Document size means that each layer will import as big as your composition, but layer size means that
each layer will import as big as the object in a particular layer.
For example, I choose layer size and click okay, as you see composition with the name of the original
file that we selected is created and also a folder is created in which there are illustrator file layers.
Well, I double click and open the new comp.
As you see, it has different layers and each one of these layers has its own area.
See, this layer area Is this much
the eye area Is this much
It is because I selected the layer size option before.
How would it be if we had selected document size?
I do it one more time.
As you see now, the size of this layer, which is for the head, is as big as my comp size
or this layer for here it's the same.
All of these layers have the same size as the comp size.
This will be problematic for you when you want to select each layer with the selection tool.