Hey, everyone, In this chapter, I want to talk about weathering animation.
You must have seen such animations on the Internet.
As you can see, weathering animation is quite intriguing.
Well, it has very simple principles, but to achieve fascinating result, you need to have patience
and put a lot of time into it.
Because the more details your animation have, the better your results will be.
In this chapter, you will learn how to create a write in effect for the text, make a bouncy animation
for it, and how to add some details to the text.
And after learning all of these and some principles that we have to follow in lettering animation,
I will work on an exercise and I'll create a leading animation project from start to end so we can use
what we learned on an actual project, not solely because these techniques are useful in rendering animation,
but also because you can use them in local animation as well.
Now let's get right into it.
The most important of slithering animation is preparing the letters.
So I import the file that I want to work on.
I put this file in the resources section so you guys can use it to.
It's best to use vector files.
I can read this vector file into a shape.
And delete the previous file.
Okay, so the first thing that I need to do is divide the letters of this text into separate parts.
I duplicate this layer.
You can use the mask for this job.
For doing so, I select the shape layer and then pick up the pencil to mask the shape.
You have to enable this option after that eye mask, this leather.
A better approach would be to delete the parts I don't need.
For doing so, isolate the point, hold control and start dragging until I don't need it and I delete
them.
Let me hide the layer below.
For the anchor point to be in the center of the layer while the layer is selected, I hold control and
double click on the pen behind tool.
So I put the first leather in a separate layer, then I rename it.
So since this letter is complex, it needs to be cut into individual parts as well.
For example, this part will be separated.
The next one would be this part and the third one would be this part.
So I duplicate this layer twice.
I make the first layer solo.
I want to keep this part, so I need to delete the rest.
For the second one.
I need to keep this part and delete the rest.
And finally, I have to cut the third one, which is this part.
I stretched the first part so it would reach this section.
All right.
After I'm done cutting the first letter into different parts, it's time to animate it.
Generally, there are two ways for creating a write in effect for this letter.
The first approach would be using the pen tool and drawing a shape for the path of the animation.
Let me change its color so it would be obvious.
I increased the stroke so it would cover the shape completely.
After that, I add a trim pass to the shape.
Since I want the animation to start from here, it has to be animated like this.
I set this thought 100 and create a keyframe.
Then after ten frames, I set the song to zero.
After doing so, I hide the path layer and slowly delete the first part.
Then I enable modes and say to alphabet.
If I move the indicator, You see, the right interface has been created.
The other way to do this that doesn't require us to create another layer is using the stroke effect.
For doing so.
Isolate the layer and use the pencil.
Then I switch to mask mode and create a mask for the shape.
After it's done, I hop on the effects control panel and add the smoke effect to the layer.
I recolor thread so it's visible.
Then I increase the brush size so it would cover the whole shape.
I increase the hardness to 100.
I set the spacing to zero so the animation would be smoother.
And then I set the paint style to reveal original image.
After doing so, once I animate the sword and the end, as you can see, where there is a stroke, it's
visible, and where there is no stroke, it's not visible.
So for the animation to start from here, I create the keyframe for the start and move it right here.
Ten frames ahead.
I say to 100.
Now I need to work on the next part.
First things first, I need to make a path for its mask.
All right.
After drawing the path, I just have to select the previous layer and copy this together.
Then at the beginning of the timeline, isolate this layer and press control V so it would create the
same animation effect just like the previous layer.
And since this one is a bit lengthy, I'll set the animation length so 20 frames.
Let me make it solo right here to fix the ride in animation.
I just have to change the path of the mask slightly.
It's fixed now.
I moved a layer right here.
And at last, it's time for this layer.
I enable the mask mode and create a mask for this layer to.
I copy the stroke effect and paste it for this layer as well.
It seems all right.
So far as you can see, I just simply created this animation to make it more dynamic.
I have to use a scale and rotation.
To do so, isolate the main layer and parent the other layers to this one.
I put its anchor point right here and make the scale and rotation visible.
Then I create keyframes for them and ten frames further on.
I create some other key frames for them.
Then isolate the first keyframes and set the Y value to a D.
And I say that this way.
I made the first cue frames eases.
After doing all of these, I add the bounce expression to it.
I enabled exploration of a scale and pace the bounce expression there.
However, I set the amplitude to 0.2 frequency to 1.5 and decay to two.
It's all good.
I copy the same expression and paste it for the rotation.
And make it overlap just a little bit.
Then I move these keyframes to the beginning of the timeline.
All right.
For this part, I have that bouncing effect.
I made this scale visible.
First I move its anchor point right here and create a keyframe for it.
Ten frames further, I increase the value of the scale and reverse the key frames.
And then I paste the bounce expression for it.
Let's see how it looks.
It looks better now.
It's more dynamic.
Took care of the letter.
I can use the benefit.
For this, I apply the benefit to the main layer.
Then I move the endpoint here and the third point right here so I can create such a look for it.
I create a key frame and press use.
I can see the key frame.
I move it right here in the beginning and in the end the pen should be zero.
And for the beginning, let me come here.
In the beginning it should look like this.
So I set it to -60 and move the keyframes right here.
Then I make it easy.
After doing so, I paste the bounce expression for the band as well.
Let's see how it looks.
And then to make it look a bit better, I move these bags so its animation would match the scale animation.
It's better now.
I can use the same effect for this part to.
To do.
So I come here and I'm parented.
Then I copied the band keyframes and paste them for this layer, and then I fixed the start and end
points of this layer.
Let's check it out.
I just need to make the animation a slightly faster.
And I decrease the band value to for the in the beginning.
And I move it back a little bit so it would match the whole animation well.
Another thing you can do to make it look prettier is to create multiple layers for your animation,
just like the example shown on the screen.
So what I'm going to do is to duplicate the first layer twice.
Then I renamed them so they would be recognizable.
And I change its color.
I apply the fill effect to it.
I promise you.
And I moved the stroke keyframe forward, so the animation would have different layers.
I do the same for this key frame.
And I recolor them.
As you can see, we can also make this kind of animation.
And to avoid this to happen, you can move this layer above the others.
You can do the same for the other layers as well if you want.
As of right now, I don't want to do that.
I just wanted to show you that we can do such things.
Well, we just learn how doing animation is done.
If I want to add decorative details and elements to our animation, what should I do?
For this I can use lines.
For example, I want to add a line that goes around here and create this letter over here.
For this I just have to use the pencil.
I draw a line in the center of the scene.
I want my line to go around like this.
And it should land here.
After I'm done drawing the line, I change its color to white.
And rename it.
Then I add a trim pass to it.
In the beginning, the start and end values are set to zero.
And after 20 frames, they should be set to 100.
And then I moved them like this.
So it would give this kind of look.
Something like this.
After that, under the stroke section, I changed the line cap to round cap.
So the start and finish of the line would be around.
And then in the taper section, I set the sod length to 100.
So it will look like this.
And here I create a keyframe for the start width and increase its value.
Isolate these three layers and move them forward.
So the animation of this line would be shown first, then the animation of the letter.
It goes around and comes here.
Well, to make it smoothly, I come here and set the start with seven.
And also I showed the path from here.
Let's see how it goes.
Okay, I move these layers back.
Entering this layer here.
I make this a little faster so that it would match the speed of the line.
And to make the animation look better, I create a keyframe for the start and end.
Then easy.
Ease them.
And I open the graph, then I decrease the speed of the line right here.
I set the keyframes to continuous so I can move the three points and out points up together and decrease
the speed.
Now.
Let's check it out.
It looks much better now, as you can see.
It pauses here for a bit and then goes there fast and creates the leather.
After doing that, I still can add more details to it.
For example, right here I create another spiral.
Apparent this layer to the main layer of the letter so it would move along with it and also for it to
be synchronized with the band animation, I just have to copy and paste the benefit for this layer as
well.
I also have to put the keyframes in their place.
It should be right here.
As you see, it's now sitting with the letter.
After doing so, it's time to animate it.
First of all, I set the line cap thrown cap under the taper.
I said the start and end to 15 so it would look like this.
I also increased the stroke width and set it to ten.
I add a trim pass to it, then I set the start and end to zero in the beginning.
20 frames further, I set both of them to 100.
And I overlap them, so it would create the animation.
I decrease it with just a little bit.
I said this is sort of the layer right here.
I think I need to make this slightly smaller.
Let's see what it looks like.
It looks all right.
We can also create a splash right here just to make it look even better.
I come here and create something like this.
To make the movement better.
I moved the layer back where the leather is starting.
Repairing the splash to this part of the letter.
I just did splash path again.
And to make it disappear smoothly, I need to create a keyframe for the width of the stroke.
I set it to zero in the end.
Isolate the keyframes and make them easy.
I open the graph editor and make the end smoother.
Let's see how it looks.
I decrease the speed of.
I can also duplicate this layer, change its path.
And decrease in size.
And change its animation.
Well, it's good so far.
And this video I talked about, the techniques and principles which you can use in animation.
You'll also learn how to make it look better and add more details.
And the next part, I'm going to animate this text completely so there wouldn't be any sort of problem
in animating the letters for you guys.
Good luck.