In this video, I work on the head of a character and how to prepare it for the point that you need
to know is draw three steps for animating the head or character.
The first step is designing the character and the head.
The second one is rigging and the third one is animating.
Every step is dependent on the next one, which means I do rigging according to the animation I want
to create for the character or its head.
This means if the animation of the character is simple, the rigging process is also simple, or if
the animation is complex and contains a lot of positions and whatnot, the rigging process is as time
consuming and complicated and also for designing.
What I mean is that based on how complex you want the rigging to be, the character design and the layers
of the character should be just as.
Now let's get right into it.
The first thing that I want to make is the circle, like part of the head.
So I make this part using shape.
Let me disable stroke and feel so I can just see the path.
When I want to only move one of the handles, I just hold out and then drag it.
I rename it to head.
And enable it, feel and recover it.
Well, after that, it's time for the back here.
I hold arms and drag it like this.
I hold out again, I click and hold again so I can make sharp angles.
Well, I wanted to make the bag here in a separate layer, but since the head layer was selected, it's
added to the head layer.
And so I can separate these two layers.
I duplicate this layer here.
I delete the second shape, and in this layer I delete the first one.
So the back here would be in a separate layer.
I change its color to the same color as the reference.
Now it's time to work on the front hair.
Ask for that in order not for the front hair to move outside of the face area while animating.
I copy this shape from the head layer, then in the front hair.
In contents and I paste it here.
The next thing that I have to do is add merge pass modifier to the content.
I don't want the stroke in the merge pass.
I say it's more to intersect.
This means it will only show the areas that are in common with both James and the rest.
And I change color to the same color as the reference.
Let me rename this one as well.
Now, if you pay attention when I move the hair layer, it won't show anything outside of this area.
After that, the next thing that you need to know is that when I'm animating, definitely I'm changing
the face.
And as you can see, if I do so, the previous problem still remains.
To fix this problem.
I parent the face path in the front handle layer to the main face path.
So by picking a pair in this to this.
Now, if I change the shape of the face, that problem won't occur anymore.
And it works fine.
I move this point a little bit upper.
After that, you can see that there is a line right here to face this in the front her face and transform.
I increase the scale a little bit.
I say it's 101.
So the line wouldn't be there anymore.
Then I do these two hair strands.
I put both of them in the same layer.
Now let's work on the years.
I changed its color to the same color as the skin.
For both of the strokes.
I said line kept around.
So these parts would be around and I recolor it just like the reference.
For the other year.
I duplicate this layer and rename it.
And to flip it, isolate the layer slate only one point.
And by holding all and dragging, isolate all points and then hit control t I move it over here and
I flip it just like this.
As you can see in the reference, the ears aren't symmetrical and this here is a little bit bigger,
but I want both of them to be symmetrical, so I won't change that.
I move its anchor point right here.
Now I'll be working on the eyebrows.
In this truck.
I increased the size.
Then in the taper, let me slow the layer so I can see it better.
And the taper.
I set the stall length to 100 so it would look like this.
And I said it's slim cap to round cap.
I increased the start with just a bit, so this part of the eyebrow would look around.
For the other eyebrow.
I duplicate the layer.
Isolate one point and then I hit control A So all of the points would be selected.
Then I hit control T and I move it here.
Then I flip it so it would match the reference.
It looks good.
Now let's work on the nose.
I change its color just like the reference.
Then I increase its size.
Then I said the line cab to round cab.
Then I added stream pass to the content.
The next thing is the mouth to create the mouth.
First I make something like this for the mouth.
I disable its stroke.
I'll rename it to Mouse in contents.
This will be inside area of the mouth.
I rename it to base.
I enable it to feel and recolor it as.
Then I have to create things and a time for the mouth.
For that.
I create a shape like this for the teeth.
I changed its colour to white again, isolate contents and create another shape for the time.
For its color.
I want it to be the same as her cheeks, but a little bit darker.
After that, just like the front hair thing.
I have to mask these two shapes inside of the mouth shape.
For that.
I like to think I hit Control G and put it in a group.
I rename it Time Group.
I do the same for the teeth to.
Then I duplicate the base layer.
I put it in the time group.
I add the merge path.
I delayed the stroke and the film is the same color as the time, which is good.
And the marriage path, I say to intersect.
So now to show you what happened.
As you can see, the sign is only visible within the mouth shape.
I place its anchor point here.
I do the same for the teeth part as well.
I recall it once because it's for teeth.
And I said the merge bus mode to intersect.
I make the base visible.
As you can see, the teeth are only visible within the area of the mouth, and outside of it it's not
visible.
I place its anchor point here.
I make the base visible as well.
So as you can see, I'm done with the mouth of the character.
I should do the same as I did for the front hair, and that is if I want to animate the mouth shape.
As you can see, this problem will occur to face that under each shape of the base.
It opened their paths.
Ripen in the path of the shames that are integral to the main shape.
I do the same for this path to.
Now, if I move the shape, you can see that the other shapes move along.
After that, I draw another shape for the line of the mouth.
Here I select contents and I make a shape here.
Rename its line.
And I said, line kept around cap.
Then I make the mouth layer look like this so it will be hidden under the line of the mouth.
So let's go for the eyes.
First I made the white part of the eye.
I add a circle shape here?
I renamed them so they would be clear.
I select contents and by holding control, shift and dragging.
I make a symmetrical circle shape right here.
I name it Light.
And I make the eyelash just like how I made the eyebrows.
Then I put this in a group.
Isolate the group and make these two other lines.
I duplicate this shape and put it here and make it smaller.
I put these three names in one group.
I change the colour of the shapes.
Well, the next thing that I need to do is this part of the shame would be only visible within the wide
area of the eyes.
For this I should do just like what I did for the mouth.
First of all, I put lights and black in one group.
I duplicate the white part and put these two in one cup.
I go to the group of these two shapes, I add a merge path.
I don't want the stroke and I set the merge path to subtract and I put the black on top so this part
would be empty.
And the color should be changed to this.
And for this group, which contains the white and the black group, I add a merge path.
Delete it strong and I set the marriage path mode to intersect.
And I changed its film color like this because it's the black part of the eye.
Let me swallow the layer.
And I can move it without worrying about anything.
Let me make the white ship visible.
And just like before, I have to paint this ship to this one.
So when the main one moves, the other one moves alongside it.
To do so, I open the path of the white ship and the group I open the path of the Y to.
And I parent this to the main shape.
Now, if I move the Y chain, both of them move.
And there is nothing wrong.
Now in the black group Transform, I create a keyframe for its position.
So if I want to move it, I can simply hit your key and make the position visible.
Look, now I have to create another shape for the eye.
So it would function as its eyelid.
So I create another shape right here.
I disabled stroke and I changed from color to the same color as the skin, and I move it below the eyelash
group so that later on I can create a blinking animation for it.
I name it, to Ireland.
To create the other.
I first I convert these circle shapes to busier path so I can manually change the patterns.
After that, I duplicate this layer.
I rename it, I select the layer and pick up the pencil.
And by holding alls and dragging isolate all of the points and hit control.
TW And I move it here.
And I flip it.
Then I try to match it to the reference.
It looks good now.
And to fix the light ship the group.
I moved here.
Well, let's go for the last ship, which is the chicks.
I place its anchor point in the center.
I duplicated.
And move it here.
Then I rename it as well.
Okay, I hide the reference layer and make the layers I made visible.
So the head of the character seems fine, but here are a few points to know.
The ear should be behind the head.
And the eyes below the front her.
So I move the front and top her layer.
It's up.
The eyebrows should also be on top of the hair.