Hi, guys.
For many motion designers, Hedrick and facial animation is very big problem and they don't know how
to do it and where to start it at all.
But in this video I will show you the rig and animating the head is not as hard as you think.
It just needs some practice.
This is the result I want to achieve in the end.
And this video I will talk about rigging the character's head, using the Jewish script and creating
a head turn animation.
I also talk about facial animation and create an emotion for the face.
Let's get to the training.
The first thing I need is a head in the front view.
As you see, I have created different layers for different parts of the head.
From the beginning, this is the back hair.
Then the ears.
Then the head layer.
The next layer is the front hair, which is within the range of the head layer.
The next layer is this part of the hair.
And these are the cheeks.
Eyes.
There are many shapes in each layer.
A ship belongs to the eyelashes.
The next step is for this part of the I that I made for the blink so that I can more easily create the
blinking.
The next layer is for the pupil, and the next one is for the wide of the eye.
Then I have the next layer for the mouth in which the first step is related to this line, which represent
the mouth line.
The next layer is related to the teeth.
The next layer is for the time, and the next layer belongs to the inside area of the mouth.
Then I have a layer for the notes for which I have created such a path.
And using the term pass, I want to create the different modes for it.
The last two layers are for the eyebrows.
So the first thing I should do is to create five keyframes.
That is five pauses for the head.
The first key frame would be the front post.
The second keyframe would be the right view.
The next left view then up and finally the head must go down.
Let's go for creating the keyframes.
Firstly, I open the properties of the layers that I need to make changes to them and create keyframes
for them so that the front view is saved in the first frame.
I move to the next frame and create the right view.
Given
the scale of the eyes and eyebrows, must be set to 90 in this post.
In the next frame, I must create the left view.
I salute the first keyframes and go to the joystick and I click on Origin to pace the front post keyframes
here.
Then I create the left view.
Then I move on to the next frame and I must create the output now.
In the next frame, I create the down view.
After that, isolate all the keyframes and go to the joystick and click on this option in the joystick
section.
I name the joystick head turn.
Then click on.
Okay.
And the joystick is created.
Now, as you can see, by moving the joystick, the head moves perfectly to and fro.
There are only a few problems, and that is the cheeks go out of the face area.
And that's not right.
To solve this problem, I just need to add the same effect to the chicks layers.
And then define the hidden layer here.
Problem solved.
I face the same effect for this layer to.
The next problem is that when I move to this side, this corner of the hair comes out and I have to
fix it.
To do that, I enter the joystick and select the head, turn joystick and click on and bind.
In the right view.
I move this part a bit further and also in the left view, I move this point further to fix the problem.
Again, isolate the keyframes and click on Bind.
As you see, the previous problem doesn't occur here anymore.
Let me change the look of the joystick a little.