After that, I move on to reading the pupils.
To do.
So I go to the eyes layer.
This belongs to the pupils.
So I go to this group and the pupil group.
There is a group named pupils.
And there I open it, transform and create a keyframe for its position so that I can only move the pupil.
As you see, when the pupil goes out of the zone, it's no longer shown.
I have made this using a birch path and put in its mode on Intersect.
I hit the key and entered the lift I.
I create the five eye poses.
Then isolate the keyframes and click on this option and just stick it in.
Let's name it I.
I totally forgot about the no changes.
So I unbind the head turn joystick.
And I create a key frame for the start and end to create a different poses.
It can isolate all the key frames and click on Bind.