Let's go and create different emotions for the face.
To do that, I need to make keyframes for the path of the mouth shape as well as the path of the eyes,
eyebrows and ears.
So I make some key frames for the values I want to change.
This would be the first emotion of the phase.
In the next frame, I just want to close the eyelids.
To make sure the blinking is done correctly.
I move the keyframes a little forward for about ten frames.
Let's have a look and see how it came out.
Looks good.
I got frame one and I need to make that I look like this is.
Well,
looks good.
These two islands are a bit different and I need to make them look alike.
After creating the blinking, I create some keyframes for the rest of the properties in frame one.
I move to the next frame and paste the initial keyframes here.
I want to show the character excitement here, so I added the mouth first.
And to create different math modes, you can use the references.
I have found this reference on the internet.
You can very easily find different references for different facial emotions.
Let's move to the next frame.
And now I want to show the sadness.
I move to the next frame and I want to show the angry.
I move on to the next frame and we're going to create the imagining mode for the face.
Let's move to the next frame and create the fear mode for the face.
Since I want the eyes to become a little bigger in this post and the pupils become a bit smaller, I
go to the shape layer and create some keyframes for the wide of the eye as well as the shapes related
to the pupil.
I copy these keyframes and paste them into the previous poses as well, so as not to face any problems.
I must do the same for this.
I too.
After creating the different face and motions, isolating all the keyframes related to the eyes.
Because I want to have separate sliders for controlling the different emotes.
After selecting the keyframes, I go to the slider section and click on this option to create a slider
for the different modes for the eyes.
I name it I.
After creating the sliders, you'll see that the null object is created here and in the effects control
panel of this null, you can control the same modes you've created for the eyes.
I added their names.
Then isolate the rest of the key frames and enter the joystick.
And a slider section.
I create other sliders.
This null object is related to the face sliders.