And for animation, you just need to set the angry slider to 100 and in the eyes also set the angry
at 100 so that the angry mode is made for you.
So animated and create a squash and stretch for the head.
Isolate all the layers of the head except for the head layer and parent them all to the head layer and
place the head layer anchor point here.
Then I can easily saw animating the head.
To be able to also control the eyebrows.
When the eye blinks, you need to go to the eyebrows and in the shape transform.
Create a keyframe for the position.
Do the same for this one too.
I move a frame ahead and take it to any pixels down.
I hit the key and select these two key frames and then go to the joystick.
And in this slider section I create a slider for the eyebrows.
The point you need to know is that when you set any mode to 100, the other modes must be at zero.
If the two modes are at 100, the face will be disfigured.
So I need to set the other modes on zero.
And.
You can go on and animate different emotions for the face.
Just note that if you want to change the sliders you've created into your sliders.
You just need to select one of the null objects.
For example, isolate the I emotional object.
Then I go to the joystick and in the slider click on create from the slider section.
I bring them here.
And as you see, these are the sliders with the same names I chosen before.
I go to the bullying slider here, you can delete the left part of your slider that you don't need by
disabling this option.
And you can go to the original layer of each one of these sliders and change your slider however you
like.
And just like what they did here, you can change your sliders however you want.
And finally, you get better acquainted with the tools and joystick script for what you do and become
able to use them professionally and also become familiar with the different methods to rig the head
using this script or find the ability to rig the different objects other than the head, such as cars
or anything else.
Enrolling my course by the link in the description, you can get it for half price.
Good luck.