Hello, everyone.
In this chapter, as I said, I want to talk about basic animations.
One of the most basic and important animations that the animator must know is bouncing ball animation.
You may think, what is the point of bouncing ball animation or why do we have to start from bouncing
ball animation?
I have to say practice in bouncing ball animation may look simple and very easy at first, but in fact
you can learn about important principles of animation in this exercise.
In the simplest case, I can say you will learn about timing, spacing, objects, weights or squash
and stretch.
And it's not like the bouncing ball animation is just for knowing about these principles, but it's
also used in professional animations to have an overview of timing and character states before drawing.
In the beginning, the bouncing ball of the scene is created and then according to that timing, the
character is animated.
That's why bouncing ball animation is important and any animator has to practice it from the start so
that when he wants to start animating professionally, like character animation, be able to use these
principles which have learned from here and get the intended result.
Before starting, I recommend that you open after Effects right now.
Open the Simple Jumping Ball project and follow me step by step.
Let's start creating a simple bouncing ball.
To do that, I make a foolish comp and name it bouncing ball.
I set its frame rate on 24 gray for background and duration and 2 seconds after that to make it attractive,
I import the image of a soccer ball.
I bring it into the comp and place it here and to turn this texture into an orb, I use the sphere effect.
I had the effect, the layer.
And as you see, the texture turns into a ball in the rotation section.
If I change these values, you see the layer completely acts as a ball.
I go to the lighting, I set the light high to 100.
Bring this 1 to 0.
In shaving ice the amount to 100 so that the ball doesn't have a shadow.
Of refuse to zero.
I bring them the radius to 100.
I put a ruler down here as a floor and saw the animating.
I also want to create this conscience.
And so it is better to put the layer anchor point here under the ball.
I create a keyframe for its position at the beginning of the timeline.
And then in frame 12, I bring the ball up.
And again, you stick in one.
I past the first keyframe frame.
I turn the work area here and take a look at the animation.
The animation is completely linear and it's not much appealing.
That's why easy is the middle key frame.
It's better little to improve it.
I go to the graph editor in a speed graph and increase handles of this keyframe until their influence
reaches 100.
Let's have a look.
Much better to have a more intense jump when the ball hits the ground.
I reduce these handles.
After that, I go for the rotation of the ball.
For this I go to the sphere if I want the ball to rotate this way and forward.
For this I create a keyframe at the beginning of the timeline.
I press Yuki to make its keyframe visible and at the end, because I want it to rotate forward.
I set this to minus one.
Let's see how it looks.
It's very good to make a shadow for it.
I use the Ellipse to.
Here.
I hold down control so that the shape is created from the center and I create a shape the same size
as the ball.
I move it below the ball layer.
Decrease its capacity, and I want to animate its scale.
I create a key frame for it here.
And when the ball is up, I settled on 40.
And when it comes down, I paste the first keyframe here again.
I want the influence of this keyframe to be exactly like this one so that the shadow and ball have the
same speed.
That's why we right click on this keyframe and go to the keyframe velocity.
As you see, the speed is zero and both influences are 100 on incoming and outgoing.
So I select this keyframe and make it easy.
Go to the key frame velocity and set influence on 100 for incoming and outgoing.
Let's see how it looks.
As you see the shadows.
Speed is synchronized with the ball speed.
After that, I go for creating squash and stretch for the ball.
For this.
Isolate the ball player, hold down, shift and press is to open the scale to.
I create the first keyframe here because the scale of the ball should be 100 here.
And when it hits the ground, the ball should be a little bit squashed.
So I increase the axis scale to 120.
And decrease the Y scale to the same amount that I increased the scale.
So I changed 100 to 80.
And in the next frame it reverses.
This becomes 90 and this becomes 110.
And in the last keyframe, it needs to be like this.
And in the previous frame like this, I also make this key frame easy ease.
And let's have a look.
Well, I have made this question stretch to improve it a little bit.
I can set this on 125 and this 1 to 75, so it squashes a little more.
And also here, 85 and 115.
As you see, when the ball is on the ground, it is squashed and when it comes up it stretches.
And as it goes higher, changes back to its original form.
And when it is coming down, it stretches and gets squashed here again.
Let's have a look.
It is really good to make our work more attractive.
I create a shape here.
I change its color to green?
Duplicated, bring it higher and make it a little darker.
And after that, isolate both layers and put them into come and call it flow.
Then I go to the comp.
Change the size, the layer size.
Crop it and go back to the main crop.
Bring it down and place it here.
And to animate it.
I use the motion tile effect.
I create a key frame here?
And another one here.
Let me bring it down.
It is a little fast, so I decrease this.
To make the ground is physical.
I use the optic compensation effect and add it to the ground.
I increase it a little and bring this one down.
And to fix these cropped parts, I use the reptile effect.
I bring it above the optic effect and increase its right and left.
To make this scene more beautiful.
I have created a football gate.
I increase its size and bring it below the floor layer and bring it down.
And I said, the color of these grasses, the same as the floor, but a little bit darker and increase
their scale.
And put them below the floor layer.
The benefit of using a sphere to make this ball and its rotation is that later you can go to the project
panel, find the texture and by the replace for this option, give another texture to your ball.
As you see now, a basketball is animating.
Let me change rotation so it gets more obvious.
Also, you can do it again and replace another texture.
In the next lesson, I'll talk about another kind of bouncing ball animation, which is a little more
professional and harder to create.
So you get familiar with different kinds of animations.