In this lesson, I want to do another exercise on bouncing ball animation, which is more complicated
than the last one.
But the difference between these two exercises is that I want to use references to create the animation,
and that's because we have to get acquainted with how to use references from the beginning and create
the animations according to them, to get a better result.
Well, I have found this image on the internet and I'll put it in the resources folder of this course
so you'll be able to use it.
I have created a foolish decomp.
I import the reference to the comp.
The reference is small, so I increase its scale to 300 and make it bigger.
And I bring it here because I want the animation to start from here.
Let's go to create the ball as I did before.
First I import the ball texture.
This time I use basketball and add this sphere effect to it.
Decrease its radius to match the reference size.
I think it's good.
As you see, I need to create the animation.
According to the reference, I open the position of the layer.
First, I want to create the main keyframes of the animation.
The first one is this one.
The second one is here when it hits the ground.
The third one here, the fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh and eighth.
We have eight main keyframes.
First, I create these keyframes.
To create this key frame.
I start counting from here to see in which frame I need to create the key frame.
This is the first frame.
So I bring the ball here in frame six.
I go five frames forward and bring it here.
Five firms ahead.
I bring it here.
To make sure the Y position of this key frame is exactly like this one.
I just need to double click on this key frame.
The Y position is one 905.
So I also set this one on 905 to be more accurate.
Four frames forward.
I bring it here again.
I bring it here.
After three frames.
It should be located here and at the end it comes here.
After creating the main keyframes, we also have to create the animation path.
For this, I select these higher key frames.
Right click on them and enter keyframe interpolation.
As I said before, this spatial interpolation is for the parts.
So I say on continuous busier to make sure when I change the handle, the other one moves with it so
the animation path doesn't get broken.
So I said it like this to make both handles grow with each other.
As I'm holding one of the handles, I had all.
Let's see how it looks.
The overall animation has been created.
I just need to set the animation speed.
For this I select high key frames and make them easy.
Now let's see how it is.
You see, it is a lot better to decrease the speed of the ball when it's in these high positions and
have a better look.
Isolate the keyframes.
Go to the graph editor and enable the speed graph.
Here I increase the handle approximately to 70.
To do it.
More precisely, I go here and type in 74, both influences.
Now let's see how it is.
The problem here is that when the ball reaches this point, it gives a little pause, but we don't want
it to do so.
I change this keyframe to continuous to bring both points higher together and I hold down shift and
bring it a little higher.
So the animation speed is in zero here.
I do the same for this one too.
I enter it and set the speed on 100.
So this one on 300.
And also the last one on 100.
Okay.
It's a lot better.
Now I go for creating the squash and stretch for the ball.
When the ball is falling.
And here when it reaches its highest speed, it stretches like this.
And when it hits the ground, it squashes completely and looks like this.
And again, in the next frame, when it wants to go up, it stretches vertically.
And at this point, when speed is at its lowest, it gets back to its original form.
And again, when it comes here, it stretches vertically.
Here it squashes and this process repeats continuously until the end with the difference that when the
ball jumps less than before, the stretching and squishing effect, less on it.
I hide the reference one frame before the ball hits the ground.
It should stretch.
I open the scale and rotation of the layer, create the keyframe for them.
Bring the keyframes to the beginning.
Here, the axes scale should decrease, I say on 70 and the same amount that I decreased from x, I
must add to Y.
So I set it on 130.
And here the rotation should be in this direction in the next frame where the ball hits the ground.
Let me specify the floor.
I paste the first keyframe here and the ball needs to be squashed.
So here I said this one on 70 and this one on 130 and set the rotation on zero.
I press you to see the position keyframes when the ball squashes.
The position of this key frame also comes a little lower.
Again, I paste these key frames here with this difference that the rotation of the ball is toward this.
Here.
Seven is too much.
So I settled on 75 and 125 to reduce stress a bit.
I also make the first keyframe of this scale easy.
Here, the scale returns to its initial form, meaning 100.
Here When the ball lands, I copy these keyframes.
But reduce caution and bring the layer a bit lower.
One keyframe backward and I paste these keyframes here and change the rotation like this.
I paste these keyframes too, and set it on 80 and 120.
It comes here again and becomes 100.
And here again, I reduce this squash.
I this key frame of scale here.
Control C.
And control we.
I go to frames forward and scale goes to its original form and position comes higher.
Let's have a look and see how it is.
I made these keyframes linear so that the maximum stretch happens exactly one frame before hitting the
ground.
And not sooner.
I make these linear and bring them a little forward.
Och, it's good.
Well now I go for ball rotation for this.
I use the sphere effect and I want it to rotate like this toward the right.
So I create a keyframe for rotation.
Let me see what direction it must rotate.
I set this on minus two.
I praise you.
And I need to bring the second keyframe here.
So the ball rotates while being stretched and squashed.
Now if take a look.
You see that the ball moves exactly like the reference.
After creating the animation.
According to the reference, I can personalize the animation and create what I want easily.
In my opinion, the animation is a little bit fast.
I can slow it down so I go on second to select keyframes, hold down alt and drag the last keyframe
to increase animation duration.
When I increase the animation duration, as you see, the keyframes don't locate exactly on the frames
and locate somewhere between two frames, and such problems occur for the animation.
For example, here, when the ball is supposed to hit the ground, it is not on the ground.
To solve this problem, I just need to select these key frames and then align them with the frames.
Now I have the problem here.
These key frames must have only one frame distance before the ball hits the ground.
Let's see how it looks much better after I create the ball animation to make this scene.
I have created a basket here, so I make it visible.
I create a background.
Bring it down and add the gradient effect to it.
Change its color to dark purple.
Dark.
And the lower part?
A little.
Bring the sword point lower near here.
And bring the end point higher to create the scene like this.
After that, I want to create a reflection for the ball.
To do this, I add an adjustment layer.
At the mirror effect it.
And put the mirror point here.
I place the rule over the ground is bring the basket lower.
Go to the mirror effect.
And place its point here.
I go to the effect and set the angle to 90 degrees and set the opacity to seven.
Now if I play, you see, the reflection of the ball is on the ground.
The next thing I want to do is for the ball to stop under the basket.
Exactly here.
So what can I do about this?
If I change this keyframe, you see, the animation path falls apart to move the layer and its animation
path together.
I need to add another object to the scene.
Then pairing the basketball layer to it.
And now when I move the null object, you see that the layer and this animation path move together easily.
If I bring it here, for example, you see the animation moves with the layer.
After that I can delete the null object without any problem.
The next thing I want to do is that I want the blonde to enter the scene from outside.
For this, I go to the first keyframe of the position and bring it back and modify its path a little.
And finally, I have to modify rotation as well.