Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, I want to create another bouncing ball animation.
In this exercise, I have made things more difficult to gain better control over the spacing, timing,
squishing and stretching of the animation.
This is the reference I want to use it.
And as you see, I have created these lines that the ball is supposed to make contact and move on them.
The ball is going to get squashed and throw itself toward this direction.
And after within this lever it jumps and goes this way, moves and hits under this line, then lands
on this lever.
This lever goes down a little and then throws the ball up and it comes here and jumps a few times and
at the end goes up a little and comes back.
The difference between this and previous practice is that here we don't use references because you want
to do the spacing and timing of the animation ourselves.
So if in the future we want to create an animation, we get to do this with our own ideas and timings.
But note that this practice doesn't mean that not using references is better.
So to reach our goal better and easier, it is good to use references, but my intention for this practice
is to improve your ability and creativity to make it fantasy animation because you can always find references
for the idea you have in your mind.
And in these times only your creativity will help you.
Well, let's get started.
First, I rotate this almost at this angle.
The ball is going to hit this lower.
I hide extra layers to have only the ball layer in the timeline.
I open the position of the ball.
The next point I have to say is that this time I didn't create this fall with the sphere effect because
sometimes our layers are shapes.
This time I find it better to work with shapes so we learn how to create a squash and stretch and rotation
for the ball using shapes.
Well, first we need to create the main key frames to know where the ball is going to be in different
situations.
After that, we need to adjust the path and then work with graphs and the speed of the animation.
Then we're going to create a squash and a stretch, and at last we will work with ball rotation.
So first I need to create the main keyframes or key poses.
To begin, I go to frames forward because I want to create a squash for the ball, so it requires energy
for the jump.
I create a keyframe here for the position.
Go three frames forward.
The ball needs to hear approximately.
Again.
I go through frames forward.
The ball comes here.
Throughout this Q frame here.
The next movement is that when the ball hits, the sliver goes here and moves the line.
This slide.
So I go seven frames forward and place the ball here.
Go six frames forward and bring the ball here.
After four frames, the ball should locate here three frames forward.
It comes here with wants to jump again, three frames forward.
It comes here.
For now, I'm creating the keyframes and their timing by guess.
But when the animation path and timing get decided, the key frames and both locations may change.
I go for frames for and it moves here.
In two frames, it goes lower.
In six frames.
It jumps and locates here.
After five frames, I place it here.
It should be here after four frames.
After three frames, it must be here.
And after five frames it should be here.
Then after five frames, the ball is on the ground.
Again.
The ball comes up.
And go down again.
It comes up.
Comes down.
After five frames, it goes here.
And after ten frames, it goes back here.
For now, I have created the main keyframes for the animation.
Now it's time to create the path for the ball.
I right click on this keyframe, go to the spatial interpolation and set it on continuous base year
so that both handles change together.
It hits.
And then I said this one on continuous busier.
Isolate these key frames and set them on continuous busier.
Let's have a look.
The path needs to be edited here.
This key frame needs to be on busier.
It should be only a little over.
This needs to move like this.
And I continue like this to edit the whole path.
Well, let's see how the ball passes.
Look, path is good for now.
Let's go for editing the speed of the animation and easing in the keyframes.
Isolate these keyframes when the ball is floating.
Gravity effects it and decreases its speed.
And I make them easy.
Let's see how it is.
It's better now, but this key frame is needed to be on easy as well.
And also this keyframe.
Isolate this keyframe and go to the graph editor and increase its influence or easing.
I double click on it and make it continuous and set its speed to 50.
So I don't get a pause here.
It needs more speed to have no puns here.
Here.
I need to increase easing or influence and make it continuous busier and set its speed to 100.
There is a pass.
I need to bring this one a little higher.
It's too much.
It should be a little over.
I think it should be here.
I go forward.
Here.
There is no need to pause until it comes here.
So isolate these three key frames and make them roll across.
It comes down, rotates.
It's this and comes here.
Delays along here.
So I decrease the distance between keyframes.
It comes down and jumps fast.
I go to the graph editor and also here the speed needs to be reduced.
And the keyframes between this jump and the next jump need to be rolled across so that the speed doesn't
have any pause here.
The speed must be reduced here again.
The same for this one as well.
And to eliminate the pass.
I bring this higher.
I bring it a little bit higher to.
And this one to.
Let's see how this part looks.
Okay, it's good.
But here, when the ball finishes the final jump, it's not well adjusted, so I delete them and create
the path again.
In ten frames.
It goes here.
And in the next ten frames, it comes back.
I said this keyframe on Busier.
Let's see how this.
I go to the graph editor and increase its speed here.
Let's have another look.
I bring these only little here.
Make this across time.
And this one is the is.
Let's take a look at the whole animation.
Okay, it's good.
Now I go to add in squash and stretch.
To do this, I open the scale and rotation of the layer, create a keyframe here for them to be able
to know this.
The rotation of the layer.
Will I add a red line to the ball?
So I get to follow its rotation, better isolate these keyframes and move them five frames forward to
create a squash in effect for the ball so that it can acquire energy for the jump.
I go three frames forward, set the X on 18 and decrease the same amount I increased there and say on
12 and put it lower.
I think 19 and 11 is better.
First, the ball needs to be in its original form, so I copy this keyframes to the beginning.
Let me first adjust the rotation of the layer.
Then I go to a squashing and stretching.
All I need to do is to adjust the rotation according to its path.
I have fixed the rotation.
Let's have a look to see how it is.
Okay, It's good.
Now I got to create a squash and stretch.
Isolate these key frames, make them easy.
I just make these keyframes linear to increase the jumping speed.
Here it is.
Squashes.
Here it should stretch.
I said this on 14.
And that one?
16.
Here, it returns to its original form.
Here again, I paste this keyframe.
Here in the why should be on 12 and this on 18.
Anything is too much.
Make it 17.
And this on 30.
In the next frame because the lever hits the ball straight should be more than the previous jump.
It returns to its original form.
Here, I paste this key frame again.
Here.
It should stretch again.
It is gorgeous here.
So I paste the scale keyframe of this position here.
And put it up a little.
Here it should assuage to.
Its rotation must be toward this.
Here in the squashes.
One frame later it stretches.
Generally when the ball is in the air, it keeps its original form.
And when it's falling or rising it stretches.
And when it hit something it is cautious.
So I continue to work and according to the ball speed, I just squash and stretch.
And here it rotates and goes ahead.
Let's have a look and see how it is.
Okay, I'll go here and animate this lever to.
I put in the layers, isolate this layer, and inside them I create a keyframe here for its rotation.
In the next frame, I bring it down and after two frames, I bring it here.
And little higher.
It's good.
Easy is this and create a spring animation for it.
Let's see how it looks.
The speed from here to here is.
So I increase it here.
Here.
When the ball hits the bottom of this layer, it must be squashed.
So I move the next keyframes forward to give it a chance to be squashed.
I have to slow down this keyframe speed.
So I go to the graph editor.
Double click on it and put 100 for a speed.
There should then be a person here for this.
So I make this key frame across time.
And correct it's rotation.
I bring this keyframe forward a little.
So it is Stretch happens later.
Well, it's good to animate this sliver, too.
I enjoy it.
And here, when it hits the ball, I create a key frame.
And create a bonus in animation as I did for the last LOTR.
Well, after that I go for rotating the ball to rotate the ball.
I don't use laser rotation.
That's because when the ball is in this state and it's stretched, if I rotate the ball, it takes a
bad form to prevent this problem.
I go to the shape contents.
By pricing control.
G I put all layers to a group and go to its transform and by using the rotation of the group, rotate
the ball correctly as you see.
Now when I wrote it, the ball that's problem doesn't happen anymore.
Let me increase the scale for a moment for you to completely notice as you see the direction of the
ball.
It doesn't change and only the shape layers rotate.
So I create a keyframe for the rotation of the group here.
Press you when it jumps.
Rotation is not needed here.
I want the ball to rotate from here until it gets here.
And rotates this way.
Let's see how it looks.
And from here it starts rotating this way.
It goes forward.
Rotates until here and continues rotating to lift.
I rotate this three times and see how it looks.
And here it goes back again.
Make this easy is.
And also easy is this one and increase its influence a little.
I hide this tape and see what the final animation looks like.
I think it's good.
Not bad.
This lesson took longer because we didn't use references.
And as you know, when we don't use references, we need to constantly check our timing, spacing and
the whole idea and edit them.
This is a time consuming effort, and the most important reason that made me do this exercise without
references is for you to don't always depend on references because you won't have references all the
time and you need to count on your creativity.
That's because as much as you use creativity in your animations and fantasize about them, you'll see
that you have created more attractive animation.
Good luck.