Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, I want to explain how to create bouncing or spring animation, which is a basic animation
that every animator and motion designer needs to know about.
I want to bring the cup from outside of the scene into the scene and create a bouncing animation for
its position.
So isolate the main layer of the cup and to move the other layer with it.
I parent them to this one.
So I like these layers and pairing them to the couple here.
Now, if I move the middle layer, you see that all layers move as one.
I open its position, put it out of the scene, create a keyframe, go ten frames forward and bring
the cup to the center of the scene.
Many motion designers who make this animation only make keyframes easy, and they are content with the
elements.
But to make your animation more appealing, it is better to give a bounce into your animation to do
so.
First, I need to copy and paste this key frame to the ending of the timeline so the final location
of the layer gets saved.
Then I go to the second keyframes and bring the layer a little to the right.
I go seven frames forward and bring it to the left.
Again seven frames forward and bring the final location here.
Okay.
Let's see how it looks.
If you see your balance in speed is low, you can make the distance five frames.
I bring this one a little closer and this one goes here.
If you want to have more bouncing, you can continue animating, move the layer this way and that,
and in each reciprocation, decrease distance between the keyframe and the final location of your layer.
So as the animation gets to the end, the layer approaches more and more to the final destination,
and at the last it stands on the final location.
This is for when you want to create balancing for the position.
If you want to do the same for rotation as well.
I already set my animation and I want to make balance in animation for this layer rotation.
To do this, I open rotation, create a keyframe for it, make it easy.
I move it two frames backward and after five frames rotate the layer this way, which means -25.
Again.
I go five frames forward here.
It must be on 25 frames.
Forward seven -15.
I decrease it by five each time.
I make the first keyframe linear, so now it has more speed at the beginning and move it a little backward.
It's better to increase the distance between these initial movements.
Until now, you have learned about creating bouncing animations manually.
To do this faster and more realistic.
It is better to use scripts that can increase your workflow speed.
If you don't have access to these scripts, you can use expressions.
For this, I deliver rotation keyframes of this layer.
I also click on the position of the cup layer and paste the bounce in expression here.
If I play now, bouncing is not really visible to work the bouncing expression properly on the animation.
The last keyframe needs to be linear, so I change this keyframe to linear.
As you see, the layer has a bounce, but it is too much.
It's roll bouncing.
You just need to change these values.
Amplitude is for the distance your layer takes from its main location.
For example, in this case, it comes to this point.
If I put this on three.
You see, it goes further away from its main location.
Well, I said this on its original value.
Frequency, as its name implies, indicates the number of round trips of the layer.
I settled on one to have less frequency.
I think it is better on 1.5.
The K indicates energy reduction.
The more I increase it, the sooner energy decreases.
For example, I say to five.
You see, it comes with their.
You can do the same for rotation.
I cut this expression.
So the layer loss is the bouncing effect and I go to the layer and animate this rotation.
I create a keyframe here, go a few frames back.
I always say that this way and make it easy.
So it's speed increases here.
I'll click on the rotation and paste the expression here.
Let's see how it looks.
As you see, the balancing that I've created for the cup is less noticeable here.
To improve it, I increase the amplitude.
And said they came on through to keep it more energetic.
You see, it is faster and more realistic than making it manually.
Good luck.