Well, the next thing to consider in your animation is that before any action you need to do anticipation,
which is one of the principles of animation.
I will explain all the animation principles in the next lessons, what they are and what are they used
for.
But then this lesson I just want to talk about the anticipation principle because it has a great impact
on animations attraction, and most motion designers ignore it and this makes their motion graphics
not much attractive.
Okay, let's go for making anticipation for my animation to do this.
When this cop enters the scene, I want it to go out again in sequence three.
Many motion designers for doing this make only one keyframe for the position.
Make it easy, easy.
And for example, after ten frames, they put it out so simple.
It comes in.
And goes out in order to make our animation more attractive and prepare the audience for its exit.
I will create anticipation to do this.
I delete the second keyframe for now.
Go seven frames forward and bring the cup slightly back and again ten frames later we drag the cob out
of the scene.
As you see, this backward movement of the club prepares the audience for the cops intention to exit.
I make the last keyframe linear, so at the end it's speed increases.
To make it more attractive.
You can reduce the speed of the middle keyframe.
Pay attention.
That anticipation of an animation depends on the layers movement.
If your layer moves to the right, like in here, usually anticipation is toward the left.
If your layer wants to move up, anticipation should be downward.
If it's going to rotate right, it should have left anticipation.
For example I will create a rotation animation to.
I put a ruler here and rotate this.
Here, I move a bit higher and for rotation and position movements to be synchronized, I have to equalize
the speed.
For this I make these two key frames easy.
Ease and Intergraph editor.
I said the influence of the position keyframe to 70 and also set the rotation on 70, so they move accordingly.
As you see this correct now.
And here I would say it like this and say, don't sin and make it linear.
Okay, let's see how it became.
And this better.
We can increase rotation again, bring position higher so its anticipation is more visible.
It comes in.
And goes out.
In the next lesson, I will talk about the overlap in principle.
Good luck.