Hi.
In this lesson, I want to talk about overlapping and follow through principles.
Overlapping means that the movement of the attachment object, like this two layer attached to the top
layer, should have a delay compared to the main object.
The follow through means that when the main object stops, the attachment object needs to continue its
movement like her movements, like necklace movements on the neck.
When the head stops moving, they continue moving, as you see.
Naturally, I have created an overlapping action for the layer here.
The rotation should be on zero.
Let me disable the expression for now.
The length keyframes.
When the cop layer moves, this layer shouldn't be straight like this and should have a delayed animation.
So up here its rotation is this way.
And when the main layer or the cop stops here, the animation of the attached layer continues.
For example, until here it rotates this way and here it rotates the opposite direction.
And at the end it is.
Let's see how it became.
The movement of the year has a delay compared to the couple of year.
And when the cop stops, the movement of the tiller continuous.
This delay of movement is called direct or overlapping.
And when the main layer stops and the attached layer keeps moving, this movement is called follow through.
To do this with expression, I go to the beginning of the timeline where the rotation is zero.
I these this keyframes.
I come here and create a keyframe for rotation.
And here I drag it backward and make this key frame easy, ease and finally enable expression.
Well, let's see how it is.
Here.
When the main lawyer is moving, the lawyer says back and when it stops, the lawyer keeps moving and
follow through is happening.
I should do the same here.
It needs to move a bit backwards.
When the player moves backward, the player needs to rotate, right?
So I create a keyframe for its rotation here and make it easy.
Here.
It rotates this way.
And when it goes here with to the left.
To improve the animation.
I bring the keyframes frames a bit forward so that overlapping happens better.
Let's see the whole animation once more.
Okay.
It is good.
Until now, you have learned about squash and strange anticipation, overlapping and follow through
principles.
Trying to use these principles in creating your animations because they help a lot to make your animations
attractive.
Note that the principles of animation are 12, which I have talked about, important ones that are easy
to use and help to make your animation appealing.
And in the future, I will talk about all 12 principles completely and you will learn about their benefits
and applications.
Good luck.