Hello, everyone.
In this chapter, I'm going to talk about character writing, which is what should we do?
So then we can easily animate our characters.
Creating a skeleton and controllers for a character is called Reading.
The purpose is to be able to animate our character with the least controller, not to animate all the
layers.
For a simple animation, which is really hard work.
There are different plugins and scripts for rigging characters, but I can say that the most popular
of them is doing because first of all, it is free and it is updated every year and it has many useful
tools for rigging and animating the character.
In this chapter, which is the subject of our discussion on character rigging, we get familiar with
the panels and options related to the skeleton and rigging the character in detail.
And in the next chapter, which is about animating the character, you will learn how to create an auto
cycle animation for your character in the easiest way, and then you will learn how to create a cycle
of walking and running in a principal way and with the help of resources from the Internet.
Well, let's look at how to install the script.
To download the script, you can download it from our x laboratory dot org or use the file I put in
the resource of this course.
After downloading the script, we extract the compressed file.
We go to the person two folder.
As you can see, there are a few files and folders which will work with these two folders optional panels
which in that you can install each one of these panels individually.
Or you can go to this UI panels folder and you can have all those panels by copying this file in the
scripts folder of your after effects.
Well, because I want the full version of the script.
I copy this file and go into my computer, drive C programs, file Adobe after Effects 2020 Support
files.
And in script folder a script UI panels and pasted.
After we've done this, we go in after effects.
And if you want to run the scripts first, we should go to edit menu preferences, scripting and expression.
And here we should enable allow script option.
And after that you can find Basil two in the Windows menu and run it.
Then we see a panel appears here.
Let me on deck this and you can go to the imports by clicking on this option and see it stalls.
At the end, you can set your cell panel by dragging its panel anywhere you want.
Good luck.