Since in this course I used the script for reading and scrutinizing my character.
It's better before I start ruining my character.
I get to know the best script and tones I use in this course generally.
So when I started the training and I started to rig the character, I don't have any kind of ambiguity.
First, I run the best.
As soon as I run the vessel, a panel will be shown to us, which is Welcome to the vessel.
Here I can see different panels of the Basil reading panel, Automation's animation camera and tool.
I go into the rigging panel and when the creating structures option is enabled, you can see options
about scrutinizing your character.
The first option is harmony, which creates a fully structure in the skeleton of the human body.
As you can see, skeletons have been created and here I can see layers related to these skeletons.
Well, I go back to the puzzle.
I have control Z.
So I go back to the first estate.
Well, the next options are the arm, leg, spine and tail.
These panels are for creating skeletons for those parts.
These options are used when you want to manually create the skeletons for those parts.
If I go into the setting of each one of these options, you can see there are three options.
The first one is for animals that are similar to humans like bears and bunnies.
The next option is for animals with claws, and the next option is for hoofed animals.
The law shows the form of a skeleton, and here you can select what kind of escalation you need for
your characters.
For example, if you want the shoulder bone, you should enable the shoulder.
And if you don't disable it.
And in part you want here, you can have it by enabling the related option.
If I enable close, you can see the hand parts of animals with claws will show.
For example, I need these three parts and then I click on Create.
As you see, three skeletons have been created for me.
The next option I should explain is duplicate.
This option is used for duplicating the skeletons you have created.
For example, I created this skeleton and I want to duplicate this form and shape.
If I do this by tapping on control D, you can see that it gets ruined.
To avoid this, isolate the skeletons and use the duplicate option.
And if I drag it to this side, you can see that the skeletons are duplicated correctly by the same
shape and form.
In the end, I have the other option which I have in the link and constraint panel to this option is
for rig in your character skeleton automatically.
Let me delineate these layers and let's create a harmonized skeleton.
Let me first note that the skeleton I created is not great at all.
As you can see, when I move the hip bone, none of the skeletons affects another and they are completely
detached.
But if I select all of the skeletons and go into a bezel and use order in this structure panel or I
go to the rig and constraint panel and use the rig, you can see that my character is completely rigged
and controllers have been created for it.
And in that timeline, new layers have been created whose colors are green, and every one of them initially
has a C in their phrases, meaning they are the controller players.
And now if you pay attention, if I move the hip, every other part of the skeleton is affected and
moved by this movement and they are completely rigged or attached to each other.
I go back to the person and the next option I should explain is zero.
By this option we can zero the layers position without changing its location.
So I can easily get back my layer or controller to its first position.
For example, isolate this controller and click on zero.
As you can see, its position is zero.
And now it doesn't matter how much I move this controller, if I want it back to its first place, is
enough to change its position to zero.
As you can see, it gets back to its first place.
Well, the next panel is automation, which has auxiliary tools for creating different animations.
The next panel is the animation, which is related to keyframes and animation.
And this panel, you can easily control different kinds of keyframes and their graphs.
The next panel is related to the camera movements.
And the last panel is the tool which you can have different tools here.
I will give a general explanation about the rename tool because I'm going to use them during this chapter.
This tool, as it's obvious from its name, it's for naming the layers more easily.
For example, this is the skeleton of my character's left hand.
Isolated and I want to delete number two, which is on the end of these layers.
For this.
I click on the last option and then type two, meaning two characters from the list of my layers.
Names should be removed.
So I type two and click on rename.
As you can see, two are deleted.
And if I want to add a letter at the first of the layers names, for example, I want to add a URL,
meaning these skeletons belong to my character's left hand.
I use the prefix option and here I add l and then underline and then click on rename.
As you can see, L is added to my layers.
If I want to change my lawyer's name completely.
It's enough to write here.
And for example, as you can see, all of the layers are renamed to hand.
And if I want to rename all layers to hand.
But number two, it's enough to check the number box and then click on rename.
As you can see, all of the layers are renamed to hand with numbers in order at the end of them.
The suffix option is used for adding a character at the end of the layers names.
For example, I had a space and I left.
Let me delete this one too, so it doesn't add again.
Then I click on rename.
As you can see, lift is added to the ends of my layers.
Names and numbers are placed after them.
I had control Z disable number and again I click on rename.
As you can see, the lift is added at the end of the layers.
Remove The first option is used for removing a character from the first.
Well, I click on this and type two to remove two characters from the first of my layers name.
If I want the added left to be removed, I type five and remove the last.
And remove the lift I added here so it doesn't add again.
As you can see, Labor's name are back to what they were.
Well, it's enough so far.
Now we are familiar with the options we want to work with.