Hey, everyone.
It must have occurred to you that you want to read and animate the character, but realize that the
character is not designed for the rig and animate and eventually your animation will have problems when
rotating the joints.
So in this video, I want to talk about how you can prepare characters for rigging.
Well, I open the file that I've downloaded from free pick.
Since I need this character.
I select the rest, cut them and paste them into a new layer using control, shave and hide it.
First of all, I need to set the art world.
Isolate the character and resize it.
After doing so, it's time to separate the different parts of the character and put them in individual
layers.
I don't need this back, so I delete it.
I cut this part of the arm.
Paste it into a new layer and name it writes are.
Then I do the same for the rest of the parts and put them in individual layers.
For her hand.
I use this layer.
After that's done, I need to save the file.
Then I go to After Effects and import the intended file.
I import it as a composition and layer size.
Afterward, I go to the camp.
I don't need this layer anymore.
I also hide the left leg and left arm for now.
Now I have to work on creating the different parts of the lake, isolate the right click and convert
it to shape to create joints properly.
First, I need to select the layer and choose the Ellipse tool, and here is where the thigh joints
should be placed.
So I make a circle right here.
It should exactly fit the leg shape.
I disabled the stroke.
I move down a little bit.
The ne part should be around right here.
So I make another circle here.
I change its color so it would be obvious.
Then I go for creating the joint of the ankle.
It should be made right here.
Then I duplicate this layer twice and specify the different parts of the lake.
In the land of the thigh.
I remove the shapes that I don't need.
I create a point here and another one here, and I remove these parts.
I also create the point here and another here and move it a little.
And I delete these.
I don't need this.
Then I changed the color of the joint to the color of the main layer.
For this part.
I don't need the side parts, so I delete them.
I changed the color of the joints to the color of their sides shapes.
Well, let's work on the food part.
I like the unnecessary shapes.
I and hide this shoe layer and convert it to shape.
Then I copy shapes and paste him into the write for the layer and I placed them right where they should
be.
Then I delete the previous layer.
After that, I should place the anchor points right in the center of the joints.
For doing so, I just have to hide all the shapes except for the joints.
Then I hold control and double click on the pan behind tool.
As you can see, the anchor point will be placed right in the center of the shape.
Then I can unhide the layers.
I do the same for these joints as well.
As you see, once I rotate the joints, I don't face any problems at all.
To prevent this.
I put this above the skin layer.
Then I layer to the thigh layer and the foot layer to additional layer.
Then I rotate the leg so it would be in a straight line.
After doing so, I duplicate the layers and use them for the left leg.
I moved forward right here.
And for it to have a different color, I add the little effect to it.
I face the same effect for the other layers as well.
I also have to remove this line.
After that, I also have to create the hip part.
To do so, I convert the body layer into a shape.
Ideally the previous layer.
Inside these isolate the body layer and create the hip.
I move this lately a little further so it would match with the hip.
The anchor point of the body should be right here.
Okay.
The next thing is working on the arms.
As you can see here, the joints are circular shapes, but the problem is that it's not possible to
place the anchor points precisely in the center of the joints for fixing this.
I need to convert it to shape and add a circle right here.
After doing so, I can easily place the anchor point in the center of the joints.
I do the same for the knee and the ankle.
And now once I wrote it, then it works well.
The problem here is that the size of the arm doesn't match with the forearm.
So I need to fix this.
For doing so.
Isolate the arm shape and delete this point and make it smaller so it would be the same size as disjoint.
If you give it a look, you can see that it's working properly.
I delete this shape to.
Then I parent the hand to the forearm and the forearm to the arm.
And place them in a straight line.
Then I duplicate these layers and use them for live.
I moved the layers right here.
Then I placed him under the lake layers.
Oh, I missed the point that I should have separated the toes as well for doing so.
I duplicate this layer and name it toes.
Then I saw these two shapes.
Firstly, I make the toes part.
Its anchor point should be placed right here.
I hide this layer.
This part of the phone has to rotate this much.
So I need to extend this shape up until here.
And now once I rotate it, you can see that there wouldn't be any sort of problem.
Okay.
I have to do the same for the other four to.
And the anchor point of the head should be right here.
And finally, if you're interested in character reading and you want to learn how to read all character
parts and the expressions which are needed in this context and once for all, make yourself needless
and read in the character, I recommend you watch this course.