Hello, everyone.
You might think that reading and animating a character is very difficult, but in this video I will
show you how easy it can be to rig and animate a character using the basil.
This is the result I want to get to at the end.
Let's get the sonnet.
The first thing I need from Regan is a character.
After downloading the character.
What I need to do is to make the joints of the character simpler so that no problem happens to the joints
while telling them.
As you see, I have made all join circular.
After that, I will go to the Duke and create the skeletons for it.
You must make sure that the anchor point of this skeleton is exactly on the layers Anchor point.
To do.
So I use this snapping tool.
To create the left arm skeleton, isolate these skeletons and duplicate them in the bezel and to rename
the layers.
I go to the tool section and then rename.
I want to remove two characters from the end of the names, so I insert tool here and also I want to
add live and an underline in the beginning.
I also want to name these layers for the right arm skeleton.
So I add this to the beginning.
I bring this skeleton here?
I don't need this.
I enable the snapping and put the layers into place.
After doing that, I move on to create the skeletons for the body.
The body consists of several parts.
First, the head.
Second, the chest.
Third, the neck and forth.
The head.
Therefore, I go to the spine settings.
I need a skeleton for the head.
One for the neck.
One for the spine.
And one for the hip.
Isolate the created layers along with the body, head, neck and hip layers.