After I'm done scrutinizing the character, I move on to parenting the layers, to the skeletons.
To do that, the characters are always or must be parented to the right arm.
Skeleton.
Which is this layer and also the other parts must be parented to their related skeletons.
After parents in different parts of the character to the skeletons, the components of the face such
as the glasses, eyes, eyebrows, nose and the mouth must be parented to the head layer.
Also, this part of the hair must be parented to the head.
After that, isolate the skeletons by hitting the selected structures option in the Links and Constraints
section, I click on the order option.
I get back to the topic again in the structure panel.
Hit the show and hide option to completely hide the structures.
As you can see, the character is perfectly right now.
After doing that to animate the character, I just need to go to the automation panel and use the work
cycle tool before I apply the work cycle tool.
I go to settings to make sure that the work cycle has identified the controllers.
I will check the controllers once more to make sure they are properly defined here.
So this is the right arm controller and it's defined correctly here.
As you see, all the controllers are properly identified here.
Let's get back.
Isolate the controllers and click on the work cycle.
Once I have the walk cycle, you'll see that the character starts to walk.
But her gait is the opposite.
To fix this movement.
I go to the main parameters in the work cycle section and remove this negative.
And now the character moves forward.
The problem here is that the left hand rotation angle is not correct.
To fix it, isolate the controller.
And here the reverse is no longer functional.
Because when I apply the work cycle, as you see the arms controller exits the IK mode and sets to the
f k mode.
To solve this problem.
I go to the individual control.
I hit the key and go to the beginning.
Since the key frames were created here and I start rectifying the characters or mangle.
Let's move to the work cycle settings.
As you see, the character legs are bent in all positions.
Well, when the character is in this post, this leg must be straight.
To fix this problem, isolate the body controller and bring the character up a little.
Let's check you out.
It got a little better now.
I think the hands still need a little look to find.
I go to the arms controller.
I go to the work site setting.
Then go to character.
I increased the energy bit to make the character more flexible.
And second control in body.
I change 5 to 3 to reduce the up and down movement of the body.
In the legs.
I increased the height.
As you can see, it affects the lifting of the legs.
I say to 100.
The pacing interval is a bit short.
So I go to the walk cycle and increase this.
The energy is a bit high.
I said it's in its own default value.
The body must go higher.
Let's check it out.
I should reduce this a bit more.
More with over.
To make the head move more, I increase this.
And as for the arms, I said this to Tim.
Let me hide the controller so I know exactly what's going on.
The body must be moved a little further.
I move the body furthermore, to make it better.
Let me set the bar.
So in the six to see if it gets better or not.
I reduced this a little.
Increase this.
And said hi to 70.
To prevent this line from getting on her leg.
I bring this layer on top of the body.
I can go here and to reduce the walking pace, increase this a little.
I set it to 230.
I think 210 is better.
As you see, I was able to read and animate the character without creating any keyframes using the basil.
To get acquainted with all the tools and abilities that the person provides you for animating and rigging
the character.
I suggest you watch the discourse on rigging the character using the pestle, which can really be useful
to beginners who want to become professional in rigging and animating the characters.