In this video, we want to talk about the 12 principles of animation and understand how to make our
animation or motion graphics more beautiful.
These principles are introduced by the two best Disney animators, meaning Oli Johnson and Frank Thomas,
for creating a beautiful and smooth motion graphic.
You should first know these principles, and then with practicing a lot, you can use them in your motion
graphics.
The first principle is a scratch and stretch, meaning you should stretch and scratch your objects relatively
the speed movement and weight of your object.
In this example, as you can see, the ball has a scratch and a stretch.
When it's falling, it stretches and when it smashes the ground it is crashes and eventually it gets
back to its first shape.
But in this one, the ball doesn't scratch and stretch anymore.
As you can see, squashing and stretching are very effective in making our animation beautiful.
This technique can be used in simple objects like these balls and complicated objects like the characters
movements and the characters face.
As you can see, character stretches when it's falling and when it is ready to jump splashes.
In this sample for looking better When the character's eye closes, the head squashes, and when the
eye starts to open up, the head stretches.
The important point this principle is the volume of the object should be always constant, meaning when
the object squashes, it should get broad and wide, and when it stretches it should get thin and slim.
Sometimes for looking at animation more appealing, we can do this stretching and squashing with exaggeration
and don't observe the proportion of the volume.
As you can see in these samples.
The second principle is anticipation, meaning before our character does.
The main move shows some movements to prepares the audience for the main move.
For example, here the character is doing a half leap, which is an anticipation, and it wants to show
the audience that it is going to jump.
When an animation has an anticipation, it looks more real because in reality, when someone wants to
jump, if he doesn't get ready for a jump and doesn't squeeze and can stretch this body, he can't jump.
So it's better than if you want your animations to look more realistic.
You use this principle.
This is an animation with anticipation.
And this one is without anticipation.
And as you can see, the left one is much more beautiful and realistic.
Let's see some more samples about anticipation in motion graphics In this sample, the character before
exiting the scene and going down shows anticipation and moves itself up a little bit and moves his hands
up.
So gets the audience ready for its exit of the scene.
And in the next example, as you can see, the rabbit for showing an anticipation before any reaction,
its head and body moves down and its knees bend.
So it gets ready our audience for the reaction it is going to do.
And as you can see, it is really effective.
And the animations beauty.
The third principle is staging, meaning that you should show the activities in your scene in a way
that your main idea can be fully understood by the audience.
In other words, staging meaning is the ability to control the viewer's attention with this principle.
We show to our viewers what elements are the main ones, what happened and what is going to happen.
We shouldn't confuse the viewer with continuous and irregular happenings.
We have to show only one happening in one movement so the viewer understands where to look and finds
out the main idea.
For these.
The main activities should happen by the turn and with a little pause so that a special moment can be
shown important.
And for showing the main objects, we can discriminate them by light size or the details we create for
them.
Let's see the main activities in this example.
The character first says Hello.
The laptop appears, which is connected to wi fi.
Then the TV which is connected to wi fi to comes into the scene, then character notices its phone and
its last activity is connecting to the internet by the mobile.
As it is completely obvious.
The main idea of the clip is that we can connect wi fi with different devices.
Try to keep your scene not too crowded and messy unless this is your main idea and you want to confuse
the viewer.
You should pay attention to this fact that in crowded scenes you shouldn't show all of the objects in
one moment because it is so hard for the viewer to focus on your animation.
Always calm your elements to the scene with delay or random so the viewer doesn't get confused.
The fourth principle is straight ahead and post to post animation.
In fact, this principle expresses two ways for designing an animation.
The first way straight ahead means that we can design the animation frame by frame from the start till
the end.
Which usually is really useful for estimating fire and water.
But using it in character.
Animation is really hard and complicated, especially when you are not aware of things that are going
to happen.
But the second way is posed to pose, which in this method, first the key poses are designed and then
the in between them.
And then you can design the easing process.
This method is better for complicated animation because you can have a general overview of the things
that are going to happen.
We will have a lot to do with this method post to pose, especially when we get to character animation
and creating a walk cycle or run cycle animation.
Let's see some samples of its usage in motion graphics.
As you can see in these examples.
Motion Designer for reaching the main idea of his animation and what he has in mind.
First, he creates key poses by sketching and creates an elementary animation of what is going to happen
at the end and then starts to finalizing the animation.
The next principle is follow through or overlapping.
This technique helps a lot.
Showing the object's movements more real follow through means that the secondary or appendix objects,
even after the main object is stopped from moving, should keep moving.
Overlapping means parts of the main object react with a delay and different speed from the main object
and stay behind.
Like these samples.
Appendix objects should keep moving after the main object stops and move at different times.
This principle is also used for showing a live objects and objects that are not moving like clothes
and hairs.
As you can see, this principle causes our animation to look more real and natural.
So certainly use it in creating your animations.
The next principle is easy in and easy out, which is the most important principle in animation.
Most activities that happen in our lives follow this principle.
Every object needs time to accelerate for reaching to its top speed and also when it wants to reach
the lowest speed from the high speed.
This should happen little by little.
In frame by frame animation, you should design more frames in the first and last parts of your animation,
so its start and finish moves are smooth and real.
More beginners mistake is that they use linear keyframes, which causes their animation to be very artificial
and rough.
Smooth animations are much better.
Elements appear at different times and they have a smooth first and end, which you can do this by smoothing
the graphs and the first and last parts.
Absolutely.
This doesn't mean that we shouldn't use linear keyframes at all, but we should know that most of the
time smoothing the key frames causes beauty.
You should know that every key frame kind is related to a particular position which you can get to know
them by experience.
The next point that you should know is sometimes you don't have only one object, but you have a few
objects that should be animated continuously, like animate awards letters.
Besides using the letters animation, the general animation of the world has got to be easing too.
So appearing the letters don't happen in turn and doesn't create a linear and boring state.
But the general animation of the words should start smooth and then it starts to accelerate and at the
end it finishes slow and the words animation should be overlap.
This act always makes your animation cool and interesting.
The next principle is arc.
Most movements in the real world follow a curve.
If we want our animation to be natural and beautiful, we should follow this rule.
This rule can be used for characters, parts and also for simple objects.
As you can see in this example, the movements of the characters body parts follow the arcs, which
absolutely in the walk and run cycles lesson we get to know with this concept practically should obey
this rule in head.
Turning to as you can see, if you don't follow this rule, how much our animation looks artificial
and boring, but when the head animation is done with arcs looks much better and beautiful.
This is an example of objects that are following the arcs.
Our truly is that in fast movements and machine movements, we should use straighter pathways and in
slower movements or normal movements, we should use more bent curves.
As you can see in the left example, because this clip's animation is speed is normal.
Bends, curves have been used.
And in the right one because it has fast speed.
The straight curves have been used.
The next principle is secondary action.
This principle expresses movements and details which causes us to know more things about our character.
For example, the secondary action of the left hand shows the character's state if his hand is fist
mode.
It shows that our character is angry.
If it is like this.
It shows his happiness.
If his hand is in the front and close to its body and he looks around, it shows that he is hiding something
and he knocks on the door secretly.
The movements we can add in this principle are so personalized, meaning my secondary action may be
different from yours, and for adding secondary action, the only thing you should do is asking yourself,
Well, what other thing can I add to it?
Sometimes adding some details to our animation can make our animation more alive.
Absolutely.
You should consider that these movements shouldn't distract our viewers mind from the main move.
Well, let's go and see their usage in motion graphics.
Look at this sample.
The main movie is that the female character wants to throw her opponents chess piece, but when she
wants to do it, her facial expression changes, which can express pride and arrogance feeling to the
viewers and her hand state when she wants to pick up the chess piece and move it.
She can express her arrogance feelings so beautifully.
In the next example, when the boy character wants to eat something looks around in a special way which
can show the viewer that he's doing something secretly.
In the next example, a character is doing her routine activities that we're taking a deep breath.
She expresses that her routine activities are so boring too.
The next principle is timing.
It means that animation's identity depends on the number of frames that have been designed for an activity.
That means the more the number of frame is, the speed of that activity slows down and the less number
of frames means the speed will be more from the physical aspect.
Every object has a different volume, weight and condition, which here means every object needs different
times for doing a particular activity.
So in the places that are necessary to show the characters speed and agility, we should use fewer frames.
And in places we want to show the details better.
Animation has a higher speed automatically.
Like this example, we should use more frames.
The 10th principle is exaggeration.
This principle means that every activity can go a level higher, so its impact on the viewer increases.
Because when we want to animate our animation like the real world, it's going to be an ordinary process
that can be so boring.
So the purpose of this principle is looking at animations more appealing by doing exaggeration in them.
For example, if the character is sad, we make it sadder, and if it's happy, we make it look happier.
If it's for it, we make him look more worried.
If it's confused, we make it look more confused.
So it shows its condition more obvious.
The important point that you should know, the exaggerated range in line exaggeration doesn't mean to
make our character bend and deform, but it means to make our animation more believable and effective.
Let's see two samples of this principle in motion graphics.
As you can see, the left sample shows a character who is going to pull the dark color.
But the animator has done this work a level higher and he has exaggerated so beautifully.
Like And the other side of the color a champion is pulling the rope, which has caused this elongation
and at the end a rupture of the rope and then the character gets thrown to the back.
If the animator wanted to show this happening natural or real, and what happens in the real world,
how boring it was.
But now that there is an exaggeration, you can see how appealing it is.
The right sample is a fantasy sample that shows a playful square that comes into the scene and bothers
the circle on the water.
And the circle doesn't do an ordinary thing for the retaliation, like throwing this square away.
But it takes that job to the next level and swallows the square, which is an appealing exaggeration.
The next principle is solid drawing.
This principle is more related to animation designers and is very close.
The frame by frame or 3D design.
And this means the form you create.
It should look like that is placed in a 3D environment, meaning the character should have the right
amount of volume and weight in different angles.
Animators should be very experienced and expand because they should know 3D Designing Perspective principles,
anatomy and different poses of a character.
And the last principle is appeal.
This principle is more related to the characters designer, and its meaning is that character should
be attractive and can get communicated with the viewer.
It is not necessarily needed that this principle should be considered for the champion character, but
it can be a monster, a villain or a diagram for making characters more attractive.
You can use dynamic designs and there are three methods for making designs dynamic.
The first way is to use different shapes for designing the characters.
Instead of using one shape for all of the characters.
Use different shapes.
The second way is to play with proportions.
In this way you can find every character's index and exaggerate it to reach a more attractive design.
Thirdly, you should keep your designing simple because this character should animate in too much detail.
Besides that, it is confusing.
It will ruin the animation to.
Well, 12 principles of animation are done.
And if you want to use these 12 principles in your animations and motion graphics, try to review these
principles before every animation you're going to make, use them in your animations.
So after high repetition, you can involuntary use them in your animations without paying attention
to these principles.
Good luck.