In this lesson, we want to learn how to create keyframes and animations.
For example, I want this plane to move and stop here.
To do so, I select the plane layer and go to the transform.
And to be able to give the plane this kind of movement.
I have to use the position of the plane.
Well, I want to give the plane a movement like this
to animate this, the first thing to do is to create a keyframe.
So to create a keyframe, you just have to click on the stopwatch beside the position property.
As soon as I left click on the stopwatch, it turns blue and you see one keyframe is created here.
You may ask why my keyframe is created here and nowhere else.
It's because keyframes are created where the indicator is positioned.
For example, if I want to create a keyframe for the scale, you see that the scale keyframe is created here,
not at the beginning of the timeline.
That's why you have to be careful where the indicator is when you are creating the keyframes.
Well, to delete the scale keyframe, all I need to do is to click on the stopwatch again or select
the keyframe and then press delete button.
Well, now we have created a key frame for the position of the plane layer, but we don't have any animation.
Why?
Because for creating an animation, we need at least two key frames for creating the second key frame.
First, we need to bring the indicator to the intended time.
For example, I put it on second two and I want to create another keyframe for the position.
To create another keyframe.
I only have to click on this option.
As you see, another keyframe is created after I created the second keyframe.
The left arrow of this option is activated.
It means you can go to the last keyframe by clicking on it or by clicking on the right arrow.
You can go to the next keyframe, and by clicking on this option again, you can delete this keyframe
or create a new keyframe.
Well, now I have created the second keyframe.
If I press the space button and play the animation again, you see, there is no motion for the plane
while we have two keyframes.
The next thing to consider is that in animation we need to keyframes with two different values.
So in the first keyframe, the position value is this, and in the second keyframe is also the same
value, and there is no change.
And this is the reason why no changes happen to the plane when I play.
To move the plane.
I go to the position, change its X and put it here.
You see, as I change its position, a line appears here that shows the movement direction of the layer.
And if I go to the beginning of the timeline and play the animation, you see that the plane moves.
I go to the second keyframe and delete it again.
The easier way to create your animation is not to create the second keyframe yourself.
As soon as you select your layer and move it, you see a keyframe is created where the indicator is placed
and the new position of your layer is saved.
I think until now you understand the meaning of the keyframe is storing the value of the position,
scale, rotation or any other property at a specific time.
You see in this time this value is stored for the position of this layer, and in this time this value is stored.
If you select the layer, you see some small dots in this direction line which are shown the layers
position in different frames.
You see in the first second.
It is here on this dot.
If I go to the next frame.
So I press page down to go to the next frame.
You see it goes on the next dot.
If I press page down again, it goes on the next dot.
These dots are the position of the layer in different frames.
You can also change your animation path.
For this you only have to select the key frame.
Activate the pen tool, then left Click on the keyframes in the path
and after appearing the handles, you can change your animation path easily.
For example, I set it like this and also make the handle visible in the beginning and set it like this.
And now if I play it, you see the plane is going to move along the path I have created.