In this lesson, we want to talk about different kinds of keyframes.
Keyframes are categorized according to their speed.
Here I have made four circles in different colors and made the same animation for them.
So after we apply these different keyframes on them, we notice the difference between them.
OK, The first kind is linear.
As you see, it has a diamond shape.
It means the speed of the animation is constant and linear all along.
If I select the keyframes and go to 'graph editor' you see here this line is representing the speed of
animation, which is linear and straight.
And if I keep my pointer on the first keyframe, you see the speed of the animation in the beginning
is on 1128 pixels per second, and this speed is kept all along to the end without increasing or decreasing.
As I explained before, by these dots and equal space between them, you can understand that the animation
of this circle is linear and its speed is the same during the animation.
Well, I go back to the key frames.
The second type of keyframe is 'easy ease in'.
This means the speed of the animation is high at the beginning and it slows down along the path.
Well, I select key frames for this layer.
I can press shift F9 or right click on the keyframes and from Keyframe Assistant, click on easy ease in.
And as you see keyframe shapes changes to the right arrow, and also from the dots, you can understand
the animation speed is high at the beginning and at the end, because of the high density of the dots,
the speed has decreased.
I play it now
As you see at the beginning, this circle goes beyond the last circle, which is linear, but at the
end they stop at the same time.
And this means at the end, the animation speed has decreased.
I select Keyframes and Inter graph editor.
As you see, speed line of the animation is not linear.
In the beginning, the speed of the animation increases to 1500, but then as it progresses, the animation
speed is decreased and falls down to zero at the end.
Well, I go to the third type of keyframe easy ease out.
Its hotkey is Ctrl + shift + F9.
This one is the opposite of the previous type.
It means at the beginning animation speed is low and the more we progress it increases, I select keyframes
and click on easy ease out.
As you see it shape is opposite of the last one and it is an arrow to the left.
If you pay attention, you see the density of the dots is higher at the beginning, meaning animation
speed is lower at the beginning and at the end speed is going to be higher.
I go to the graph editor.
You see it is the opposite of the previous case.
Low speed at the beginning and increasing over time.
Okay, let's go to the last one easy ease, with hotkey F9 in this type.
The beginning and end of the animation is speed are low, but it's increased in the middle.
I select keyframes, right click and easy ease them.
Now, if you pay attention here, the density is high.
It is high here, too.
But compared to the beginning and the end, the density of the dots is lower here.
And as you see, the shape of the keyframes is like an hourglass.
I select keyframes and go to the graph editor, as you see at the beginning.
The speed is zero.
It goes higher to this point and then it goes down to zero here.
If I play now, you can see, even though the duration of all these circles is the same because they
have different speeds, they also show different animations.
Now that we know four main types of keyframes, let's go to the next column to get familiar with other
types of keyframes as well.
The first one, as I explained, is easy ease.
At the beginning, speed is low.
It goes higher and then it decreases again and falls down to zero.
The next one is easy ease in, at the beginning speed is higher and at the end the speed decreases
and the next one is easy ease out, which I explained before.
The next one is linear.
Another keyframe you need to know about is toggle hold.
This means our layer is in a frame in a specific place.
Then in the next frame is in another place.
And this happens without any movement.
To summarize, the hold animation happens in a jump, not by movement.
We just see in a moment.
It goes from here to there.
The next kind of keyframe is Rove across time, and it's for when you want to change the animation path and
apply single easy is to the whole keyframes.
Well, I select Rove across time keyframes, disable Rove across time, and I want to create single easy ease
for whole animation of this ball.
That means at the beginning of the animation speed is low here in the middle speed increases and at
the end speed decreases again.
So I select keyframes right click and easy ease them.
If you pay attention, you see what we intended to do Didn't happen correctly
because the circle has a short pause where the keyframes are, and this makes
our animation doesn't run smoothly.
If I go to the graph editor, you see the speed of the animation is zero at the beginning.
Then increases, decreases again, increases again.
And so on
As you see, this makes the circle stop in the animation path.
To solve this problem I have to use Rove across time.
To do that, I select middle keyframes and enable Rove across time.
Now, if I go back to the graph editor, you see the keyframes as dots are spread in the speed graph
of the animation, and it is completely harmonic with the animation speed graph.
Now, if I play, you see that I have created the intended animation.
At the beginning.
Speed is low.
It increases and at the end it decreases.
Although I have three key frames here, I was able to create single easy ease for the whole animation
without any pause
I increse Its ease slightly.
From these dots, you can completely understand what animation speed is going to be.
The next type of keyframe is linear continuous.
Its hotkey is Ctrl + Click and it has a shape like a circle.
This kind of keyframe is for when you have middle keyframes.
Like this animation.
I select three key frames and easy ease them and play.
As you see, the layer has a little pause on the top.
And I want to remove this pause
For this.
I go to graph editor and here to remove the pause I bring this keyframe higher to increase layer speed.
If I do this, you see, the keyframe becomes two points and I have to adjust them separately.
And this job takes time.
To prevent this, I just need to select this keyframe.
Hold down Ctrl and left Click on it
as you see the keyframes change into a circle shape and now you can increase or decrease
the speed of your keyframe without it becoming two points.
You can also do this in graph editor by right clicking on the keyframe, selecting keyframe velocity
and enabling the continuous option.
For now, I disable it.
You see, it becomes two points, and then I go to Velocity and enable it.
And you see two points of the keyframe move together.
Well, in this lesson, we got to know about different types of keyframes.
In the next lesson, we'll learn about different kinds of graphs and how to edit them.
Good luck.