And this is I'll be working on a project from scratch to finish so you can better understand the process
of creating an animation.
In this part I'll be using the shape tool for designing, and also you'll find a brief introduction
to this tool and how to use it, because in the later lessons there will be a dedicated chapter about
shapes, their modifiers and how to create animations using them.
As I explained before, the first thing that I need to do is create a new composition.
So I create a composition for the savings of the comp.
I use the presets I choose HD 1920 by 1080 and I said the duration of the comp to 30 seconds and I set
the background color to gray.
I hit okay.
After that, I want to use this reference and create this be using the shape tool to do so.
I like the layer so it won't be selected and moved.
Isolate the shape to.
And I thought designing this.
I began the designing process by clicking here and then dragging as I drag.
You can see the two handles appear with which you can control the curve of the path.
If I hold shift and drag, you can see that the handles will be in fixed, horizontal, vertical and
diagonal lines.
So I make it straight like this.
The next point would be here I clicked and drag, so the shape matches the reference flawlessly.
For now.
I don't need this truck, so I disable it so that I can see the path and design the shape more precisely.
I create the next point here and track.
I continue like this for now, and then I come back and fix these parts later.
I create another point here?
Then I click on the first point again.
So the path would be closed for these parts where the path doesn't match their friends.
I have to fix the handles for them.
As you see, if I move one of the handles, the other one moves as well and I don't want this.
So to adjust one of the handles I hold alter and change one handle.
Okay, I have to fix this Part two.
I hold on and match the path with the reference.
I want to rename the layer so I selected and hit enter and I type body.
I click on the stroke and select solid color so its stroke will be enabled.
I make the straw color brown.
And I said it switch to five pixels.
I click on the field, select solid color and hit the okay.
And to change the field color, I hide the layer for now.
I click on the field color and choose the color of the reference.
Now, if I show the layer, you can see that the film color matches the reference.
To see the way you're better, I swallow the layer so you can only see this layer.
I hide the body layer.
Now let's work on creating this part to create this part much faster and easier.
I duplicate the body layer to do that, isolate the layer and heat control.
I name the layer line.
And isolate the pen tool and create one point for the shape right here.
I create another point here?
Another point here and a point over here.
After that, I swallow the layer so I can work on it better.
Then I have to isolate the other points for that, isolate one point and hold onto and select the point
that I don't need.
And I hit the delete key.
I don't want this point either, so I delete it as well.
After that I don't want it struck, so I disable it.
I make the reference visible.
I hide the line layer for now so I can match the path with the reference better.
I hold all two and try to match it with the reference.
Again, I hold alt and try to do that.
I do the same for these points as well.
I make both layers visible and I make the line color brown.
Let me hide your reference so I can see how much we have progressed.
Now let's work on this thing part.
I just have to create a triangle.
I put it below the body layer and I name it this thing.
For the eyes.
I use the lips tool.
I come here in the center of the circle, I hold control shift and start driving.
So it starts from the center and it remains symmetrical.
And for the anchor point to move to the center of the shape, isolate the layer, hold control and double
click on the pen behind to.
I rename it.
I duplicate the layer and rename it again.
For the you're not to move around and in unwanted directions, just hold shift and drag.
So it would only move alongside the x axis.
Let's take a look at it again.
Then I create the cheeks.
For that I just have to duplicate this layer and move it over here.
To scale up the layer.
I just have to use these points.
I hold shifts so as not to disturb its proportion.
I changed color like the reference.
I duplicate it and move it here.
Let's work on the mouth part.
For that.
I use the pen tool.
I create a point like this here.
And here.
Like this.
I disable its feel.
An enabling stroke.
I swallowed the layer.
As you can see, these parts aren't around to round them up.
Just like the reference.
I have to go to the shape layer in contents.
I open the shape.
In a stroke section.
I set the line cap to round cap.
And now these parts are around and about the settings.
Don't worry, because I've explained all these settings in the Shape chapter.
Well, let's take a look at the layers we've created so far.
It looks all right.
Let me rename this layer to.
Then I'm going to create the antennas for that.
I use the pen tool.
I renamed the layer.
As delayed and isolated.
I create this circle so that both of the shames would place in one layer.
I come to the center of the circle and by holding control shift and dragging, I create the circle.
I disable it.
Stroke.
And enable its feel and I change its color like the reference.
To fix its size.
I make it smaller.
I hold shifts so as not to disturb its proportion.
I have to place its anchor point here because I want to rotate it from here to make the other antenna.
I duplicate this layer and put it here and rotate it.
Then I'm going to create the wings.
For that.
The easiest way would be to create a circle here.
I rename it.
Note that when you use these tools to create your shape, you won't have any control over the points.
As you can see, if I want to change any point, I can do that.
And the only control you have is changing its size and position.
But if you want to have control of its path and points, you just have to right click on the Leap's
path and convert it to a busier path.
After doing so, if you hover over the points using the pen tool, the icon of the tool changes and
now you can freely change the path for that, isolate one point and hit control.
A So all of the points would be selected and then I hit control tw.
So this tool appears and now I can transform, rotate and change the shape however I want.
Then I rotate the shape in a way that this point would be aligned with the connection point of the wing
to the body.
Then I pick up the pen tool again, hold alt and click here.
So all points would be select and I select this point and move it here.
And now I adjusted like this.
Isolate the shape, change its true color.
And I changed the field color like the reference.
And I place the anchor point over here.
This layer should be placed below the antennas.
I duplicate the layer and move it below the body.
I rotated like that.
And I slightly move it to the right.
Let me hide your reference and I make the other layers visible.
Well, I create a background as well.
Rename it.
And I place it below the other layers.
And then I have to create a shadow for this.
For it to be exactly in the center.
I enable Title Action save.
And then I hold control and create a shadow for it.
I disable it strong and make the film color brown.
I name it Shadow.
And I put it below.
I disable title action save.
I place its anchor point in the center and decrease its opacity a little.
Well, our design is quite ready.
In the next part, I'll begin animating the speed.
So I'll see you there.