As you know, I designed this be in the previous video.
Now I want to animate it to do that first thing.
First, I want to animate the body of the body.
First of all, I place its anchor point in the center of it.
I open the position of the layer by hitting the key.
I create a keyframe for it.
I zoom in a bit.
It's shift page down so I got and frames forward.
And I moved the body up a little bit.
As you can see, once I move the body of the B, the other layers don't move alongside it all at once,
all of them to move.
So for this to happen.
I move back to the beginning of the timeline where all of the layers are intact and in one place, and
I select every layer.
And by the pickup I parent them to the body layer.
Now, if you notice, once the body moves up, every other layer moves as well.
I hit shift pitch down and I moved ten frames forward and now I want to copy and paste the first keyframe
here, isolate the keyframe copy and paste it here.
And then I make the keyframes easy.
As you can see, I made such a movement for the B.
I want my B to constantly go up and down.
To do so.
I can select all the keyframes and copy and paste them frequently, which is a time consuming method
and unprofessional.
Because if you need to change the animation later, you have to change all the keyframes to get rid
of this repetition.
I have to look the value of the position for that I hold onto and left click on the stopwatch of the
position.
I click on this arrow icon and in property.
I click and loop out cycle.
After that, there will be an expression in the expression box which makes the animation loop continuously.
Okay, I click over here, so the expression would be applied.
Now, if I play, you can see the B constantly goes up and down.
Let me make the scene fit.
Now let's work on animating the wings.
Isolate the wings.
By hitting the R I open the rotation, I create the keyframe for them.
I go two frames forward.
I rotate the wing downwards.
And the other one as well.
I decrease the opacity of the wings.
For that I select the layers I see and set their opacity to 75.
Again, I select the wing layers and reduce the keyframes which show up.
I move two frames forward.
And they want to copy and paste the initial keyframes here.
If I choose the keyframes of two layers and hit control C then control E.
As you can see, the layers duplicate instead, which isn't what I wanted to copy the keyframes.
Only I have to use a script, so I use the motion tools, the script which I have put in the resource
folder of the course.
You can find and use it and to install it you can go to the after effects installation folder.
For that right click on the After Effects icon.
Again, right click on the After Effects and choose properties.
Click on open file location.
Then go to the scripts folder and then scripts your panels.
And right here just pays whatever script you want.
For instance, I copied this script for the resource folder of the course and pasted it right here.
After that, just go to edit.
Preferences, General.
Right here in scripting and expressions.
Check these boxes and hit OC.
Then you can run the motion to the script in the Windows menu.
I close this and open it again just to show you all.
I hit this and it opens again.
And if it was floating, you can just drag it and hold in its name and place it wherever you want.
Now let's get back to the animation, isolate the keyframes and copy and paste them right here.
I use the clone option.
As you can see, only the keyframes got copied, not layers.
And then I make them easy is.
As you can see, it only moves its wings.
Wants to look the animation of the wings.
I can hold on and click on one of these stopwatches again from here.
Properly I choose Look out cycle.
To do this easier, I right click on the property that has the expression and choose copy expression
only.
Then select the properties that you want to have this expression and it's control V.
Now, as you can see, the animation of the wings works perfectly.
So add motion blur to the animation of the wings.
You can select the wing layers and enable motion blur for them.
And then you have to enable this option too.
If you pay attention, the animation of the wings has motion blur.
After that, let's work on the antennas.
For that isolate both antennas a heads are and open the rotation.
I create a keyframe for them here.
I rotate this little bank in the beginning, using the page down.
I move four frames forwards and I rotate this layer to the left, this one to.
Again, four frames forwards and I copy and paste the initial keyframes here.
I make the keyframes easy, and because I've already copied the expression isolate these values and
hit control V.
Let's take a look at the animation.
All right.
It looks good for the animation of the antennas to look more natural and not for both of them to move
at the same time because the first antenna is affected by the wind sooner than the other one.
I can move these keyframes back a little bit.
After that, let's work on animating the ice.
To animate the eyes.
I open the scale.
I create a key frame for it.
Two frames ahead and I disable this chain icon so I can only change its y value.
And I said it to.
And I said it's X to 120, so it looks wider.
Again, three frames forwards.
I copy and paste this keyframe because I want its eye to be closed if it's right here.
And again, two frames ahead, I copy and paste the initial keyframe, so it's like it's opened.
I move the keyframes here, so the animation of the blinking occurs later.
And for the animation of the other, I just copy these keyframes and select this layer, then open scale.
I have to move the indicator to where the first keyframe is.
Isolate the scale and hit control V.
Now if I play.
You can see that both eyes blink together.
And to make it blink several times I could where I wanted to blink and by using the clone option and
selecting the keyframes.
I copy and paste the blinking animation to wherever I want.
Let's see how it turns out.
I want to trim the worker.
You are here for that.
I hate MN so it would get trimmed and after effects only renders this area.
And to loop the animation and make the starts and end of the animation invisible.
I just have to set the end of the work area where the bee goes down because it is down in the beginning.
Let's take another look.
It looks great.
Now let's work on animating in the shadow.
For that I open the scale.
Isolate the body and hits you so I can see it's keyframes.
And according to these keyframes, I animate the shadow layer.
To do that, I create a keyframe for its scale.
I come here with the B goes up.
The shadow should be smaller.
So I set it to 80 and here it returns to its original size.
I make the keyframes easy and I copy and paste a look expression for it to.
Let's check it out.
See, as the beam moves up and down, the shadow gets small and big to.
And to show the movement and speed of the B better.
I can draw a couple of lines.
Enabling stroke.
I open its position and create a keyframe for it here.
I move it there.
I want its anchor point to be in the center of the layer four that I can use the motion to script,
isolate the layer and click on this option.
Ten frames forward.
Isolate the layer and hold shift so it moves straight.
And I move the layer over here.
I enable motion blur for it so it moves more naturally.
I duplicate this layer.
I hit you.
And I want the other layer to go up a little bit for that.
If I do it in the very beginning, you can see that the path gets crooked.
So for the whole animation to be changed, I must put the indicator on one of these keyframes, then
select both of the keyframes and then move the layer above.
I move this back a little bit so it won't be visible in the beginning.
I shorten this a little bit and delay animation is slightly.
Look for these lines to pass constantly.
I love these layers as well.
When I do that, they pass pretty fast to make it slower.
For example, ten frames after the second keyframe, I copy and paste the second frame.
And also for this layer.
Now they pass with a little bit of delay.
For this layer not to be on the B, I move it below everything else.
And they often it's an events so they won't seem repetitive.
I also make the lines thin a bit so they look more natural.
Look, it looks good to me.
The animation is done in the next part.
You will learn how I can render and export this animation.