After I'm done with the animation to render it, I have to go to the composition menu and choose the
add to render queue option.
After the render cue panel showed up here from the output module, I click here.
Here you can choose the format of your clip.
I choose Edge 264 in previous versions of After Effects.
This option doesn't exist and you had to choose QuickTime and export your clip as a move file.
However, in newer versions, the H 264 is available and you can easily export your animation as an
MP for file.
Here you can choose your clip channel to be either RGV or Alpha.
Alpha makes it black and white.
When you choose H 264, you don't have to change any settings.
If you wanted to change the dimensions of your output, you can do that here.
You can change the height and width here and here you can crop your output file.
But now I don't need this.
If you ever want to do that, it's better to do these things in your composition.
These options are mostly for light weighted previews of your work, but in general you'd better use
the settings of the composition I hit.
Okay.
I click on this option so I can choose where I want my render to be saved.
After I named my final file, I hit save.
And then here I click on render.
Well, after rendering is done, you can click on this arrow and this address so it would show you where
your file is saved.
I right click on it.
I go to its properties.
As you can see, the size of the final render is 350 kilo points, which is pretty good.
In the next lesson, you will get to know how to work with graphs and graph.
I'll see you there.