In this lesson, we want to talk about graphs and graph editor window.
Generally, we have two kinds of graphs, value graph and speed graph.
Well, as you see, I've created a simple animation for the position of this layer to enter graph editor
I just have to select these keyframes and activated this option, as soon as I activate this option,
you see some graphs shown here.
Each of these is related to one dimension.
The red graph is for the x position and the green one is for the y position of the layer.
As you see here, the changes in value will be shown in the vertical axis and changes in time on the
horizontal axis.
For example, if I keep my pointer on the second key frame of the Y position, you see its value is
861 pixels and its time is one second ten.
But if I bring it here, you see its value is 308 pixels and its time is on zero.
The next thing to know is how to find out if these graphs are value graphs or speed graphs.
For this, all I need to do is left click on this option.
And here, as you see, the 'edit value graph' is enabled.
So I get that these graphs are for the value of the layer.
Now I enable the 'edit value graph' option and as you can see, the graph is changed; 2 graphs became
one graph, and that's because the speed of the animation is not in two kinds and we have only one speed.
As you see in the vertical axis, the speed value is shown and on the horizontal axis the time.
And if I bring my pointer here, you see the speed of this keyframe in frame ten is 3318 pixels per second.
Well, I go back to the value graph so I can give more description of it, and then I will go for the speed graph.
You have to pay attention.
edit in the value graph is only possible if you have created animation for the uniaxial property such
as opacity and rotation.
But if you animate position and scale that are biaxial properties; by default you cannot edit your graphs.
And to edit this graphs you have to separate your property.
To do this, I right click on the property and select separate dimensions.
After that you see that the X and Y position are separated.
And by using the pen tool, you can edit your graph; to edit the keyframe.
I hold on Ctrl and select the keyframe.
As you see, a handle is appeared for the keyframe, and by using this handle you can change the y position
of your layer.
And as you see these dots change as I make changes here.
I hold Alt and click on it so that the handle appears.
And to create a new keyframe, it just needs to left click with the pen tool on the graph line that you want.
And for four appear in the keyframe handles.
I hold down alt and click.
Well, as you see, the bouncing ball animation is a little bit fast.
To slow it down, I need to select keyframes, enable this option so a box like this appears.
And by using this box I can decrease the speed of the animation.
Let's see how it became.
A lot better.
Well, if I want to animate the X position of the Layer too, I need to put the X position here
as I change the X position.
You see, the vertical value chart changes.
I select two values, bring X key frame to the end so that the X and Y positions stop together.
Here. I hold on shift and bring it higher so the ball moves more to the right.
Let's see how it is.
Okay, it's good animation, but if I want more control over my animation, like if I want it to have
a low speed at the beginning and high speed as it hits the ground and when it's in these peaks,
have a low speed and have a floating effect
I have to go to the speed graph and use this graph to have more control over the speed of the animation.
Well, I have created a new animation for this layer.
I have created three keyframes.
The first keyframe is here.
The second keyframe is at the highest point, and the third one is down here.
Let's go to the graph editor.
And if I want to make the ball a little bit floating when it's here and have a lower speed
for this, we cannot use the value graph and I have to go to the speed graph.
Let me separate the property.
For this I use this option this time and disable this for now.
As you see, if I create a graph like this for the Y position, the animation completely falls apart.
And that's because the value graph, unlike the speed graph, affects the animation path directly.
I go back to the first state and enter the speed graph.
I want the speed of the ball to decrease around here, let me play it and see the animation.
As you see, it's completely linear and it's not natural.
Okay, I select the middle keyframe and make it easy so that the animation speed falls down to zero here.
As you see, the speed is zero Here
it is 2662 here and here is 2800.
I play it again to see how it goes.
Let me trim the work area here.
As you see, a little pause is created here.
It happens because as you see, the speed graph is zero here, but it shouldn't be like this.
I want the speed to decrease around here, not to fall completely to zero and stop.
For this I bring the key frame up to prevent it from splitting into two points.
I right click on the key frame, then select keyframe velocity and enable continuous.
Then I hold down shift and bring it up so the animation speed doesn't go to zero here and the ball doesn't pause.
It got better to lower speed here.
I increase the length of these handles.
As you see, it's better now, to notice this better i select keyframes and increase distance between
them to decrease the animation speed.
To increase speed here.
I set this handle like this and here the same.
I increase the speed a little.
It got better a lot.
It's good to create the bounce return animation.
I hold down Alt key so that both handles change together, i select keyframes and go to the speed graph.
I trim the work area here.
To fit the window to the graphs.
I just need to click here so that the graphs fill the window completely.
Next important point is that sometimes when you increase these handles manually, it is possible that
the speed increases on this side more than another side, to make sure your animation speed is the same.
Or in other words, the size of the handles is the same.
You just have to double click on the key frame or right click and enter keyframe velocity and in incoming velocity.
You see the influence is on 91 and an outgoing velocity influence is on 96.
So the animation speed in these two parts is different.
Well, to make them the same, you can enter two equal values.
You see now your handles have the same length.
You can do the same here.
Double click on the key frame.
And enter the value you want.
So the handles have the same size.
Also, if I right click on this key frame and go to the key frame velocity, you see influence is on zero.
While if I right click here and go to the key frame velocity.
You see, the influence is not on zero and the speed is different on the two sides.
So I change it to zero and press OK
Now, if we look at the animation, we see the ball speed when going and coming back is the completely same.
To completely master the grapg editor window and work better with keyframes.
You need to know about these options too, the first option, as it's obvious from its icon, is for appearing
graphs of properties I have selected.
For example, I go to the value graph.
The first option is for appearing graphs of properties I have selected.
If I select this, you see the graphs disappear, and when I select the property they appear again.
And if I separate them, you see each of the graphs is shown separately.
The second option shows the animated properties of a layer and the next part.
The first option shows kinds of graphs automatically.
This means for the position, it shows the speed graph and for other properties
Value graph.
This option shows the value graph and this one speed graph.
And this option shows both graphs.
These options are obvious from their name.
It is for showing waveforms of the sound layers.
This is for showing the beginning and end of the layers.
For example, if the layer ends here; in here you can see the end of the layer.
It shows this.
This option shows the description of any keyframe you bring your pointer on it.
This option is to show your keyframes in a box when you select them so you can change the animation
speed easily.
With this one, you can synchronize the selected keyframe with the value or time of another key frame
and snap it.
This option is for auto zoom.
This option is for showing your graph completely in this panel.
This option is for showing the selected keyframe individually so you can work on it easily.
The next option is for separating dimensions, which I have already explained.
The next option shows the same option when you right click on a key frame.
The next option is for turning a key frame to toggle hold.
The next one is for linear.
The next one is for linear continuous.
For example, i select this key frame and enter key frame velocity, disable continuous.
Now, by selecting these two points of the key frame and selecting this option, make the key frame a linear Continuous.
These options are obviously to turn keyframes to "easy ease" "easy ease in" and "easy ease out".
Well, it's enough for now.
In the next lesson, we will start creating a simple animation to put into practice what we have learned so far.
Good luck.