Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, I want to create a simple animation so you get familiar with previous content practically.
I have opened after Fix and I want to create a new project.
So I click on new project after the new project is created.
For getting started, I have to create a new composition.
I set my composition size at 1920 by 1080 and its frame rate at 25.
Let the resolution be on full and I set the duration to 10 seconds and choose gray for the background color.
I name it Click.
Well, now I want to import the designs into after effects.
To do so, I double click on the project panel and import the intended file.
After this, as I said before, I want the layers to be imported as a composition.
So I choose composition and I set the footage dimensions on layer size so I can easily select the layers in the preview.
I open click comp and I want to create a simple clicking animation; for transferring the layers to the
comp that I have created.
I choose layers and press Ctrl+X and here I press Ctrl+V.
Before I start animating, let me delete "Yes" and "No" layers.
I don't want this layer, so I put it here for now.
I want to create two buttons for Yes and No.
For this I use the rounded rectangle tool and here I make a button like this.
I enable its fill, change its stroke color same as this text color.
And set it's fill on the gradient.
And change its color to the same as this one.
And set it's handles like this.
I increase its size a little bit and bring it here.
I set the stroke on 5, so it gets the size as other lines.
to center the anchor point of this layer.
we just select the layer.
Hold down Ctrl and double click on the 'pan behind' tool.
To make a duplicate of this layer and put it here.
I need to select the layer and press Ctrl+D.
I hold down, shift and drag the layer to this side so it only moves on the x axis.
I delete this layer.
After that, I want to create a Yes text here and a No here.
I go for the text tool and write a yes here.
I go to the character panel, change its color to this text color, and as the text layer is selected,
I go to the paragraph panel and select the center text so that the anchor point transferred to the center of the layer.
Again, I go back to the character panel and decrease the size.
I put it on 80, i select the layer, press Ctrl+D to make a duplicate of this layer and bring it here
and write No.
I think it's better to reduce these text mass
Let's go for animating.
First, i select the pointer.
And to put its anchor point here, I use the pan behind tool and bring it here.
In the beginning, I put it out of the scene.
I select the mouse layer, open its position and create a keyframe for it.
I go to second 1; to make the second keyframe
I bring the pointer on the Yes button.
And to put the pointer on the button, I put it on top of the layers.
I want it to stay here for 20 frames
for this I hold down shift and press "page down" twice, so I go 20 frames forward.
Then I want to copy and paste this keyframe here.
So I select this key frame and press Ctrl+C then Ctrl+V to copy and paste the key frame here.
And if you watch the animation, we see the pointer move and stop on the yes button.
And in this time span, the pointer doesn't have any movement.
I go to second 3 and drag it out of the scene.
OK, After the pointer got here, I want it to click on this button.
For this.
I put the indicator here, select the mouse layer and press Shift+S so the scale property of the mouse appears too.
I create a key frame here for scale; 3 frames forward and set the scale on 80.
Again, 5 frames forward and set it on 100.
Let's see how it looks.
Okay, it is good For now.
Let's animate the yes button, i select the yes button, open its scale and create a keyframe for it.
Then I go to the frame where my printer shrinks and reduce button size too.
I put it on 90.
And again here on 100.
I just bring this keyframe 2 frames forward so it gets a different animation than the pointer animation.
Let's see how it is.
It's good for now.
Well, let's move on to shrinking the Yes layer
to minify the Yes layer.
I don't need to create keyframes for this scale of this layer.
I just have to parent the layer with the pick whip tool to the button layer so that the yes layer obeys the button layer in all transform properties.
Let's have a look and see how it is now.
As you see, the Yes layer is also magnifying.
I select the bottom layer; press U key so only keyframes are visible and values without keyframes get hidden.
After that, I have to adjust the speed of the animation.
I want the pointer to have a high speed at the beginning and slow down as it approaches the Yes button.
For this, i select this key frame and make it easy ease.
I go to the graph editor to slow it down even more.
I drag this handle and reduce its speed when it approaches the Yes button.
Let's see.
And I do the opposite here.
I want it to be slow at the beginning and at the end have a higher speed.
So i select this key frame and make it easy.
I go to the graph editor and decrease its speed here.
Let's see how it is.
It's good; also to improve the scale keyframes.
I select them and make them easy.
Let's have another look and see how it is.
The speed of the pointer exiting is low a bit.
That's why I bring this keyframe here so it goes faster.
Again.
Let's see how it looks.
Much better.
The animation is good, but this linear movement doesn't look that interesting; to improve this linear movement.
All I need to do is select the mouse layer.
Select the pen tool.
Then click and drag from this point.
As I do this, a handle is created here and by that you can control the path of the pointer movement.
I set it like this.
And at the end Like this.
As you see now, the path of the pointer has a curve and lost its linear bad movement.
The next thing to do is to change the color of the yes and no buttons when the pointer goes over them.
To do that, I go to the frame where the mouse has not yet been placed on the button, which is this frame.
I select the No button and go to the effects Control
from the Effects and Presets panel.
I add the Tint effect to it.
And said its amount to 50.
I create a keyframe for amount, select layer 2 and press U so the keyframe can be visible in the timeline
in the next frame that the pointer goes on the No button.
I set this on zero so that the Tint effect gets ineffective.
I go forward, here that the pointer exits the no button area.
Again, the No button must return to the previous state.
So I go back to the previous frame.
Copy this keyframe.
Then in the next frame I copy the initial Tint keyframe here; so that it goes back to this state.
I must do the same for the Yes button.
To do this easier, I just need to copy these keyframes.
And in the frame where the pointer has not yet gotten to the yes area.
Meaning, Exactly here
i select the layer and press Ctrl+V
As you see, the keyframes are placed here.
I press U key to see the keyframes.
To prevent the Yes button color change early to its original color.
I select these key frames and take them far away.
After the pointer clicks and leaves the bottom area.
I put the keyframes here.
Let's have a look at the animation and see how it is.
As you can see, when the pointer goes on the buttons, it changes color and clicks and it goes out of the scene.
Well, it's good.
Good luck.