Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, I want to talk about interpolation.
Interpolation is the process of creating intermediate frames between two key frames so that you don't
need to adjust the layer frame by frame.
And as you create an animation with two key frames, interpolation comes in and creates movement between
these two key frames.
These in between key frames once were created by traditional methods and manually, but now interpolation
does this automatically.
For example, I created a keyframe for this layer here and another one here, and interpolation calculates
key frames for the frames between these two key frames and moves the layer like this.
Well, what is the benefit of interpolation when you create two key frames for your animation, like
these two key frames, sometimes you need to adjust the values more accurately or edit your animation
path.
Precisely.
Interpolation helps you a lot.
Overall, we have two interpolations in after effects, one temporal interpolation and two a spatial
interpolation to enter the interpolation section of the key frames.
I just have to select the keyframe.
I want to change this interpolation right, click on it and click on Keyframe interpolation and enter
it.
As you see here, we have two kinds of interpolations temporal interpolation and a spatial interpolation.
Temporal interpolation, as it's written here effects the property have keyframe over time.
Most usage of this interpolation is for unique axial properties like rotation, opacity or separated
position.
But the spatial interpolation as it's written here, affects the path of the layers, and obviously
a path exists when the position exists.
So a spatial interpolation is more about layers, position and effects layers path.
First we start with a spatial interpolation, so we understand these options easier, and after that
we go to the temporal interpolation.
Well, the example I created here is four balls with the same animation speed.
They move together, they go up and down together.
But the only difference is these layers path or their interpolation.
Isolate the first layer, select the middle keyframe, and I go to the keyframe interpolation.
As you see, a spatial interpolation of this layer is linear and the movement path of this layer is
linear.
If you look at the second layer, the moving path of this layer is like this.
And if I select the second keyframe and enter keyframe interpolation, you see that the spatial interpolation
is on busier.
Until now, you have noticed the difference between linear and busier.
The linear sets the animation path in a linear manner and creates no handle for that key frame in the
path.
But busier curves the animation path in the intended key frame and creates two handles.
So we get to edit the animation path in any way we want.
The next step of a spatial interpolation.
As I have written, it is continuous busier.
This like the busier option as you see here, that the key frame is continuous busier, the animation
path is curved and two handles have been created for this key frame just like the last one.
But the difference between these two interpolation is that you cannot change one of them separately
in the continuous busier, and by changing the right handle, the left one changes with it.
And you don't have the same controls here as you have in busier, which is a feature in itself, or
when you don't want your animation paths to be broken.
The last type of a spatial interpolation is also busier.
This type of interpolation is almost the same as busier.
But here, if you change your animation path direction, you see the handles change according to the
angle of your animation path to keep their curve.
Let me change this one.
You see that what happened there is not like what is happening here.
The same is here as a change.
This there is no effect on the past is before the keyframe.
But in order busier when the path changes according to the curve, the key frame handles also change.
As I try to change the handles, it changes to continuous busier.
And now if you change this, you see it is not as it was before.
Now that we got familiar with this spatial interpolation, let's go for temporal interpolation.
To do so, isolate this keyframe of this layer.
Go to the graph editor in the value graph.
Right click on the keyframe and go to the keyframe interpolation.
Temporal interpolation.
As I said before, this interpolation is usually applied for uni axial values.
To do so, I separate the position of this layer so its handles up here, isolate the middle keyframe,
enter keyframe interpolation and from temporal interpolation I click on linear you see as a selected
linear.
The value graph of the animation is set on linear and it is obvious here.
If I change this key frame, you will see that it is completely linear.
I go to the second option.
Busier.
Busier acts exactly like this option.
But the difference is that the spatial interpolation effects the animation path, but here it affects
the value graph.
I change the handle.
You see, I can edit each of them separately.
Again isolate the key frame and turkey frame interpolation and choose continuous busier.
Continuous busier, as I said, here is for changing the handles together and making sure no breaks
happen in the graph.
I go to the next option a little bit easier.
As I said before, it is for when I change the graph.
The handles change according to the curve of the graph.
You see, when I drag it up in here, it sits lower and also we see its effect after the keyframe.
You see, when I drag it down, this side goes higher.
And when I bring it higher, this goes down.
The last option is hold, which is toggle hold.
That allows me to make my keyframe goes into all manner.
I also made this keyframe toggle hold.
As you can see, when I use toggle hold, the value of the key frame I put on toggle hold is applied
until the next keyframe.
It stays in place until here, and in the next keyframe it transfers to the next keyframe location.
If I want the same thing to happen here, I have to put these two keyframes on hold.
Option.
Well, in this lesson we learned about the concept of interpolation and its different kinds in aftereffects
and their effects on the path and value of the animation.
In the next chapter, I start creating basic animations that are essential for any animator to know
so you can create a tractive motion graphics.