Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, I want to talk about creating a work cycle animation for my character.
As you recall, I created this animation with the work cycle tool automatically, but in this lesson
I want to create work in animation manually.
First, let me hide the layers.
I don't need to make the scene uncrowded.
Isolate all the layers and shy them.
And only on the character controllers.
And enable the shy option.
The next thing to do is delete the all white cycle animation I made with the watch cycle tool.
To do this, isolate the work cycle layer and delete it.
As you can see, a warning appears for the expressions.
To delete the locks.
I can completely I need to click on this magnifier and delete expressions for the properties it shows.
After deleting expressions of properties related to the work cycle tool, you'll see that the yellow
warning goes away and you can know that all the settings for the work cycle tool are deleted.
If I move the indicator in the timeline, you see nothing happens.
Before I start animating the point, you should know which you got familiar with in the animation principles
lesson.
I have two methods for animating.
The first method is straight ahead or frame by frame.
In this method, character pose is designed frame by frame, and animation is formed little by little.
But in the second method, which is supposed to pose, firstly, the key poses of the character are
created.
Then in between imposes and finally the animation is formed.
And because after fixed automatically creates movements between two key frames, it's better to use
the second method post to post the create post to pause animation, I need references.
So I have downloaded a reference and as you see different poses of walking or drawn here.
And the frame number related to each pose is specified.
Okay, I bring this.
Bring it higher than the background so I can see.
And place it here.
As it's shown here, the work cycle happens in 25 frames and as you see, the frame rate is also on
25 frames.
So one second is 25 frames.
So I term the work area here and start creating different poses for walking.
The first pose I have here is contact.
So I create a marker here and name it contact.
The next contact pose is on frame 13, so I go on and create another marker.
And also another one in frame 25.
Now I go for creating the first contact post.
As you see in the first contact, links are completely apart from each other and the character's body
gets lower than the straight from the characters standing because the legs are separated and obviously
body gets lower.
To do that, I open the position and rotation of the body and legs.
Create keyframes for them.
I don't need other layers for now.
So I shy.
And also I don't need hands to.
So I shake the hand layers.
And to make both legs recognizable from each other, I add a little effect to the back leg.
And darken it.
I enable the shy option and start creating the first post.
I bring down the character's body to bend the legs almost in this position, right leg forward.
And look behind.
As you see, when I drag the leg, too much joints get separated.
To prevent this, I go to a fixed control panel of this controller and in the IK section and in this
stretch I disable all those stretch.
I do the same for this controller.
This flick comes for an illegal and this one illegal forward.
I bring body a little lower.
I speak for the ground with a ruler.
And also set the ruler on the character's head.
So like the reference, I know where the character's head is supposed to be.
The frontal claws need to be upward, as I see in the reference.
So I said it's rotation on -20, and the body, as it's shown in the reference, is bends a little forward.
So I say on five.
Now let's go for creating the last contact.
The last contact must be exactly like the first one, as it's shown in the reference, because I want
to create a working cycle.
The beginning and end of the animation must be the same.
To do that, I have to copy and paste these keyframes here.
I select them all.
Go to the basil and in the animation panel I copy and paste them here.
Well, I go for the second contact post.
In this post, the legs need to be exactly opposite of the first contact, so I bring the front leg
to the back and set its rotation to zero.
And bring the back leg to the front and set its rotation to -20.
And create these keyframes here again.
After creating contact poses, I go for the inbetween poses, the in-between poses of two contacts or
passing poses.
So I go to frame seven.
Create a marker and write pass.
The next passing pose is on 19.
So I create another marker here.
In the first passing.
As you see, the leg is under the body a little behind.
So I said the rotation of the right leg to zero.
Bring it back and bring the body higher so the leg straightens completely.
The other leg has an approximate angle of 100 degrees like this.
And food rotation should be like this.
I go to the next person.
And the left leg needs to be straight.
So I said, it's rotation on zero.
Bring it back.
The A right leg should be placed like this.
And I placed body frames here.
I bring the leg more to the back.
Until now, the character walking is almost complete.
You have to pay attention when you create poses.
The movement path of the controller should be something like this.
Rotation of the body in passing poses needs to reduce.
So here I said it on three.
And here I set it on three.
Let's see how it looks.
After creating these poses, I create up and down poses.
The downpours is between the contact and the passing poses and the pose is between passing and contact
poses.
So I go to Frames four and 16 and create a down poses marker.
On frame ten and 22 is the poses.
Here.
The body comes down.
Set rotation of the front leg is to zero.
And in the outpost, the body comes higher.
As you see, the body is almost upon the toes.
I bring it a bit higher.
I also paste the keyframe here.
Also for the second down.
I copy the first down keyframe.
And zero the rotation of this slate.
Let's have a look and see how it is.
Legs moving is almost complete.
Let's go to animate the head.
I open the head controller.
Create a keyframe for its rotation, and when it reaches passing, the head goes upward a little.
I saved on minus five.
In the contact poses, I say on three.
And in second person on five.
And ease them.
And if I want to make the animation continuous until second segment so I can add background and other
stuff, I look at the properties, I create the keyframes for them.
Well, I copy this expression and paste it for other properties.
To make the head animation clearly isolate key frames related to the contact poses.
Set them on seven and set the key frames related to the passing pose and minus.
Isolate keyframes and bring them back to have overlapped animation.
It's good.
Let's go to animate the hands.
I appear to handle layers.
Layers?
Because I have used the work cycles all before.
The hand controllers aren't on IK modes and they are on f k mode.
Now if I move the hand controller you'll see that the hand won't be changed because I'm on f k mode.
If I enable IK, you can see now I can control the hand, but it's better to use it k mode in working
animation.
So I disable like as it was before and start animating the hands.
And if game mode to animate the hand, I should go to the section and in individual control I can animate
the hand by these options.
First, I create a keyframe for these three properties.
I do the same for the left hand press you to see the keyframes.
And here, because the right leg is ahead, the left hand must be back.
I set it completely straight and I rotate the rest as much as possible.
And I do the same for the left hand.
Because the left leg is back.
The left hand must be forward.
I can bend this a little.
And I would say that this way.
I copy these keyframes and paste them for the last contact.
I go to the basil copy and paste, and for the middle contact I do the opposite.
First I in this.
Rotate this one back.
And bring it here.
Then I easy's these cue frames and look them.
I copy the expression and paste it here.
To make the overlap animation for the hand parts and make them more realistic.
I set the keyframes like this.
Let's see how it looks.
As you see, the hand movement is much better now.
Well, I don't need the reference anymore.
I hide it.
I appear the other layers.
I add the gradient rap effect to the background and adjust it like this.
I hide controllers and watch the animation to see how it looks.
This cloud should place behind the trees.
And I create a simple animation for the scale of the song.
And I look at.
And also I create an animation for the position of this cloud.
And change the cloud to it.
And I also have to edit this shadow animation.
Yeah, it's good in first contact and passing.
But here.
It should be here.
And its mode must be set on cycle to be in harmony with the work in animation.
Well, the work cycle animation has finished, and the next lesson I will deal with wrong cycle animation.
Good luck.