Hello, everyone.
In this video, I want to talk about the three main and important principles of creating cycle animation
that usually are inside of the bubble so that you won't be needing to use them, for instance, while
creating such animations all the time.
Firstly, you have to animate the body and move it up and down.
If I want to show you more precisely, it has such a movement path.
Secondly, the movement path of the foot controller should be like this.
And finally, to have a real and overlapping movement for the hands, you have to use f k instead of
k.
So let's see how to do this practically.
The first thing you should know is that they've already reached the character using the expression two.
It's also good to mention that I've set the frame rate of the count to 24 frames so that the whole lifecycle
animation will happen within 24 frames or just one second.
As you can see, I've specified the work cycle process by markers.
Every pose is three frames apart from the next pulse.
The first principle about work cycle animation that you need to know is the body of the character has
an up and down movement.
So for creating such movement, I hide the controllers that I don't need.
Then I open the position of the body and then I separate it in the pose.
I move the body up a little.
Then I create a keyframe for the y position of the body.
In the down pose.
I lower it down.
I make these key frames eases and for the next down and opposes, I duplicate these key frames.
And in order to create keyframes for the contact poses, I go to the second content and create a keyframe
for the oil position and put it for the first and last contact poses.
And I make them linear so there wouldn't be any pause for the beginning and end of the animation.
The body should be like this.
Let me hide the arms and like layers.
As you can see, the body should move like this.
The next thing that you need to pay attention to is that when the body is in the contact pose, it would
slightly move forward in the past, impose it back to its initial position.
And I duplicate these two key frames for the next passing and contact poses.
Then I made them easy.
Ease.
The movement path of the body should be like this.
Now let's move on to body rotation.
The body rotates forward when it reaches the contact post.
So I set it to two and create a keyframe for it.
In the passing post.
It should be zero.
Then I make the keyframes easy.
Ease.
And in order to create an overlap in action, I moved the rotation key frames backward.
Then I look at.
I looked at other ones as well.
After animating the body, it's time for the second principle or making the movement path of the legs.
For doing so, I unhide the right leg of the character.
As you can see, the movement path of the leg controllers should be like this.
For doing so, I open the position of this controller.
And the first contact post should look like this.
In the second contact pause, the leg moves backward.
And in the last contact post, I duplicate the first key frames here.
In this second passing post, the leg moves up.
Basically, I just made a triangular path like this for the controller of the leg, and I made the path
curved.
In the downpours.
The rotation of the lake should be zero.
It should be like this here.
After that, I made the keyframes of the contact process eases.
I copy these keyframes and paste them for the position and rotation of the left leg controller.
Then I move the keyframes back.
So the last keyframes would be for the second contact post.
In the outpost.
The body is slightly upward than it should be.
So I just select the outpost keyframes and move the body down a little bit.
Okay.
After animating the legs, it's time for the third principle, or using f k for animating the arms,
not k for doing so.
Isolate the controller of the right arm and disable the IP option so now I can animate it using f k
in the f k section.
Individual control.
I create keyframes for the upper lower and go in the first contact where the right leg is a hit.
The right arm should place behind and in the next contact where the right leg is behind the right arm
should be forward.
I make the keyframes easy.
Ease.
Then I looked them.
And in order to create an overlap in action, I move them like this and place the last contact keyframes
for the first one.
I copy these same keyframes and paste them for the right hand as well.
They should be like this.
This should be exactly the opposite of the right hand.
Okay.
After that, we can also animate the head.
For doing so in the contact poses where the character lands on his front leg, the head rotates a little
bit down.
I set it to five and in the passing post it should be zero.
Then I make the keyframes eases, and for overlapping action, I move them back and loop them all.
Now that I'm finished animating the character, it's time for animating the background.
To do.
So I create keyframes for the position of this shape.
It should be here at the beginning of the timeline.
And after a couple of frames, I wanted to be here.
I animate this line to.
I make this line look like this so it would look like it's in perspective.
Let's see how it turned out.
In the 6 seconds.
I moved the last keyframes right here to increase the number of fences.
I use the effects.
Let's see how it looks.
I move the second keyframes at the beginning of the timeline, and in the second six I increase the
number.
After that, let's work on animating the three.
First, I create a keyframe for its position since the tree is located in the back.
Speed should be relatively slower.
I go to the second eight.
I create a keyframe for it.
For the first keyframe.
I move the tree out of the scene and for the second keyframe, I move it right here.
Let's see how it looks.
In the second six, I duplicated the three layer.
I put the ruler here.
So the location of the tree is obvious at the end of the animation.
I go to the beginning of the timeline and move the second tree right here so the loop would work correctly.
And once this tree goes out of the scene, I trim the layer.
Now let's animate this song.
Let's see how it turned out.
Let me make a shadow for the character as well.
As you can see, the lob works perfectly and there is no problem while repeating.
Good luck.