Hello, everyone.
And this.
Listen, I want to create a run cycle animation for the character.
You may think running is the same as working with more speed, but in fact, it's not the case.
Because if you take a look at the running poses, you see that one of the main poses of running the
legs are in the air and there is no contact with the ground while in walking.
The character's leg is always touching the ground and in no pose, the character is separated from the
ground to create their own cycle.
I open the Work cycle project.
First I have to delete the controller's keyframe and then start animating again.
This expression morning is for values.
I have looked them.
To remove this warning, I just need to disable these expressions.
Well, I hide the layers.
I don't need to lighten the scene and animate the character easier.
I put the character in a straight form to create poses more precise.
It's good.
As you remember, to create a work cycle, I needed 25 frames, which means one second.
But because the wrong cycle is faster, I use 16 frames to create a.
I trim the worker here, delete the markers I don't need.
And only keep up and down poses.
Well, I opened the reference and as you see, running poses are similar to walking.
It starts from the contact post in which the right leg is in front.
In the second contact, the left leg is in front and in the middle.
The passing pose is located between the contact and pass poses is the down pose and between the pass
and contact is the opposite.
Here, I don't need to start from contact poses as I did before.
Then passing pose and then up and down poses.
So I start with up and down poses because I can edit the controllers movement path using motion path
and I don't need to create all the poses.
Let's get to work and see what they mean.
I put the outpost for the first pose, so the last pose is going to be the pose as well.
The middle of these two poses, which is frame edge should be the opposed to.
Between two opposes.
The down should be placed.
In this post, the character's body goes a little higher almost here.
And as you see, this is the outpost.
The right leg forms like this and the left one like this.
And the distance from the ground is almost the same.
So I select the right click, bring it back.
Its rotation is like this and bring the front leg forward.
An ankle rotation is like this.
I put a ruler to bring both legs to the same height.
The first post of the OP is created, I create keyframes for the position and rotation of the layers.
Here, the body must be rotated forward.
So I put it on ten.
I go to the last post and have to paste these keyframes here.
To do so, I go to the puzzle in the animation section, copy the keyframes, and then click on the
paste button.
I go to the middle of post and reverse the legs.
The next post to create is the downpours.
As it's shown here, the character's body is at its lowest.
Let's take this form the back leg in the oppo stakes.
A support role for the body in the down pose.
So in the outpost, this is the back leg and must take a support role.
So I bring it down and also the body comes down almost in this position.
I zero the rotation and bring the leg lower.
Bring the body a little more down.
The other leg takes this position.
And in rotation like this.
Also the rotation of the body should increase.
I put it on 20.
I go on the next town post and create a reverse of this position for the links.
I copy and paste body control keyframes for the first down post here.
I zero this rotation and put it on the ground.
This other leg should be like this.
Let's have a look, see how it is.
The running animation has been created, but it's not attractive.
That's because I need to adjust the controllers path.
To do that, isolate the pencil and create such a path for the controller.
After in the pads, you see that the leg movements are better.
After that, I go for the easing of the keyframes.
First isolate body keyframes.
Easy, easy for them.
Go to the graph editor and where the character comes down on the ground.
Like here, the speed needs to be increased and where the character is in its opposition, the speed
needs to be decreased.
So I decrease the speed in these poses.
Let's see how it looks.
To increase the speed of these keyframes.
I select them and I go through each vessel in animation and increase their speed by this slider a little.
I put it on 70.
Let's see how it looks.
After the same speed I created for the body position keyframes I need to create for the controllers
and body rotation to.
Okay to do so, I select keyframes.
Easy.
Then select keyframes related to the post.
And set them on 70.
Well, let's have a look and see how it is.
As you see, it's much better.
I can also increase animation speed in the poses to improve it.
Much better.
Now I go to animate the hands.
I make the hand layers visible.
To animate the hands in the wrong cycle.
I need to use FCW so I create a keyframe for the upper lower and goal for the right hand controller
and do the same for the left hand.
I select controllers press you to see the keyframes here, where the right leg is in the back.
The right hand should be in front of here.
And the left hand should be behind first.
I just left hand.
And then turn it backwards.
I placed these keyframes on the last post.
In the middle oppose and should be reversed.
Isolate these keyframes and ease them.
Let's see how it is.
For the hand parts to have overlap animation isolate these key frames and bring them to frames forward.
Let's go for animating the head.
I make the head controller visible.
Here I create a key frame in the Opposed.
It should turn backward.
I put it on minus seven.
And in the downpours in the forward interaction.
Seven I think it's better to increase it here a little.
Here again, I paste the post keyframe.
Here, though.
And again here up then I easy's the key frames.
And bring keyframes to frames forward to have overlap animation.
After doing this, I can enable loop expression to see the character animation with the background.
I increase the work area and hide the controllers to see how is the animation?
The animation is good.
I make the scene layers visible.
Let's see.
How is the work?
I can increase the background speed a bit.
Isolate the null object.
Press edgewise to open its expression and 700 free speed to increase.
To make the background continuous.
I can select this layer first control DX and bring it here.
Same for this one.
It's good.
I can also increase the speed on seven.
I do the same for these two lives later.
And at the end I can also harmonize the character animation and its shadow.
Well here.
This key frame should be placed and then down this keyframe.
Here.
The shadow needs to be small and in the downpours it should be bigger.
And here it should be a small.
And the speed of the opposed keyframes of the shadow needs to be on 70 to move with the character.
Okay.
It's good.
If you wanted to get familiar with the script completely and know all of the uses of options and the
way of working with them in reading and animating the character, I recommend you to watch Derek and
animate the character in due course.
Because there I had explained all of the tools and options and the usage of them completely, and it
can be so useful for those who want to follow the characters, drink and animate professionally.
Good luck.