Hello, everyone.
In this video, I want to talk about how you can create a simple run cycle animation for your character.
The run cycle is relatively faster than the work cycle, so I'm going to create the run cycle animation
in 16 frames just like before.
Here I'm going to apply the same three principles that I worked on for the work cycle.
However, in the run cycle, the up and down movement of the body is much more than before.
And also it's faster.
What's more, the movement path of the food controller is different.
Without any further ado, let's start.
Initially, I work on animating the body, isolate its controller and open its position.
Then I separate it.
And I saw animals in the Y position in the down pose.
The body moves lower.
I create a key frame for it in the outpost.
It moves up and I make these two key frames eases.
And for the next up and down poses, I duplicate them.
And to create a keyframe for the contact post, I go to the second contact post and create a keyframe
and put it for the first and last contact poses.
As you can see, the body should move like this.
Now it's time to animate in the x position.
In the passing pose, I create a keyframe for it and in the contact post, the body should move a little
forward.
Then I copy the keyframes and paste them right here.
Then I make them easy.
All right.
Now it's time to work on the rotation.
In the passing post, I create a key frame for it and set it to nine.
In the context post.
I set it to 14, then I make them easy, easy and duplicate them for the next passing and contact poses.
And to create overlapping movements.
I move the keyframes backwards.
Then I look them.
Now let's work on animating the head.
I opened its rotation in the passing pose.
I create the key frame for it, and in the contact post I set it to seven.
I duplicate the same key frames for the next passing and contact poses.
Then I make them easy, easy, and I move them back just to create the overlapping movement.
Then I look at.
Let me hide the arms and the left leg so I can focus on animating the right leg.
Isolate the right controller and open its position and rotation.
In the contact post, I create a keyframe for its position and move it forward so the right leg would
be completely stretched.
I create a key frame for its rotation.
In the passing post.
The link should be located in the back.
And the rotation should be like this.
In the concept post, it should look like this.
And the next person post.
It should be like this.
In the outpost.
It should be here.
And for the last contact, I duplicate the first keyframes.
In the down pose.
I move it lower a little bit.
And right here.
In the contact post.
I moved back a little.
Basically, we must create a path like this for the controller in the outpost.
It must be here.
In the down post.
It should look like this.
After doing so, I curve the path.
Let's see how it turns out.
I just have to change the rotation right here.
Right here.
The rotation should look like this.
And over here, I rotated like this.
And also, it should be up here a little.
Then I make them Yeezys.
I copied the keyframes and paste them for the rotation and position of the left leg controller.
I can.
The left leg.
Then I look the keyframes.
I move the left leg controller back.
So the last keyframes would be placed on the second contact.
Well, let's go for animating the arms.
Firstly, I make the arms visible.
Then isolate the right arm controller.
Then in the effects control section, I create keyframes for the upper lower and go in the first contact.
The right hand should be the opposite of the right leg.
So I move it backward.
In the next contact, I move it forward and in the last contact I duplicate the first keyframes and
make them easy.
Let's see what it looks like.
The first concert.
I moved up a little.
And for the overlapping movements, I move the keyframes like this.
And then I look at the hand animation.
I put the keyframes like this.
Then isolate these keyframes and then copy and paste them for the other hand.
Isolate upper, lower and goal and press control V and move them like this.
So the left hand would be exactly the opposite of the right hand.
Now let's work on animating the shadow.
All right.
Let's check what it looks like.
Very well.
I can hide the background layers and expand the work area to 2 seconds, and let's see how it came out.
The animation of the right leg is sloped.
So I have to loop it.
I do the same for the body.
As you can see, the run cycle animation is done and everything is looked.
Please don't forget to like this video and consider subscribing if you like more of these videos.
And finally, if you want completely to learn reading and animating the character by the basil and also
to get acquainted with other tools that are very useful in raking and animating the character, I suggest
you watch this video.