Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we want to talk about text animations.
Every motion designer or animator needs to learn about text animation sooner or later, so it's better
for us to learn about it now in the beginning.
Takes Animation has many usages.
For example, subtitles, title animation, and also every project with text content.
The customer wants it to be editable so he can change it later.
So it takes animation.
Importance is obvious when we could change text without this animation getting into any problem after
Effects is a powerful software for creating text animations.
It has very useful tools to make the text animation process easier and more flexible for us.
What you need to learn about text animation principles and how to work with these tools.
So let's get started.
Click on the text tool and click on the preview panel to create your text.
As soon as you click on the preview panel, you'll see a red layer in the timeline in the Layers section,
and now you can write whatever it takes you want.
Okay.
After creating your text, you'll see your text.
Your name is the same as the text you have written.
Panels related to text or character and paragraph.
The character panel includes several options.
The first option is for changing the font of your text.
The second one can change font style.
With these tools, you can change the color of your text.
For example, isolate black as the color.
Here you can change the field color and to enable the stroke, you can click here and select a color
for its stroke.
By clicking on it.
You can change the color easily.
Here you can change your text size.
Let me create another line.
Sign the whole text.
And here you can decide the distance between two lines.
With this option, you can change the spacing between letters.
Here.
If your text has a stroke, you can increase or decrease the stroke size.
And here you can specify whether the stroke is on the fill or the fill on the stroke.
Here, you can apply different edits to your text.
The next panel is the paragraph panel where you can change the alignment of your paragraph.
Here it's on a line left.
You see its anchor point is on left.
If I put it on a line center, you see the anchor point goes to the middle of the layer.
And if I click on right, it goes to the right.
I put it in the center for now.
So its anchor point locates in the center of the layer and press control home to bring the text to the
middle of the preview.
Here are the options to adjust margin and takes titles.
Okay.
Now that you got familiar with text panels and text adjustments, let's overview the properties of the
text layer.
I open the text layer in the text section we see the first option is source text.
With this option, you can change the contents of your text layer.
For example, I create a keyframe here and go ten frames forward and I change my text because isolated
a line center takes in the paragraph panel when I type, the text is formed from the center and it doesn't
go to level rise and it's very good.
As you see, the keyframes are created and they are toggle hold first, the initial text is shown and
when I get to the second keyframe, the next text is shown and it's not necessary to create multiple
layers to change the text.
Since the key frames are toggle hold, you cannot change the animation speed or edit the graph.
The animation changes in one frame.
The next property is the path option, which allows you to align the text along the path.
For example, I want to create a mask, select the text layer, select one of these shapes and create
the shape.
As you see, this layer is mask.
To change this mask to a path so that it doesn't mask the layer.
I just need to put this on none so it gets ineffective on the layer after that.
In the path option.
In the path.
I can select the path.
As you can see, the text layer is arranged according to the created path.
And here you can see various options.
The first option is reverse path, which allows you to put your text inside or outside of your path.
The next option makes your leather stand vertically.
The next option may still solve your Texas spread with equal distance along the path.
With margin options, you can offset your text.
To learn about more option properties.
We should go for animating the text.