Well, we get to the most interesting part of text animation animating texts.
Basically, the method of animating the text layer is different from what I learned in animating layers
properties like position, rotation and scale to create an animation for the text.
I need to use this option.
I click on this option here.
The first option is for making your characters takes 3D in 3D space.
If I go to the custom view, you see the layer is 3D.
Okay.
I go to the animate option.
Disable this option and also disable this option to turn the layer into 2D.
The next section is for animating properties that you had in layer transform like anchor point, position,
scale and rotation.
Exactly the same options I have in transform of the layers I have here so that I can create all the
animations I did for the layers I do for the takes two.
In the next section you can animate fill color, a stroke, color and stroke with.
In the next section, which is for a spacing, you can animate the distance between letters or words
and other features.
For example, I want to create an animation for takes position.
So I select position.
As you see, when I click on the position and the animator is added to the text layer.
The subset of this animate there is a range selector.
Using this, you can animate your text.
First, I must apply the changes that I want to see in the position of the takes.
For example, I want to text go from down top.
To do this, I change the y position of the text layer and bring it down after that to animate the text
I use.
Range selector options start and and offset parameters.
Let me increase this a little.
As you see, when I increase this sort, the text starts to come up from the beginning to describe it
in layer animation.
A start makes the text move from the first keyframe that is down position to the second keyframe, which
is the initial position.
If I decrease the end, you see this happening from the end.
Offset is for moving the saw and the end together.
Let's go for creating an animation for the text.
To do that, I can use a start and end, but it's better to use offsets.
I create a keyframe for offsets.
Go on second one and set it on 100.
If you take a look, you see the animation is created and it takes moves from down to up.
The animation has been created, but its movement is linear.
To ease the keyframes, isolate them and press f nine.
I go to the craft editor and decrease the speed at the end.
I also increased the animation length so the easy is looks better.
Let's go for the advanced settings of the text.
I go to the advanced.
First option is units.
Here you can choose a unit for your text in animation.
By default, it's on percentage.
You can specify your animation with a number between 0 to 100, but if you want to do it more accurately
or animate the specific leaders, you just need to set this on index.
And as you see the value for the sort and and offset also changes.
And when I get to the second keyframe, the offset is 14, which is in fact the number of the letters
used in the text.
I set it on percentage again.
The next option is based on.
You can decide that you want your animation to be delivered by leather, leather by leather, ignoring
spaces, or by word or line by line.
I said it on word for now to see the text animation in word by word, too.
The next thing to know is that for each animator I can animate multiple properties.
I added position here to add another property I click on ADD.
I go to the property and add the scale and set it on zero.
Let's see how the animation is.
As you see, the animation has both position and scale.
As I said before, I want the animation to happen word by word.
In the position is right.
But you see that this scale animation is letter by letter.
To solve this problem, I go to more option.
In anchor point grouping, you must choose the word so that each of your words has one anchor point
you see now its anchor point is one if was on character, each letter has its own anchor point.
So I said one word to get a single anchor point, and the scale properly applies to the whole world.
And you can also specify if you want your scale animation to happen from the bottom or from the center.
For example, here it happens from the bottom.
It's because the anchor point of the takes is located on the bottom.
Well, I go to group alignment and bring the anchor point in the center.
Now the text scales from the center.
I go to the advanced section.
The next option is mode, which has the same modes as a mask.
It's on ADD by default.
If I set it to subtract, you see the animation reverses before the text would appear and then animation.
But now first text disappears and then animation.
I said mode on ad again and based on on character.
I delete the animator scale for now.
Then I go for the amounts option.
This allows you to control the animation of your animator generally.
It is on 100 by default, which is the animation I have created.
If I say to -100, you see, it shows the opposite animation I have created.
If I said it on 50, for example, it moves half of what it used to.
And if it's down zero, it shows nothing.
I said this as it was on 100.
Now I go for the next option.
Shape as its name represents and specifies the shape of your range selector.
It's on the square by default, as you see on the screen.
Your insulator is a square and shows the letters accordingly.
The next option is softness.
You can specify the softness of your animation here.
For example, let me give it some space here to make it more obvious.
As you see, there is move up.
If I set the softness to zero, you see letters don't move and jump to their next position.
I said it on 100 again.
The next option is is high.
This option sets a slow movement at the beginning and a fast movement at the end of the letter's animation.
For example, I set it to 100.
I make the keyframes linear to make their animation more obvious.
As you see, when the leader wants to move upward, it has a low speed at the beginning and a high speed
at the end.
And same for other words.
Okay.
I said this is your.
Is law is the opposite.
In the beginning.
It has a higher speed and in the end the speed decreases.
In one frame.
The cylinder moves from the initial position to here and in the end it speed decreases.
If you want a smooth beginning and ending, I can say on 50 and this one on 52.
I think you understand now that the is high ex the same as the easy is out which is the speed is low
at the beginning and at the end the speed is high and is low is the same as eases in which is the speed
is high at the beginning and at the end the speed decreases.
But the difference is that is high and is low or for adjusting the animation speed for characters.
But if you make the keyframes eases, you have changed the overall speed of your text animation while
is high and is low just to fake the leaders animation.
This is a specific tip you need to pay more attention to it.
I make these key easy is again.
The next ship is ramp up.
As you see, it's for creating a ramp mode for your text animation.
And as it's obvious on the screen, the width of this range selector shape is two times more than the
square shape.
So at the beginning I must set the offset on -100 so that all of the letters placed on the initial location.
Let me change this to zero.
As you see, the overall animation is easy, is what each of the letters doesn't have.
Easy is and is not appealing as they are before.
To modify this.
I go to the middle of the animation and increase this.
As I said before, it is high, the speed is low at the beginning and at the end the speed increases.
Here, it's slow and in the end it increases.
Well, I said this one on 50 and this one on 52.
Increase its speed a little.
Bring it on.
2 seconds.
To get familiar with other options in shape properly.
Pay attention to this clip.
As you see, I have brought all the options here for you to completely understand how other shapes work
and how the takes animations would be.
To make the text animation more attractive, isolate the text layer and add a mask to the layer.
Set the mask mode on, subtract to hide the text at the beginning.
As you see, the text is not visible in the beginning and appears slowly.
I increase the animation speed a little.
The next thing you need to know is that I can create multiple animators for a single text.
To create the returning animation for the text.
All I need to do is add another animator from this menu or duplicate this animator.
And bring its key frame here.
After doing this, I go to advanced and set it smooth to subtract.
If I play now, you'll see the tapes appearing and returning again.
And you can apply any changes to your first animator without the second animator affected.
For example, I go to advance and set based on on word.