In this lesson, I want to talk about selectors.
As I said before, we can add different properties to the animator.
As you see here, we can also add different selectors to the animator.
Here I can add a new range selector or a vehicle selector or an expression selector.
For example, I add a selector to the animator.
As you see the lenders vehicle according to the value of the position I have entered here.
And when the offset moves and gets to the second keyframe, wiggling stops.
I go to the range selector now in advance and set its amount to zero so that the animation of the range
selector is disabled.
For we going to affect the text.
I go into it and said it's more than AD now.
The text wiggles, but now the range selector doesn't stop it and it wiggles according to the property
set.
Now, if I add a new property to the animator and like a scale and say on 50, you see its scale and
position both change, the next option's minimum and maximum amount is for determining the range of
characters changes in position and scale.
For example, I set these 2 to 0.
If I set the maximum to 100, you see, the scale and position of the characters don't go higher than
the value that I've entered here.
If I said it -100.
The opposite of this happens.
That is the scale and position don't go lower than the value that I entered, and it's always higher
than 50.
I set these on default.
So that the scale and position of the characters can go less and more than the intended value.
Based on his obvious character or.
The second is how much characters move per second.
I say ten, for example.
You see their movement increased.
Correlation is for controlling the vibration of your vehicle.
You see now we're going happens a lot.
This means their vibration is more.
If I increase this, you'll see vibration get closer to each other and make it very smooth.
Temporal and spatial phase options or to control wiggling manually.
For example, I said this to zero and make a keyframe frame for temporal.
I come here and I wanted to kill this much and then stop.
I said this on two occasions.
The next option is the like dimension, which is for a scale.
If I enable it, you see, the characters don't get deformed and scale on the X and y axis together.
The random see is to randomize wiggling.
I delete these for now and go for the next selector, which is the expression selector as it's obvious
from its name.
This selector is to control the animation through an expression.
When I go to expression selector, there is a based on which I talked about in amount.
There is an expression option You need to write or place your expression here.
I pace the bouncing expression here and said exposition on zero.
And bring it down a little bit.
As you see it takes animation has a bouncing mode.
And here you can change its values.
The L.A., as its name implies, is for the delay between letters.
For example, I said this on five.
You see, the animation of the characters is done with a delay.
I press control Z to set it to the previous state.
The next value is the frequency, which is the number of back and forth movements or bouncing.
For example, I said this on.
Let's see how it is.
As you see, it gives this spring animation.
At first Control Z.
Amplitude or overshoot is to determine the amount of movements of the characters.
Look, right now the taste has gone up this much.
If I set the amplitude to 200, you see it goes higher than here.
And the more the value, the higher it goes.
Look how it is.
Let me put this on 500 to make it more obvious.
As you see, the amount of movement has increased a lot and they go higher.
Let me delete this scale.
Well, I bring it again on 100.
Decay means energy depletion.
The more the value gets, the energy decreases sooner and the less it gets energy decreases later.
Okay.
I said this on one.
Now you see animation stopping takes longer.
If I said this on ten, you see, the animation takes less bouncing because it's energy depletion happens
faster.
I said none at.
In the next lessons, I go for creating some useful text animations.
Good luck.