Hello, everyone.
In this video, we're going to learn the bouncing text animation.
Let's do it.
First, create a text ahead, control home to set the text layer in the center of the comp.
Then as a position animator to the text.
And here, add an expression selector.
And delete the range selector because we don't need it.
An expression selector in a base.
The bounce expression here.
Set the Y position on -150.
If you do it opposite, the thanks goes up.
And also you can use this expression for any property you want.
Well, if you want to personalize the animation, you can go to the expression and change these values.
Frequency determines the speed of the bounce.
For example, if I set it on 20.
You can see the speed increases.
Amplitude or overshoot determines the power of the bounce.
For example, the ladder moves down up to here.
But if I set it on 600, you'll see it goes further down.
Decay defined the amount of energy loss.
The more you increase the decay, the sooner the animation stops and the less you decrease, the later
it stops.
If I said this to Tim, it will stop sooner.
DeLay determines the delay of the letters animation.
For example.
I set it on five.
To make the animation looks better.
I want to add a rotation to it so I duplicate the animator, delete the position.
And the rotation.
And also enabled the pre character 3D to be able to rotate the leather separately.
Set it on -90.
Go to the expression, decrease the decay a little so that the rotation bonus stops later.
After that mask the text layer and set its mode on subtract.
Well, if you want to use this animation you've created as a preset in another project, select the
animators and in animation menu, click on Save Animation Presets and save it as a preset.
And then if you want to create the same animation for your text in another project, select the text
layer and in animation menu, select the upload animation presets and open your preset.
And finally, you just have to mask your layer.
Och, that's it.