Okay, let's go and create the second sample of our text animations.
I create a text and bring it to the center of the scene.
And this time I want to create an animation for it by tracking.
I create a keyframe for tracking amount.
Go to the second to create another keyframe.
Go back on the first keyframe and increase it until here.
I added Blur to the animator.
Put it on 100.
And create a key frame for it.
In second to I put it on zero.
Also, I create a scale for the ticks in the soil.
I increase its scale and in the end to 100.
I decrease tracking a little and to place the anchor point at the center of the ticks.
I go to the more options and place the anchor point in the middle.
Isolate keyframes and make them easy.
Ease.
I go to the graph editor and make the second keyframe smoother.
Let's see how it looks.
It's very good.