Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, I want to create a glitchy animation for the text.
I write my text.
Here I use the character of the property.
As you see, when I increase this, the letters of the text change randomly.
I put it on 35.
And for this randomizing to have an animation, I use the vehicle selector.
I go to the regal selector and put the regal second on five to increase its speed.
I go to the range selector and create a keyframe for its offset.
I go on second two and put this on 100.
As you see, the takes appears thereby.
I add another animator with opacity property and put it on zero.
And with its train selector as the previous range selector.
I bring the keyframes of the first line selector a little forward to improve the randomizing.
Isolate keyframes and make them easy.
By the scale to the animator.
I duplicate this animator and this character offset.
Instead, I add the scale and put its value onto 100.
I increase, it's why bring it on 600.
Let's have a look.
To make the tax not come down.
I only need to go to the more options and bring its anchor point in the middle of the text.
It's good.
I can play with keyframes to improve it.